[
  {
    "question": "The Roman population had a large group of people similar to what we would call the \"middle class\" today.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Roman society defined friends as people who did things for each other.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The philosophical tendency to separate things into sharply opposed categories is called:",
    "answer": "Dualism",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following were prominent tensions in the Hellenistic world except:",
    "answer": "Salvation and damnation",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Hellenistic social world included which of the following?",
    "answer": "A great deal of religious syncretism <br>Shocking economic inequality <br>A wide variety of philosophical perspectives on life",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The writers of the New Testament were confident that what they were writing was scripture and should be treated as such.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The books of the New Testament are completely unified in their theological perspectives.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The study of the Bible with the intent to explain and analyze what a text actually says is called:",
    "answer": "Exegesis",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The letters contained in the New Testament are arranged in chronological order based upon when they were written.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Reflection on the contents of the Bible and the process of interpretation with the intent of finding meaning through the lens of a particular philosophical stance is called:",
    "answer": "Hermeneutics",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a feature of Acts concerning the role and character of God?",
    "answer": "God only offers salvation to Israel",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In modern scholarship, the speeches in the Book of Acts are most often understood as . . .",
    "answer": "Literary devices for expressing Luke's own theology",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Powell, all of the following are reasons Luke wrote Acts except...",
    "answer": "To demonstrate the love and compassion of God through Christ for Roman rulers",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the \"We Passages\" in Acts?",
    "answer": "Passages where the author writes as a traveling companion of Paul",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a parallel between Luke and Acts?",
    "answer": "Jesus and the disciples receive the Holy Spirit and then preach a sermon",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the book of Acts, Jesus remains active on earth . . .",
    "answer": "Through the work of the Holy Spirit. <br> Through the use of his name. <br> Through the lives of his followers.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Acts, the Gentile mission...",
    "answer": "Begins in Jerusalem and spreads to all nations",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many missionary journeys of Paul are recorded in Acts?",
    "answer": "Three",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Luke created a number of speeches in Acts that relay in his own words the general sense of what the speakers said.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jesus is rejected by the Jews in Luke but they accept Paul in Acts.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "There are several discrepancies between how Acts portrays Paul and what Paul writes in his own letters",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Book of Acts provides a detailed account of everything that happened in the first three decades of Christianity.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the New Testament, Paul's letters to churches are arranged...",
    "answer": "From longest to shortest",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a feature of letter writing in ancient times as reflected in the New Testament letters?",
    "answer": "The mandatory use of official Roman stamps or imprints on letters",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which word meaning \"false ascription\" is applied to the practice of ancient authors attributing their own writings to other people?",
    "answer": "Pseudepigraphy",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a typical Christian greeting in an ancient letter?",
    "answer": "Grace and Peace",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Students writing letters in the name of their teachers was an established convention of the ancient world.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The early church always welcomed pseudepigraphical works and forgeries as long as they taught Christ.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "When preaching about Jesus in new areas, Paul usually follows which basic pattern?",
    "answer": "He targets urban, commercial settings",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul is known for his focus on what part of the story about Jesus?",
    "answer": "Jesus' death and resurrection",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The \"New Perspective on Paul\" is a scholarly view that:",
    "answer": "Understands \"works of the law\" not as \"works righteousness\" but as ethnic markers that designate Israel as God's chosen people",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Paul's letters and Acts, which of the following is not accurate?",
    "answer": "Paul was born in Jerusalem",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul's missionary travels are typically understood as being divided up into three missionary journeys.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In order to finance his mission work, Paul relied exclusively on income he received by working with his hands and did not rely on any financial support from the churches he established.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "By the time the gathering was over, Publius felt like he had a good understanding of major Christian beliefs based upon the religious practices and ceremonies he had witnessed that evening.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Publius, the visitor to the church's gathering (and the narrator of the story) is put at ease by the greetings that he and his own hosts (Clement and Euodia) receive when they reach Aquila and Prisca's home.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following best describes the way Roman societal norms are (or are not) reflected in the church's gathering?",
    "answer": "The people fit the Roman culture they are part of, but they modify the cultural norms significantly to reflect their values.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Like many others in Roman society, Aquila and Prisca, the main leaders of the church, live a subsistence lifestyle of significant poverty.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Clement, when does the church meeting start?",
    "answer": "When the hosts greet them as they arrive.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Although containing some minor points of speculation where data was inadequate, Going to Church in the First Century by Robert Banks is based on reliable research findings in the areas of biblical studies, Roman and Greek literary studies, and archaeology.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following was NOT a topic of major conversation in this church's gathering?",
    "answer": "Whether or not slavery was moral according to Christian standards.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT an example of ways the members of this church served each other in this story?",
    "answer": "Washing one another's hands after each course of the meal",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following best describes the perspective the members of this church have about 1 Corinthians?",
    "answer": "It is a letter from a wise friend whose perspectives and judgment they trust but are willing to challenge.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The gathering of this church was an informal one, more like a family meal than anything resembling Roman or 21st century Christian religious practices and worship services.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Some church leaders in Thessalonica had not even heard of Jesus just a few months before they took a leading role.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of suffering did the Thessalonian Christians most likely experience?",
    "answer": "Social shaming for not participating in the religious and entertainment events of the city",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Greek word referring to Jesus' second coming is parousia.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "From Paul's words in 1 Thessalonians, one can describe his ministry as...",
    "answer": "Preaching while also working with his hands",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "2 Thessalonians is essentially the same as 1 Thessalonians, with no significant changes in content, style, or tone.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1 Thessalonians, Paul addresses concerns about those who died...",
    "answer": "Before Christ returned",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Nearly all scholars believe that 2 Thessalonians was written by Paul just a few months after he wrote 1 Thessalonians.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Most scholars think that 1 Thessalonians is Paul's...",
    "answer": "First biblical letter written",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What group of people did 2 Thessalonians have particularly harsh ways of addressing?",
    "answer": "Idle believers, who didn't work",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "How did other Gentiles view the newly converted Christians in Thessalonica?",
    "answer": "As irreligious, antisocial, and unpatriotic.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does Paul think the Galatians are fools?",
    "answer": "They want to be circumcised",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did Paul rebuke Peter at Antioch?",
    "answer": "Peter quit eating with Gentiles",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In his letter to the Galatians, Paul is so upset he leaves out what basic part of the letter?",
    "answer": "The thanksgiving",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul's opponents in Galatia have apparently said that his gospel lacks endorsement from the apostles in Jerusalem. What is Paul's reply?",
    "answer": "The apostles in Jerusalem do approve, but it doesn't really matter since he received his gospel from Christ and it needs no human endorsement",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul compares living under the Law of Moses to being immature or childlike.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul claims that if the Gentiles seek justification (a right relation with God) by observing the law, then they are nullifying what?",
    "answer": "The grace of God",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul's meeting with the Jerusalem leaders about circumcision mentioned in Galatians 2 undoubtedly corresponds with the description of a meeting in Jerusalem found in Acts 15.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In contrast to Paul, the opponents claim that the \"good news\" to Gentiles is that they can become...",
    "answer": "Members of Israel",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the traditional designation for Paul's opponents who were Jewish Christians advocating a gospel that Gentiles must first become Jews by obeying the Law of Moses before receiving full salvation from Jesus, the Jewish Messiah?",
    "answer": "Judaizers",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The significance of the debate over whether Galatians was written to \"north Galatia\" or \"south Galatia\" is that the destination might determine which of the following?",
    "answer": "The letter was written early or late in Paul's career",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the letter to Philemon, Paul states Onesimus has become like what to him?",
    "answer": "A son",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "When Paul mentions that he hopes to visit Philemon soon, it is just one more tactic intended to persuade Philemon to set Onesimus free.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul used all of the following persuasive tactics in his letter EXCEPT:",
    "answer": "Reminding the master of the immorality of owning slaves",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Slavery in the Roman world was characterized by all of the following EXCEPT...",
    "answer": "Roman slaves had no legal protection when in conflict with their masters",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What Roman legal practice provides a reasonable context for understanding Paul's letter to Philemon?",
    "answer": "A slave who had wronged his or her master could seek arbitration and sanctuary through a colleague or friend of the master",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "There is evidence that Onesimus may have become one of the bishops of the church in Ephesus.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul uses puns in his letter to Philemon using the name of Onesimus, whose name means what?",
    "answer": "Useful",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Philemon probably lived in what Asian city?",
    "answer": "Colossae",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a fact concerning the person Onesimus?",
    "answer": "The head jailer of the prison where Paul is incarcerated",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a fact concerning the person Philemon",
    "answer": "He had a bitter argument with Paul",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Scholars have explained the dissimilarity of Ephesians with Paul's undisputed letters in all of the following ways except...",
    "answer": "Paul wrote Ephesians as a rough draft for Colossians, but it was mistakenly inserted into the collection of Paul's letters.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In English Bibles, Paul's letter to the Ephesians is addressed \"to the saints who are in Ephesus and are faithful in Christ Jesus.\" Some of the oldest Greek manuscripts are missing a few of these words. Which are the missing words?",
    "answer": "In Ephesians",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The \"mystery\" referred to in Ephesians concerns what?",
    "answer": "God's plan to unite all people in Christ",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the German word scholars use to describe discussions of family responsibilities in the Greco-Roman era?",
    "answer": "Haustafel",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not part of Ephesians' idea or perspective of the church?",
    "answer": "There are two dimensions of the church, the heavenly ministry inspired by Christ but also the sinful struggle of living in this world.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the \"table of household duties\" found in Ephesians is compared to such tables that were typical for this culture and time period, the most remarkable aspect is...",
    "answer": "The inclusion of instructions for husbands, fathers, and masters.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ephesus often earned the title neokoros for the region around the city. This title indicates that...",
    "answer": "Ephesus served as the official headquarters for the imperial cult",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the authors of the household codes of Colossians and Ephesians wrote them, they meant the codes to be applied exactly as they are in all times, places, and cultures.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Of the two letters, Ephesians and Colossians, scholars think Ephesians was written first.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Household Code in Ephesians challenges those in positions of power to give of themselves in selfless service to others.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is one main reason some scholars think Colossians may not be written by Paul?",
    "answer": "Colossians has a different style from Paul and a more developed theology",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Colossians presents Christ as exalted and cosmic in all of the following ways except...",
    "answer": "Christ descended to Hades",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a feature of or fact about the city of Colossae?",
    "answer": "Colossae was the hometown of the emperor Nero.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Colossians, spiritual growth and maturity are attained by doing what?",
    "answer": "Remaining steadfast in what has already been taught",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not an aspect or characteristic of the so-called \"Colossian heresy,\" that is, the philosophy or teaching that threatened their Christian identity and faith?",
    "answer": "Christ was fully divine but only appeared to be human.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Of the following options, which is not a distinctive, theologically well developed theme of Colossians (in comparison with Paul's undisputed letters) that causes some scholars to doubt Paul's authorship of the letter?",
    "answer": "A greater emphasis on pneumatology",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul was not the founder of, or missionary to, the churches in Colossae in the region of Phrygia. Who was the Christian pastor working with the Phrygian cities, including Colossae?",
    "answer": "Epaphras",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Letter to the Colossians represents a development in Paul's thought on a number of different religious topics (whether or not actually written by Paul).",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The letter of Colossians quotes an early Christian confession or hymn.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"Realized eschatology\" refers to the idea that the blessings of the end times can only be realized after Christ's Second Coming.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Philippians is written in the form of a/an...",
    "answer": "Friendship letter",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following are true descriptions of Philippi, except what?",
    "answer": "Philippi became a thriving port city to rival Corinth",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "One way Paul emphasizes unity in Philippians is to use which prefix on a variety of words?",
    "answer": "Syn",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a major theme in Philippians?",
    "answer": "False Apostles",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul urges the Philippians to have humility, which in this letter means what?",
    "answer": "To put others first and seek what is best for them",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What person exemplifying humility does Paul suggest the Philippians should imitate?",
    "answer": "Paul himself, Timothy, Epaphroditus",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which word used by Paul in Philippians would have had special meaning to those living in Philippi?",
    "answer": "Citizenship",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Christ Hymn in Philippians 2:6-11 is one of the earliest literary references to what?",
    "answer": "Jesus' Preexistence",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "When Paul writes Philippians, he knows that his own death may be near.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Some believe that the letter to the Philippians is actually composed of portions of two or three of Paul's letters edited together.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The church in Philippi gave generously to help Paul in his mission work.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Philippians, those who live in a manner worthy of the gospel will never suffer.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following issues divided the Corinthian church?",
    "answer": "Eating food offered to idols, Taking one another to court, Boasting about an incestuous relationship",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The two groups of Corinthian Christians, those who approved of prostitution and those who prohibited all sexual relationships (even in marriage), had a common commitment to what?",
    "answer": "Being Spirtual",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not one of the three guidelines that determines Paul's teaching about marriage in 1 Corinthians?",
    "answer": "God created all males and females for marriage",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What occurred between the writing of 1 and 2 Corinthians?",
    "answer": "-Paul made a visit to the corinthians during which he was hurt and humiliated",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "-Paul received news from Titus that the corinthian church had repented of hurting",
    "answer": "...",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "-Paul wrote a letter challenging the church to prove their obedience to him and discipline an individual had wronged him",
    "answer": "...",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the topic of 2 Corinthians 8-9?",
    "answer": "Fund-raising",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2 Corinthians, Paul is driven to boasting by whom?",
    "answer": "Super-apostles who tout their own credentials and achievements",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What effect did Paul's \"tearful\" letter have on the Corinthian churches?",
    "answer": "Repentance",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Problems arose around the Lord's Supper in the Corinthian church because...",
    "answer": "Wealthier members were eating food before the lower class members arrived after long hours of work.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does Paul think the Corinthian Christians should do with regard to eating food sacrificed to idols?",
    "answer": "Be willing to give up their rights for the sake of others",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul's initial plan to visit the Corinthians and his subsequent cancellation of that plan resulted in what accusation?",
    "answer": "Paul is unreliable and self interested.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the Greek word often used for the phenomenon of speaking in tongues?",
    "answer": "Glossolalia",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does Paul suggest the corinthians do instead of advocating for their own rights",
    "answer": "Consider other people first",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not true about Roman Corinth?",
    "answer": "As a colony it held steadfast to Roman morals and virtues",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What characterization best describes the church in Corinth?",
    "answer": "A divisive church with problems",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are scholarly hypotheses regarding the abrupt changes in tone found in 2 Corinthians?",
    "answer": "Paul was on the road, writing a little here and a little there, the letter itself is a compilation of a few different letters, in ancient letter writing, sharp transition were quite common",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who from the Corinthian congregation originally visited Paul and reported on the activities of other members in that church?",
    "answer": "Chloes people",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul taught that Jesus freed people from the Law and therefore freed people to do whatever they want.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "1 Corinthians is the first letter Paul wrote to the Corinthian church.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Lord's Supper (Eucharist) originally included a full meal.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Some believe that 2 Corinthians contains parts of three or more letters Paul wrote to the church in Corinth.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Romans, Paul uses the story of this Old Testament character to show that Jews and Gentiles can be saved by God's grace.",
    "answer": "Abraham",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to proponents of \"the new perspective on Paul,\" which of the following is probably Paul's main point in Romans?",
    "answer": "Salvation is universally available",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Romans, Paul says that \"all Israel will be saved,\" which has been interpreted as meaning what?",
    "answer": "A literal conversion of Jews will come about in the end times, a literal salvation of all Israel because of gods mercy and covenant with Israel, not \"Israel\" as an ethnic people but as a people, both jewish and gentile, who accept Israel's messiah",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Romans the word justification is most closely associated with what idea?",
    "answer": "Reconcolliation",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Romans, Paul teaches that church members who know that it is permissible to eat the food which others think it is sinful to eat should do what?",
    "answer": "Avoid eating that food as an accommodation to those who might be offended by their action",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "When and from where does Paul write Romans?",
    "answer": "Corinth in the year 57 or 58",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a proposed reason why Paul wrote Romans?",
    "answer": "To reestablish contact with the Roman church that he had established during his second missionary journey",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Romans 8, the earth itself will be redeemed along with God's people.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul established the church in Rome.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul tells the Roman Christians that he hopes to share the gospel message to the west as far as England after he visits them.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the person Titus best known for?",
    "answer": "Being brought to Jerusalem by Paul as a test case for the church in deciding whether Gentile converts needed to be circumcised",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The false teachings addressed in the Pastoral Epistles have a number of similarities with which early second century heresy?",
    "answer": "Gnosticism",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which instruction about women in ministry does not occur in the Pastoral Letters?",
    "answer": "Women may baptize other women",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Generally speaking, the letters to Timothy and Titus deal with two threats: persecution and what else?",
    "answer": "False teaching",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Timothy and Titus were...",
    "answer": "Paul's emissaries",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why are 1 Timothy, 2 Timothy, and Titus called the \"Pastoral Letters\"?",
    "answer": "The are addressed to individuals charged with the leadership of congregations",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Although many consider the Pastoral Epistles pseudepigraphal, recently scholars have suggested that one of them may have been composed by Paul. Which one is now viewed as more likely to be authentic by some?",
    "answer": "2 Timothy",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a proposal to explain why the Pastoral Letters do not seem to fit with Paul's career?",
    "answer": "The Pastoral Letters are compilations of letters written during different times in Paul's ministry",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following does not apply to the person Timothy?",
    "answer": "He was converted from Cynicism",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Most biblical scholars view the role of women as taught in the Pastoral letters as compatible with what Paul writes elsewhere.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "One difference between the Pastoral letters and Paul's \"undisputed letters\" is that in the latter Paul always addresses the entire church when dealing with false teachers rather than individuals.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the ideas and style, the letter of James seems to have been influenced by all of the following traditions except what?",
    "answer": "Jewish mystical tradition",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not an aspect or characteristic of \"wisdom from above\" according to James?",
    "answer": "It is a secret knowledge that provides salvation",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What or who is the source of temptation in the letter of James?",
    "answer": "Ones own desires",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Both Paul and James look to the story of this Old Testament character for a model of faith.",
    "answer": "Abraham",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the letter of James, all of the following are true about God except this.",
    "answer": "God often tempts believers to test them",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is James called a \"catholic epistle\"?",
    "answer": "The letter was addressed to the whole church",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which James is traditionally identified as the author of the Letter of James?",
    "answer": "The brother of Jesus who led the Jerusalem church",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does James advise Christians to do when a rich person enters the assembly?",
    "answer": "Treat rich and poor equally",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "With which Old Testament book does James have the most parallels?",
    "answer": "Proverbs",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "James uses biblical stories more than images drawn from the world at large to communicate his advice to Christians.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The real problem for believers is what James calls \"double-mindedness.\"",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Some scholars think that Hebrews is a...",
    "answer": "Sermon",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote Hebrews?",
    "answer": "Unknown",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the two main themes the Book of Hebrews emphasizes repeatedly?",
    "answer": "The superiority of Christ and the condemnation of apostasy",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The humanity of Christ is theologically significant in Hebrews in all of the following ways except...",
    "answer": "Being human allows Christ to trick the devil so that his divinity can destroy evil",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which obscure Old Testament figure is raised to significant prominence in Hebrews?",
    "answer": "Melchizedek",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "This word refers to the portable worship space of the Israelites before the construction of their Temple in Jerusalem.",
    "answer": "Tabernacle",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which dominant image of Jesus in Hebrews is almost entirely absent elsewhere in the New Testament?",
    "answer": "High priest",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the relationship of Christianity to Judaism as presented in Hebrews?",
    "answer": "Christianity has continuity with Judaism and is superior",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Book of Hebrews discusses the Jewish religion as it was practiced in the Jerusalem Temple.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The idea of \"perfection\" in Hebrews is moral purity - maturing to the point where one no longer sins.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The author of Hebrews used a different Old Testament than the one on which modern translations are based.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "A prominent theme in Hebrews is that God has provided \"something better\" in Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In terms of authorship, which of the following is NOT true about 1, 2, and 3 John?",
    "answer": "Only 1 John mentions that John is the author",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What concrete example of loving one another is given in 1 John?",
    "answer": "Giving material help to Christians in need",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Johannine writings seem to indicate that the early church was still working out which doctrine?",
    "answer": "Christ's humanity and divinity",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What word occurring in some English translations of the Bible refers to Christ's death as an act that placates the wrath of a God offended by human sin?",
    "answer": "Propitiation",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "All three of the Johannine letters appear to have what purpose?",
    "answer": "To deal with conflict and division in the Johannine churches",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The genre of 1 John is probably best described as what?",
    "answer": "A theological tract",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What word occurring in some English translations of the Bible refers to a cleansing or removal of defilement, usually in reference to Christ's death?",
    "answer": "Expiation",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "For what is Gaius noted in 3 John?",
    "answer": "Providing hospitality to missionaries",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Johannine letters (2 John specifically) say to \"love one another\" but to do so without welcoming anyone who fails to keep Christ's teachings.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The term \"dualism\" refers to Christians who viewed Jesus as both human and divine.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1 John the label \"antichrist\" applies to anyone opposed to Christ and his followers.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Most scholars believe the author of 1, 2, and 3 John also wrote the entire Gospel of John.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Second Peter responds to the delay of Christ's coming in all of the following ways except . . .",
    "answer": "Christ will not return until all Jews accept Jesus as Messiah and the gospel is preached to the entire world.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a key element of ancient testamentary literature?",
    "answer": "The hero leaves some special memento or relic behind for memory",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In addition to Hebrew scriptures, Jude also relies on...",
    "answer": "Apocryphal writings",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the letter of Jude is . . .",
    "answer": "To appeal to its readers to contend for the faith against the threat of false teachers",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not one of the ways 1 Peter addresses suffering?",
    "answer": "The suffering experienced by the readers is God's punishment on them",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Household Code (Haustafel) in 1 Peter is particularly distinctive from the Household Codes in other New Testament books for all of the following reasons except what?",
    "answer": "It compares the father-child relationship to that of God and Jesus",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "2 Peter uses the flood narrative out of the Book of Genesis to support what argument made by the author?",
    "answer": "God destroyed the world once in response to evil and will do so again",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of suffering addressed by 1 Peter was being experienced by its first readers?",
    "answer": "Social ostracism and general harassment",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2 Peter, what theme functions both to emphasize accountability for the wicked and to motivate a life of godliness for believers?",
    "answer": "The coming judgment",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a primary purpose of 2 Peter?",
    "answer": "To warn about and counter the effects of false teaching",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The identity of the troublemakers (false Christians) in Jude include all of the following proposals except . . .",
    "answer": "They are Christian slaves who employ radical aspects of the gospel for a slave revolt",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a reason many scholars believe Peter did not write 2 Peter?",
    "answer": "Emperors who ruled after Peter's death mention the letter",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "From what New Testament book does 2 Peter borrow extensively?",
    "answer": "Jude",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was Jude, the attributed author of the New Testament letter that bears this name?",
    "answer": "The brother of Jesus, who became a believer after the resurrection",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the opening of 1 Peter, what does the author call his audience?",
    "answer": "Exiles of the dispersion",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "First Peter was intended for many congregations in various regions within the Roman Empire. It is therefore known as what?",
    "answer": "A circular letter",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paranesis is a form of teaching that motivates one to live in accordance with what one already knows to be true or right.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jude is more interested in rescuing those under the influence of the false teachers than converting the false teachers themselves.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "To combat social persecution, 1 Peter encourages the development of an alternative community of support, the household of God.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "When scholars refer to 2 Peter as a \"testament,\" they mean a fictitious account of a famous person's \"last words.\"",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Like today, plagiarism was frowned upon in the ancient world.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Some Gentile Christians viewed themselves as part of Israel, God's chosen people, after conversion.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "First Peter's message differs so radically from the teachings elsewhere in the New Testament that some doubt Peter could have written it.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the first century, becoming a Christian frequently resulted in having to cut off one's ties with former associations (i.e., family, public rites and festivities, fellow workers).",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Revelation does all of the following except...",
    "answer": "Offer bland advice to acquiescent imperialists or predict the future",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following are common in apocalyptic literature except . . .",
    "answer": "Chronological stories",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The book of Revelation shares features of all the following genres except . . .",
    "answer": "Homily",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "To what does the term \"gematria\" refer?",
    "answer": "Assigning numerical values to words",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Academic scholarship has a clear preference for the historical reading of Revelation because the book's intent (based on the book's genre) is to . . .",
    "answer": "Address the current circumstances of its original readers",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "To the extent that Revelation is prophecy, it should be read as a communication intended primarily for people . . .",
    "answer": "Living at the time when it was written",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The book of Revelation reveals all of the following except . . .",
    "answer": "What believers want to hear",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Apocalypse means . . .",
    "answer": "Veil is pulled back",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements about the author of Revelation is true?",
    "answer": "He is very familiar with the Old Testament <br> He writes like one for whom Hebrew or Aramaic is the first language <br> He appears to have authority among the churches in Asia.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Reading the number of the beast (666) as a reference to the Roman emperor Nero, or perhaps Domitian, is illustrative of which approach?",
    "answer": "Historical",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "ALL BIBL 102.01 QUIZZES",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/290956928/all-bibl-10201-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Some church leaders in Thessalonica had not even heard of Jesus just a few months before they took a leading role.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of suffering did the Thessalonian Christians most likely experience?",
    "answer": "Social shaming for not participating in the religious and entertainment events of the city",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Greek word referring to Jesus' second coming is parousia.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "From Paul's words in 1 Thessalonians, one can describe his ministry as...",
    "answer": "Preaching while also working with his hands",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "2 Thessalonians is essentially the same as 1 Thessalonians, with no significant changes in content, style, or tone.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1 Thessalonians, Paul addresses concerns about those who died...",
    "answer": "Before Christ returned",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Nearly all scholars believe that 2 Thessalonians was written by Paul just a few months after he wrote 1 Thessalonians.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Most scholars think that 1 Thessalonians is Paul's...",
    "answer": "First biblical letter written",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What group of people did 2 Thessalonians have particularly harsh ways of addressing?",
    "answer": "Idle believers, who didn't work",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "How did other Gentiles view the newly converted Christians in Thessalonica?",
    "answer": "As irreligious, antisocial, and unpatriotic.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does Paul think the Galatians are fools?",
    "answer": "They want to be circumcised",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did Paul rebuke Peter at Antioch?",
    "answer": "Peter quit eating with Gentiles",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In his letter to the Galatians, Paul is so upset he leaves out what basic part of the letter?",
    "answer": "The thanksgiving",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul's opponents in Galatia have apparently said that his gospel lacks endorsement from the apostles in Jerusalem. What is Paul's reply?",
    "answer": "The apostles in Jerusalem do approve, but it doesn't really matter since he received his gospel from Christ and it needs no human endorsement",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul compares living under the Law of Moses to being immature or childlike.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul claims that if the Gentiles seek justification (a right relation with God) by observing the law, then they are nullifying what?",
    "answer": "The grace of God",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul's meeting with the Jerusalem leaders about circumcision mentioned in Galatians 2 undoubtedly corresponds with the description of a meeting in Jerusalem found in Acts 15.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In contrast to Paul, the opponents claim that the \"good news\" to Gentiles is that they can become...",
    "answer": "Members of Israel",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the traditional designation for Paul's opponents who were Jewish Christians advocating a gospel that Gentiles must first become Jews by obeying the Law of Moses before receiving full salvation from Jesus, the Jewish Messiah?",
    "answer": "Judaizers",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The significance of the debate over whether Galatians was written to \"north Galatia\" or \"south Galatia\" is that the destination might determine which of the following?",
    "answer": "The letter was written early or late in Paul's career",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the letter to Philemon, Paul states Onesimus has become like what to him?",
    "answer": "A son",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "When Paul mentions that he hopes to visit Philemon soon, it is just one more tactic intended to persuade Philemon to set Onesimus free.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul used all of the following persuasive tactics in his letter EXCEPT:",
    "answer": "Reminding the master of the immorality of owning slaves",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Slavery in the Roman world was characterized by all of the following EXCEPT...",
    "answer": "Roman slaves had no legal protection when in conflict with their masters",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What Roman legal practice provides a reasonable context for understanding Paul's letter to Philemon?",
    "answer": "A slave who had wronged his or her master could seek arbitration and sanctuary through a colleague or friend of the master",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "There is evidence that Onesimus may have become one of the bishops of the church in Ephesus.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul uses puns in his letter to Philemon using the name of Onesimus, whose name means what?",
    "answer": "Useful",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Philemon probably lived in what Asian city?",
    "answer": "Colossae",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a fact concerning the person Onesimus?",
    "answer": "The head jailer of the prison where Paul is incarcerated",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a fact concerning the person Philemon",
    "answer": "He had a bitter argument with Paul",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Scholars have explained the dissimilarity of Ephesians with Paul's undisputed letters in all of the following ways except...",
    "answer": "Paul wrote Ephesians as a rough draft for Colossians, but it was mistakenly inserted into the collection of Paul's letters.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In English Bibles, Paul's letter to the Ephesians is addressed \"to the saints who are in Ephesus and are faithful in Christ Jesus.\" Some of the oldest Greek manuscripts are missing a few of these words. Which are the missing words?",
    "answer": "In Ephesians",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The \"mystery\" referred to in Ephesians concerns what?",
    "answer": "God's plan to unite all people in Christ",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the German word scholars use to describe discussions of family responsibilities in the Greco-Roman era?",
    "answer": "Haustafel",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not part of Ephesians' idea or perspective of the church?",
    "answer": "There are two dimensions of the church, the heavenly ministry inspired by Christ but also the sinful struggle of living in this world.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the \"table of household duties\" found in Ephesians is compared to such tables that were typical for this culture and time period, the most remarkable aspect is...",
    "answer": "The inclusion of instructions for husbands, fathers, and masters.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ephesus often earned the title neokoros for the region around the city. This title indicates that...",
    "answer": "Ephesus served as the official headquarters for the imperial cult",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the authors of the household codes of Colossians and Ephesians wrote them, they meant the codes to be applied exactly as they are in all times, places, and cultures.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Of the two letters, Ephesians and Colossians, scholars think Ephesians was written first.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Household Code in Ephesians challenges those in positions of power to give of themselves in selfless service to others.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is one main reason some scholars think Colossians may not be written by Paul?",
    "answer": "Colossians has a different style from Paul and a more developed theology",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Colossians presents Christ as exalted and cosmic in all of the following ways except...",
    "answer": "Christ descended to Hades",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a feature of or fact about the city of Colossae?",
    "answer": "Colossae was the hometown of the emperor Nero.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Colossians, spiritual growth and maturity are attained by doing what?",
    "answer": "Remaining steadfast in what has already been taught",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not an aspect or characteristic of the so-called \"Colossian heresy,\" that is, the philosophy or teaching that threatened their Christian identity and faith?",
    "answer": "Christ was fully divine but only appeared to be human.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Of the following options, which is not a distinctive, theologically well developed theme of Colossians (in comparison with Paul's undisputed letters) that causes some scholars to doubt Paul's authorship of the letter?",
    "answer": "A greater emphasis on pneumatology",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul was not the founder of, or missionary to, the churches in Colossae in the region of Phrygia. Who was the Christian pastor working with the Phrygian cities, including Colossae?",
    "answer": "Epaphras",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Letter to the Colossians represents a development in Paul's thought on a number of different religious topics (whether or not actually written by Paul).",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The letter of Colossians quotes an early Christian confession or hymn.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"Realized eschatology\" refers to the idea that the blessings of the end times can only be realized after Christ's Second Coming.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Philippians is written in the form of a/an...",
    "answer": "Friendship letter",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following are true descriptions of Philippi, except what?",
    "answer": "Philippi became a thriving port city to rival Corinth",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "One way Paul emphasizes unity in Philippians is to use which prefix on a variety of words?",
    "answer": "Syn",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a major theme in Philippians?",
    "answer": "False Apostles",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul urges the Philippians to have humility, which in this letter means what?",
    "answer": "To put others first and seek what is best for them",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What person exemplifying humility does Paul suggest the Philippians should imitate?",
    "answer": "Paul himself, Timothy, Epaphroditus",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which word used by Paul in Philippians would have had special meaning to those living in Philippi?",
    "answer": "Citizenship",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Christ Hymn in Philippians 2:6-11 is one of the earliest literary references to what?",
    "answer": "Jesus' Preexistence",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "When Paul writes Philippians, he knows that his own death may be near.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Some believe that the letter to the Philippians is actually composed of portions of two or three of Paul's letters edited together.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The church in Philippi gave generously to help Paul in his mission work.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Philippians, those who live in a manner worthy of the gospel will never suffer.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following issues divided the Corinthian church?",
    "answer": "Eating food offered to idols, Taking one another to court, Boasting about an incestuous relationship",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The two groups of Corinthian Christians, those who approved of prostitution and those who prohibited all sexual relationships (even in marriage), had a common commitment to what?",
    "answer": "Being Spirtual",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not one of the three guidelines that determines Paul's teaching about marriage in 1 Corinthians?",
    "answer": "God created all males and females for marriage",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What occurred between the writing of 1 and 2 Corinthians?",
    "answer": "-Paul made a visit to the corinthians during which he was hurt and humiliated<br>-Paul received news from Titus that the corinthian church had repented of hurting<br>-Paul wrote a letter challenging the church to prove their obedience to him and discipline an individual had wronged him",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the topic of 2 Corinthians 8-9?",
    "answer": "Fund-raising",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2 Corinthians, Paul is driven to boasting by whom?",
    "answer": "Super-apostles who tout their own credentials and achievements",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What effect did Paul's \"tearful\" letter have on the Corinthian churches?",
    "answer": "Repentance",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Problems arose around the Lord's Supper in the Corinthian church because...",
    "answer": "Wealthier members were eating food before the lower class members arrived after long hours of work.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does Paul think the Corinthian Christians should do with regard to eating food sacrificed to idols?",
    "answer": "Be willing to give up their rights for the sake of others",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul's initial plan to visit the Corinthians and his subsequent cancellation of that plan resulted in what accusation?",
    "answer": "Paul is unreliable and self interested.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the Greek word often used for the phenomenon of speaking in tongues?",
    "answer": "Glossolalia",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does Paul suggest the corinthians do instead of advocating for their own rights",
    "answer": "Consider other people first",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not true about Roman Corinth?",
    "answer": "As a colony it held steadfast to Roman morals and virtues",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What characterization best describes the church in Corinth?",
    "answer": "A divisive church with problems",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are scholarly hypotheses regarding the abrupt changes in tone found in 2 Corinthians?",
    "answer": "Paul was on the road, writing a little here and a little there, the letter itself is a compilation of a few different letters, in ancient letter writing, sharp transition were quite common",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who from the Corinthian congregation originally visited Paul and reported on the activities of other members in that church?",
    "answer": "Chloes people",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul taught that Jesus freed people from the Law and therefore freed people to do whatever they want.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "1 Corinthians is the first letter Paul wrote to the Corinthian church.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Lord's Supper (Eucharist) originally included a full meal.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Some believe that 2 Corinthians contains parts of three or more letters Paul wrote to the church in Corinth.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Romans, Paul uses the story of this Old Testament character to show that Jews and Gentiles can be saved by God's grace.",
    "answer": "Abraham",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to proponents of \"the new perspective on Paul,\" which of the following is probably Paul's main point in Romans?",
    "answer": "Salvation is universally available",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Romans, Paul says that \"all Israel will be saved,\" which has been interpreted as meaning what?",
    "answer": "A literal conversion of Jews will come about in the end times, a literal salvation of all Israel because of gods mercy and covenant with Israel, not \"Israel\" as an ethnic people but as a people, both jewish and gentile, who accept Israel's messiah",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Romans the word justification is most closely associated with what idea?",
    "answer": "Reconcolliation",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Romans, Paul teaches that church members who know that it is permissible to eat the food which others think it is sinful to eat should do what?",
    "answer": "Avoid eating that food as an accommodation to those who might be offended by their action",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "When and from where does Paul write Romans?",
    "answer": "Corinth in the year 57 or 58",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a proposed reason why Paul wrote Romans?",
    "answer": "To reestablish contact with the Roman church that he had established during his second missionary journey",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Romans 8, the earth itself will be redeemed along with God's people.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul established the church in Rome.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul tells the Roman Christians that he hopes to share the gospel message to the west as far as England after he visits them.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBL 102.01 Test 2 Laura Callarman Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281059867/bibl-10201-test-2-laura-callarman-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "120",
    "answer": "How many people spoke in tongues on the day of Pentecost?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/35373195/bible-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "3000, then 5000",
    "answer": "Christian Jews were estimated to be in what numerical count according to the book of Acts?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/35373195/bible-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Acts of The Holy Spirit, Acts of the Risen Lord Jesus Christ",
    "answer": "Although traditionally called Acts of the Apostles, Powell suggests it could better be called what?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/35373195/bible-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ephesians, then Galatians",
    "answer": "Base don't he modern methods of measurements, what should be the arrangement of Paul's letters?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/35373195/bible-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Holy Spirit, his followers, the word, the use of his name",
    "answer": "How is Jesus present after the ascension?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/35373195/bible-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "2",
    "answer": "How many Herod Agrippas are in Acts?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/35373195/bible-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Preach, speak in tongues, and perform miracles",
    "answer": "The Holy Spirit enables the apostles to do what?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/35373195/bible-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Written by James, brother of Jesus",
    "answer": "Who wrote James?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/35373195/bible-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Thessalonica",
    "answer": "Important city<br>diverse city<br>visited by Paul c 48-51<br><br>In Paul's ministry:<br>-he stays serval months<br>-practices a trade<br>-forced out of the city<br>-takes refuge in Corinth<br>-tries to visit again but can't.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "1 Thessalonians",
    "answer": "Dates c 49-52<br>-from Paul, Silas, and Timothy<br>-written from Corinth<br>-was a response to Timothys visit back to Thessalonica<br>- general structure of a typical letter<br><b>Purpose</b><br>-celebrating and confirming relationship<br>-reminding young believers of the importance of what they've seen and learned<br>-addressing a misunderstanding about Jesus' return and the resurrection of believers.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jesus' Parousia",
    "answer": "Not a theology of the rapture, means second coming",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Themes in 1 thessalonians WCSH",
    "answer": "<b>Working for a living</b> <br>-dont be idle while awaiting Jesus' return<br>-dont burden the church; rather, support it<br><b>conduct of Paul's ministry</b><br>-pauls actions demonstrate upright conduct<br>-depth of devotion as family<br>-defensive or inspirational?<br><b>Honor and Shame</b><br>-Believers suffering loss of esteem and prestige<br>-honored by God, unlike their neighbors<br>-create a culture of honor among themselves. <br>-Keep a low, peaceful profile with outsiders<br><b>Sexual Morality</b><br>Abstain from extramarital, exploitative, and lustful sex<br>-sexuality as an obvious distinction between believer and non-beliver",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Themes of 2 Thessalonians CDP",
    "answer": "<b>Certainty of Judgement</b><br>-opponents of Christianity will \"Suffer the punishment of eternal destruction\" (1:9)<br>-distinct from Paul's perspectives elsewhere<br>-surprisingly positive emphasis<br><b>Day of the Lord Has Not Yet Come</b><br>-in a response to claims that it had come and gone<br>- parousia won't occur until the \"lawless one\" has been unrestrained and revealed.<br>-Jesus' return will be unmistakeable and certain things have to happen before hand.<br><b>Problem of Idleness</b><br>-Some believers taking advantage of the community's generosity<br>-Paul and his companions as examples<br>-deny food to those not willing to work<br>-believers are living at the start of the end times and must live faithfully and healthily as they wait.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Comparison of 1 and 2 Thessalonians",
    "answer": "both Paul, Silas, and timothy.<br><b>1 Thessalonians</b><br>-judgment and destruction coming<br>-idlers to be demolished<br>-all should hear the letter<br><b>2 Thessalonians</b><br>-Gleeful about judgement and destruction<br>-idlers to be denied food<br>-all should obey the letter.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Authorship of 2 Thessalonians",
    "answer": "Is Paul restating his own materials more darkly or is someone else reworking 1 Thessalonians?<br>How can we even attempt to determine? <br>-placement within Paul's career<br>-style similarities or differences<br>-content and themes<br><b>Scenario 1</b><br>-written by Paul from Corinth a few months after 1 Thessalonians<br>-in response to a new theological crisis<br><b>Scenario 2</b><br>-written by someone else after Paul's death (Maybe around 80)<br>-summarizing later views on the parousia<br>-meant for circulation throughout the church",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Galatians",
    "answer": "Destination and Dating:<br>- to believers Paul evangelized<br>-Galatia: a roman province in cereal Anatolia (Modern Day Turkey)<br>-if to southern Galatia (Derbe, Lystra, etc)<br>-if to northern Galatia- Mid 50's<br>up in the air if before or after the Acts 15 council.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Judaizers",
    "answer": "Rival teachers, undermining Paul<br>-Jews who preached salvation through Christ is only for Jews<br>-Gentiles must commit to Jewish law and circumcision to correctly follow Christ<br>-Paul is not a trustworthy teacher<br>Tone is Mad!<br>-no thanksgiving section<br>he is astonished, calls them foolish, and wishes they would emasculate themselves.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pauls response",
    "answer": "Astonishment<br>-turning to a different gospel<br>on the defensive<br>-conflict with Peter<br>Thesis statement <br>on the offensive<br>-galatians are fools (but he loves them)<br>-true purpose of the law<br>-meaning of freedom<br>exhortations and summary.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul's authority in Galatians",
    "answer": "<b>Reestablishing attacked credibility portrayed as:</b><br>-misunderstanding/misrepresenting the gospel<br>-latecomer who didn't know Jesus<br>-having only derivative authority if his ideas are vouched for by reliable church leaders.<br><b>response:</b><br>-his authority is not derived from others<br>-his views are affirmed by (and even influential with) church leaders. <br>-but he doesn't need their affirmation because his message is directly from Jesus",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Christ and the Law in Galatians JGLT",
    "answer": "<b>Justification by faith, not works.</b><br>-pistis tou Christou - faith in Jesus/faithfulness of Jesus<br><b>Gods favor is universal in scope</b><br>-there is no favored group<br><b>living in a new era</b><br>-old covenant is obsolete and inappropriate<br><b>the spirit produces what the law cannot</b><br>-new creation, characterized by fruit of the spirit.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul's Evidence EAS",
    "answer": "<b>Paul appeals to experience</b><br>-did you receive the spirit by doing the works of the law or by believing what you heard? - 3:2<br><b>Paul appeals to Abrahams example</b><br>-god made promises to Abraham through faith, before circumcision<br>-like Abraham we receive the promise of the spirit through faith (without circumcision) 3:14 <br><b>Paul appeals to sociocultural values</b><br>-law enslaves; spirit frees and makes us children, \"for freedom Christ has set us free\" (5:1)",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The conclusion of Galatians and the Law",
    "answer": "The grace filled gospel from God about the cross and spirit is sufficient for entry into, and life within, gods covenant people. Circumcised and following jewish sumo and law are inappropriate. <br><br>the Law:<br>-was later than the promise and thus can't change it<br>-wasn't opposed to the promise, but because of sin couldn't deliver life<br>-had an important but temporary role until the promise was fulfilled.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Central Issue of Galatians",
    "answer": "IS NOT: are we saved by grace or by works? (Martin Luther)<br><br>IT IS: must the gentiles be circumcised and required to keep the Law in order to be considered a part of the covenant people of God? If not, how else will they be transformed?",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Philemon background",
    "answer": "-undisputedly from Paul<br>-pauls shortest letter<br>-written while Paul was in prison, probably from Ephesus in 54-55 OR from Rome in 60-61",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Philemon",
    "answer": "Probably lives in/near colossae<br>wealthy and influential<br>friend and co worker, but also Paul's disciple",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Onesimus",
    "answer": "Recent convert beloved by Paul<br>useless or useful?<br>-achrestos/achristos/onesimos<br>has wronged Philemon somehow<br>-likely causing financial loss<br>-Paul will pay the debt<br>-Paul asks Philemon to welcome onesimus back<br>slave or brother?<br>Paul wants him back",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Slavery in the Roman World",
    "answer": "-Large slave population, one fourth or one third of empire<br>-variety of ways of becoming a slave<br>-wide range of conditions and experiences<br>-no honor or autonomy and few legal rights",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Major themes of Philemon PP, PS",
    "answer": "<b>Paul's powers of persuasion</b><br>-reminder of philemon's generosity<br>-who really owes whom<br>-Paul has authority to command but doesn't<br>-playing on phileon's sympathies and guilt?<br>-Paul's upcoming visit<br>-public reading of the letter. <br><br><b>Paul's Perspective on slavery</b><br>-Doesn't reject it outright<br>-may consider it irrelevant<br>-may not be sharing his full opinion<br>-goes out of his way to assist a particular slave<br>-calls for good, just treatment of slaves<br>-\"Slave for christ\"<br><br>in the end, it likely favorable for onesimus, and he might have even been a bishop.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Literary Siblings of collosians and Ephesians",
    "answer": "Use of distinct style (sentence length, wording, redundancy), 1/3-1/2 of the verses in Ephesians have parallels are often repeated in the same order some passages are repeated almost word for word.<br><br>Thematic similarities<br>-Cosmic, victorious Christ<br>-Cosmic, Mysterious church<br>-realized eschatology<br>-liturgical style<br>-implications for everyday life.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Contexts for Colossae and Ephesus",
    "answer": "<b>Colassae</b><br>-one of the 3 cities of the Lycus River Valley<br>-Hellenized Jews, Pagan cults, mystery religions<br>-Epapharas was local preacher and teacher<br>-tied to Philemon<br>-Earthquake of 61 CE<br>-warns against Collossian Heresy<br><b>Ephesus</b><br>-Capital and financial center of Asia<br>-Temple of Artemis (one of the seven wonders of the world)<br>-neokoros of the region<br>-visited by Paul twice; he lived in Ephesus 2-3<br>-encourages belief in God's plan and identity in Christ",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Colossians outline and themes",
    "answer": "<b>Outline</b><br>Salutation, thanksgiving, prayer<br>christ hymn<br>theological implications<br>-christ in you, the hope of glory<br>-dont be deceived by human philosophies<br>ethical exhortation<br>closing<br><b>Themes</b><br>High Christology<br>-focus on Jesus' divinity<br>-exalted terms with universal implications<br>realized eschatology<br>-end times blessings are available now!<br>-not a logical temporal chronology<br>knowledge and maturity<br>remain in the body and bear fruit",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ephesians Outline and themes",
    "answer": "<b>Outline</b><br>-salutation, blessings, and thanksgiving<br>-Saved by grace and made alive as one new humanity<br>-live a life worthy of that calling, one that is unified in community and that has behaviors that are set apart.<br>closing<br><b>Themes</b><br>God's mysterious hidden plan to unite all things in christ<br>-elevation of the universal church (Interdependent and unified)<br>the idealized believer.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Household Codes in Ephesians (5:21 - 6:9) and Colossians (3:18-4:1)",
    "answer": "-Adresses all major relationships of the household<br>-adresses members of lesser AND greater power<br>-fits and challenges culture of its day<br>-portrays church as God's household<br>-based on social distinctions and theological convictions <br>-christ is the perfect, self denying model.<br>-weird thing in this that is different from normal codes is that it gives rules for husbands, fathers, and masters.<br>\"Based on social distinction, not on gender characteristics, and on the proportional relationship of self denial to ones privileges of status and power\"",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Collosians vs Ephesians, By Paul or not by Paul?",
    "answer": "<b>Colossians</b><br>-ties to philemon<br>-stylistic differences<br>-different theological ideas<br>-pauls later, contextualized theological developments?<br>-or someone else's attempt to be faithful to Paul's thoughts crediting him?<br><b>Ephesians</b><br>-based off of Colossians?<br>-stylistic and conceptual differences<br>-odd tone for a close relationship<br>-not actually a letter to the Ephesians?<br>-Just different to actually inconsistent?",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Colossians vs Ephesians Authorship scenarios",
    "answer": "<b>Colossians</b><br>-by Paul as occasional letter (early 60's)<br>-by a pseudonymous author<br>-disciple (late 60's)<br>-admirer(s) (80's)<br><b>Ephesians</b><br>-by Paul as circular letter (late 60's)<br>-by a pseudonymous author (disciple (70's-80's) or admirer (early 90's)<br>-by the same pseudonymous author<br>-by a different pseudonymous author (early 90's)<br><br>Are Colossians and Ephesians \"the mature fruit of Pauls thought\" \"An inspired reinterpretation of pauls thought\" or the beginning distortion of Paul's thought\"",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Phillipians historical background",
    "answer": "Philipi<br>-Farming community in macedonia<br>a point of connection and trade<br>-a history of importance and pride<br>-retirement community of roman citizens<br>-first European church; full of loyal converts<br><br>written by Paul at some later date, from prison. <br>-possible composite letter as there are three conclusions, section with a different tone, out of place thanksgiving, multiple timelines.<br>there are 1, 2, and 3, letter theories<br>-a friendship letter<br><b>Overview</b><br>-salutation, prayer of thanksgiving<br>discussion of pauls imprisonment<br>-apeal for humility and unity (kinetic hymn)<br>call to suffering, unlike false teachers<br>-exhortations, thanks, closing greetings",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Incarnation in phillipians",
    "answer": "key biblical passage (2:6-11 and John 1:1-18)<br>christs preexistence<br>could be a challenge to monotheism?",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Themes in philipians HSFF",
    "answer": "<b>Humility</b><br>proper sense of self in a universe of wonders, of which you are one.<br>-placing others interests ahead of ones own<br>-possible based upon following examples<br>-Jesus- the ultimate example<br>-timothy, epaphroditus, Paul<br>promise of ultimate exaltation<br>reflections based upon a particular problem?<br><b>Suffering</b><br>inevitability and potential value of suffering<br>-can have positive effects<br>-sharing in the suffering of Jesus<br>ultimate reunification with christ and vindication of suffering<br>-Paul understands and so does Jesus<br>-not an attempt to answer the problem of evil<br><b>friendship and fellowship</b><br>koinonia and syn-everything<br>emphasis on being in this together<br>unique relationship with Paul<br>love of christ as the foundation<br><b>Fellow Citizens</b><br>rights and responsibilities of citizens<br>ideal citizens contrasted with the non-ideal<br>living as citizens of heaven<br>-in a wold dominated my the empire<br>-in a way that makes allegiances clear<br>-in patience and hopeful expectation for our ultimate home",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Corinthians context",
    "answer": "Corinth:<br>capital city of Achaia, ports city<br>-one of the largest and most prosperous cities in the ancient world<br>-50 miles and a worldview away from athens<br>-haven for the rich and upwardly mobile<br>-open to new ideas, tolerant of diversity<br>-lavish lifestyles and conspicuous consumption (Las Vegas of Its day)<br>Paul spent 18+ months there, (50-53)<br>-ethnically and socially diverse community",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Corinthian Correspondence",
    "answer": "First: The \"Lost letter mentioned n 1 corinthians<br>then: Chloe sends people with a report, and the corinthians write back with questions.<br><br>Second: 1 corinthians sent around 53-57<br>Then:Paul planned a visit, surprised the church early, then canceled original visit. Possible conflict with \"super apostles\"<br><br>Third: The lost letter \"of tears\" Paul sent with Titus <br>Then: Paul experiences \"trials\" in Asia, Titus returns with a report about the corinthians. <br><br>fourth: 2 corinthians written around 55-58.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "2 Corinthians",
    "answer": "could be a patchwork epistle? many letters are referred to in its writing, thought to be 6<br><br>Pro: disjointed content, abrupt transitions, extreme mood swings<br><br>con: thematic coherence (pauls relationship with the corinthians, unity that pauls ministry seeks), rhetorical function of strong emotions.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Practical problems in 1 corinthians",
    "answer": "Community factions - unity in christ by spirit<br><br>obsession with worldly wisdom and power - gods wisdom and power shown in human weakness and foolishness<br><br>fully actualized salvation NOW - Christ crucified: salvation has yet to be fully realized<br><br>body is irrelevant- only spiritual purity matters. bodily resurrection - the body is home to the spirit<br><br>social divisions in the lords supper by class and status - wait for one another, do not humiliate the poor. <br><br>We are Free! Therefore, all things are lawful - we are slaves of christ - all is lawful, but then ask \"is this good for me and for Christs body?\"<br><br>boasting about sexual freedoms<br>-do not boast! Excommunicate the offender<br><br>only the spirit matters (deny the body, its bad - abstinence in marriage. Indulge the body, it doesn't matter - prostitution and adultery)- the body matters too: it can glorify God, care for the body, teachings on abstinence, celibacy, marriage, and divorce. Be of the greater possible service to God and the community with your body<br><br>Food Sacrificed to idols DO NOT EAT or idols have no power- you can eat it. Done participate in idol worship, food is food BUT better not to eat if it harms a brother or sister. agree with the strong, side with the weak. <br><br>spiritual gifts, especially glossolalia - don't let them be disruptive or a source of pride, but don't totally prohibit them. part of the diverse but unified body, use them well to build up the community. <br><br>Love - agape- unmotivated unmerited love. defined in terms of unselfish behavior, put in the context of the ekklesia.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Themes of 2 corinthians PAHG",
    "answer": "<b>Pauls ministry</b><br>-from God<br>-based on close relationship with corinthians<br><b>apostolic authority</b><br>-Paul claims a great deal of authority<br>-how to tell true apostles apart from false ones, at least in this scenario<br><b>humility and boasting</b><br>-Paul can legitimately boast - in strength and in weakness<br>-human weakness reveals God's true power<br><b>Giving/fundraising</b><br>-a privilege as stewards and caretakers<br>-inspired by Jesus, to bring glory to God.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "New Perspective on Paul",
    "answer": "Salvation happens through faith rather than obedience to covenant law. proponents of this emphasize pauls point on the universal scope and availability of salvation.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Themes of Romans",
    "answer": "<b>Gods righteousness</b><br>Emphasis on God's righteousness as displayed through Jesus' self offering<br>god shows faithfulness and generosity by showing grace to all humanity<br><b>Justification through faithfulness</b><br>to be restored into right relationship with God<br>occurs through pistes Christou<br>-peoples faith in God<br>-God's faithfulness to promises<br>-Jesus' faithful obedience to God<br><b>God and Israel</b><br>it is all in gods hands<br>metaphor of tree and grafting<br><b>Obedience of faith</b><br>-Christ the new Adam<br>-obedience comes through faith<br><b>Death and resurrection</b><br>-connects justification to Christs death and resurrection<br>-through baptism people participate in Christs death and resurrection",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Live in christ like friendship. imitate the self emptying love demonstrated by Jesus",
    "answer": "Philippians",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul adresses questions and issues a church has around sex, gifts, the lords supper, and more.",
    "answer": "1 corinthians",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "dont be deceived by empty human philosophies, but trust \"christ in you, the hope of glory \"",
    "answer": "Colossians",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Salvation is found in faith in Christ and not works of the law",
    "answer": "Galatians",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Follows these instructions on how to live at the beginning of the end times, but before Jesus second coming",
    "answer": "1 and 2 thessalonians",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul adresses challenges from \"super apostles\" to the integrity of his ministry",
    "answer": "2 corinthians",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "God is working to incorporate gentiles into the people of God while still being faithful to prior promises to Israel",
    "answer": "Romans",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The church is the mystery of Gods eternal plan to bring Jews and Gentiles together as one new humanity",
    "answer": "Ephesians",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul builds a broken relationship in not so subtle ways",
    "answer": "Philemon",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "BIBLE 102.01 Laura Callarman Slides and Study guide",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281454247/bible-10201-laura-callarman-slides-and-study-guide-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The theological view, rooted in temple sacrifice, that says people have sinned against God and God therefore demands a sacrifice to set the relationship right again is called ___________.",
    "answer": "Atonement",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "When Jesus restores believers to a right relationship with God, this is called __________.",
    "answer": "Justification by faith",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Paul's letters and Acts, which of the following is not an aspect of Paul's early life?",
    "answer": "Paul was born in Jerusalem",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Paul, how is God faithful to God's promises to Israel?",
    "answer": "Salvation comes through a Jewish messiah",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Powell, \"The cross becomes the emblem not only of Christian salvation, but of Christian ______________.\"",
    "answer": "Conduct",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to proponents of \"the new perspective on Paul,\" which of the following is probably Paul's main point in Romans?",
    "answer": "Salvation is universally available",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Acts records that Paul __________.",
    "answer": "Was a Roman citizen",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "For Paul, Christian ethics are shaped primarily by what?",
    "answer": "The imitation of Christ",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "For what reason was Paul writing to the churches in Rome?",
    "answer": "All of the above",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "If actually written by Paul, which two letters would be dated at the same time as his letter to Philemon?",
    "answer": "Ephesians &amp; Colossians",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Judaism, which rite is viewed as a sign of the covenant God made with Israel?",
    "answer": "Circumcision",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Romans 6, Paul interprets this ritual as the believer's participation in Christ's death, burial, and resurrection.",
    "answer": "Baptism",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Romans the word justification is most closely associated with what idea?",
    "answer": "Reconciliation",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Romans, Paul interprets Israel's \"rejection of Christ\" as __________.",
    "answer": "An example of God's mysterious purpose",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Romans, Paul says that \"all Israel will be saved,\" which has been interpreted as what?",
    "answer": "All of the above",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Romans, Paul teaches that church members who know that it is permissible to eat food that others think it is sinful to eat should do what?",
    "answer": "Forgo eating that food as an accommodation to those who might be offended by their action",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the Book of Acts, Paul is also known by this Hebrew name.",
    "answer": "Saul",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "It is generally believed that Paul spent the interim years between his conversion and his first missionary journey doing what?",
    "answer": "Honing his missionary skills and developing his theological understanding of the gospel",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Many chronologies of Paul's life start with the connection to this governor who served in Corinth from the summer of 51 to the summer of 52.",
    "answer": "Gallio",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Of the material available for understanding Paul's life and thought, what are the primary sources?",
    "answer": "Seven undisputed letters of Paul",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "One image for explaining how Christ justifies people is atonement, which basically means what?",
    "answer": "Jesus dies on the cross to offer a supreme sacrifice that fulfills God's requirement for nullifying sin",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul encourages the Roman Christians to give money for a collection to be offered for what purpose?",
    "answer": "The care of the poor in Jerusalem",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul is known for his focus on ___________.",
    "answer": "Jesus' death and resurrection",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul uses the story of this Old Testament character to show that Jews and Gentiles can be saved by God's grace.",
    "answer": "Abraham",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul uses the words \"mind\" and \"heart\" as synonyms.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul was a member of which Jewish tribe?",
    "answer": "Benjamin",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul was a young man when he witnessed the martyrdom of Stephen, but he considers himself an old man when he pens which letter?",
    "answer": "Philemon",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul's letters and the Book of Acts agree that Paul...",
    "answer": "Worked with his hands",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Powell notes that some scholars believe Paul's three missionary journeys in Acts are...",
    "answer": "A literary device",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Since the Reformation, what have most interpreters regarded as the main theme of Romans?",
    "answer": "Justification by faith",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Some scholars argue that \"Paul transformed the message of Jesus to a message _________ Jesus.\"",
    "answer": "About",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "People have been unfaithful to God and destroyed the relationship between humanity and God. When Jesus repairs this relationship this is called ____________.",
    "answer": "Reconciliation",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The \"New Perspective\" on Paul suggests that his language about being \"saved by grace through faith\" is not a statement against \"works\" but a statement against _______________.",
    "answer": "Ethnic (Jewish) privilege",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The term justification comes from what kind of language in the traditions of Israel?",
    "answer": "Covenantal",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "This written source helps scholars to understand the order of events in Paul's life.",
    "answer": "Acts of the Apostles",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "To which Jewish group did Paul belong?",
    "answer": "Pharisees",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the \"dynamic force\" that Paul calls \"the power of God for salvation to everyone who believes\" in his letter to the Romans?",
    "answer": "The gospel",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the thesis of Paul's letter to the Romans?",
    "answer": "The gospel reveals the righteousness of God",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What trade did Paul engage in to support his missionary activity?",
    "answer": "Tentmaker",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "When and from where does Paul write Romans?",
    "answer": "Corinth in the year 57 or 58",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "When preaching about Jesus in new areas, Paul usually follows which basic pattern?",
    "answer": "He targets urban, commercial settings",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which emperor expelled Jews from the city of Rome in 49CE because of disturbances due to \"Chrestus\"?",
    "answer": "Claudius",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of Paul's letters was written during his second missionary journey?",
    "answer": "1 Thessalonians",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following beliefs did Paul not change when he became a Christian?",
    "answer": "His identity as a Pharisee",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following does Powell suggest would have disturbed Paul?",
    "answer": "Catholics and Protestants are divided over their interpretation of Romans",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a proposed reason why Paul wrote Romans?",
    "answer": "To reestablish contact with the Roman church that he had established during his second missionary journey",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following women did Paul regard as \"prominent among the Apostles\"?",
    "answer": "Junia",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following women does Paul commend to the Roman Christians as a deacon of the church in Cenchrea?",
    "answer": "Phoebe",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following women, frequently mentioned elsewhere in the New Testament, does Paul state risked her life for and has earned the thanks of all Gentile Christians?",
    "answer": "Prisca",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tense does Paul use when speaking of justification by faith in Romans?",
    "answer": "Present",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the two people below who were the married couple that lied to the Holy Spirit about their money in Acts 5.",
    "answer": "Ananias and Sapphira",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who probably delivered Paul's letter to the Romans?",
    "answer": "Phoebe",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What characteristic does the author of Acts often associate with the early church's life and mission?",
    "answer": "Joy",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Acts of the Apostles focuses on which two apostles?",
    "answer": "Paul and Peter",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Approximately how much of the Book of Acts is speeches?",
    "answer": "30%",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Geographical Framework in the book of Acts covers which of the following geographical areas?",
    "answer": "Jerusalem, Judea, Samaria, The ends of the earth",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Acts, the Gentile mission...",
    "answer": "Begins in Jerusalem and spreads to all nations",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a feature of letter writing in ancient times as reflected in the New Testament letters?",
    "answer": "The mandatory use of official Roman stamps or imprints on letters",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the Book of Acts, the Holy Spirit ______.",
    "answer": "Empowers the apostles to preach and perform miracles",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the \"We Passages\" in Acts?",
    "answer": "Passages where the author writes as a traveling companion of Paul",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The book of Acts is known as what type of biography?",
    "answer": "Cultic Biography",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In ancient times, people wrote letters on...",
    "answer": "All of the above",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Acts, the mission to the Gentile churches in the name of Jesus is...",
    "answer": "Successful",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What term is used for the secretary or trained scribe who writes letters for other people?",
    "answer": "Amanuensis",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Seven letters addressed to the church at large are called what?",
    "answer": "The Catholic Epistles",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following New Testament letters is not anonymous?",
    "answer": "Jude",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which New Testament books are frequently counted among the Prison or Captivity Epistles?",
    "answer": "Ephesians, Philippians, Colossians",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "One basis for determining pseudepigraphy is historical anachronism. The anachronism discussed specifically by Powell works from an assumption that the early church originally lacked something which eventually became well-developed. What was it the early church supposedly lacked?",
    "answer": "A hierarchy",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Determining the authenticity of a Pauline letter (or any other New Testament letter) is important for also determining...",
    "answer": "The historical context of a letter",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of Paul's letters lacks a thanksgiving section, probably indicating his anger and disappointment?",
    "answer": "Galatians",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Luke's representation of Paul in Acts is sometimes regarded as inaccurate because in contrast to Paul's own letters the \"Paul of Acts\" __________.",
    "answer": "All of the above",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the most common writing material in the first century?",
    "answer": "Papyrus",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many missionary journeys of Paul are recorded in Acts?",
    "answer": "Three",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Acts, Luke portrays most people as...",
    "answer": "Just, respectable, and sympathetic",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the context of authorship and pseudepigraphy, what is honorable pseudepigraphy?",
    "answer": "-Admirers write letters in the name of a deceased leader in tribute to his influence, believing themselves to be responsible bearers of his tradition",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Based on modern methods of measurement, which one of Paul's letters should technically be placed in front of Galatians?",
    "answer": "Ephesians",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Powell, all of the following are reasons Luke wrote Acts except...",
    "answer": "To demonstrate the love and compassion of God through Christ for Roman rulers",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which section of Paul's letters sometimes hints at topics that will be addressed in greater detail later?",
    "answer": "Thanksgiving",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Acts, Paul presents the theology of...",
    "answer": "Luke",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following New Testament letters does not belong among the undisputed letters of Paul?",
    "answer": "Ephesians",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which books of the New Testament do scholars often call the Pastoral Epistles?",
    "answer": "1 &amp; 2 Timothy, Titus",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "During the Cold War between Democratic Capitalism and Communism, the Marxists accused the Christian church of failing to live up to its what?",
    "answer": "Communistic nature",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many of the 27 New Testament books appear to be letters?",
    "answer": "21",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which portion of Paul's letters tends to be somewhat haphazard, not adhering to normal conventions with any sort of regularity?",
    "answer": "Closing",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the label given to confessional statements that summarize key articles of faith?",
    "answer": "Creed",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which letters attributed to Paul are difficult to fit into what is known about Paul's life from his other letters and the Book of Acts and therefore viewed as pseudepigraphal by some?",
    "answer": "1 Timothy &amp; Titus",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the New Testament, Paul's letters are arranged...",
    "answer": "From longest to shortest",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Acts is an optimistic book insofar as ________.",
    "answer": "All of the above",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Although traditionally called \"The Acts of the Apostles,\" Powell suggests it could better be called \"The Acts of _______.\"",
    "answer": "The Holy Spirit",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the first gift given to the Christian community by the Holy Spirit in Acts chapter 2.",
    "answer": "Proclamation",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "How is Jesus present in the book of Acts, after his ascension and before his Second Coming (Parousia)?",
    "answer": "All of the Above",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a typical Christian greeting in an ancient letter?",
    "answer": "Grace and Peace",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The early church, as recorded in the Book of Acts, sought to eliminate what?",
    "answer": "Poverty",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The stories about a disciple named Apollos, a silversmith named Demetrius, and seven sons of Sceva in Acts all occur in which city?",
    "answer": "Ephesus",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Acts 1:8 the Holy Spirit was given to Jesus' disciples so they could serve as his what?",
    "answer": "Witnesses",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Scholars who think that the New Testament letters ought to be considered authentic writing (not pseudepigraphical) may argue that...",
    "answer": "All of the above",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many kings named Herod Agrippa are mentioned in Acts?",
    "answer": "Two",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In contrast to Paul, Acts emphasizes this aspect of the Holy Spirit.",
    "answer": "External manifestations of power",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is counted among the deutero-Pauline letters?",
    "answer": "Ephesians",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which word meaning \"false ascription\" as applied to the practice of ancient authors attributing their own writings to other people?",
    "answer": "Pseudepigraphy",
    "user": "cheerleadercmw",
    "pageTitle": "Bible 2 Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/19947140/bible-2-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Speeches take up approximately how much space in the Book of Acts",
    "answer": "30%",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Although traditionally called \"The Acts of the Apostles,\" Powell suggests it could better be called \"The Acts of ________\"",
    "answer": "The Holy Spirit",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the context of authorship and pseudepigraphy, what is honorable pseudepigraphy",
    "answer": "Admirers write letters in the name of a deceased leader in tribute to his influence, believing themselves to be responsible bearers of his tradition",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In contrast to Paul's letters, the book of Acts emphasizes this aspect of the Holy Spirit",
    "answer": "External manifestations of power",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the New Testament, Paul's letters are arranged",
    "answer": "From longest to shortest",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "One image for explaining how Christ justifies people is atonement, which basically means what",
    "answer": "Jesus dies on the cross to offer a supreme sacrifice that fulfills God's requirement for nullifying sin",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "For Paul, Christian ethics are shaped primarily by what?",
    "answer": "The imitation of Christ",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Romans, Paul uses the story of this Old Testament character to show that Jews and Gentiles can be saved by God's grace",
    "answer": "Abraham",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "People have been unfaithful to God and destroyed the relationship between humanity and God. When Jesus repairs this relationship this is called...",
    "answer": "Reconciliation",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul was a member of which Jewish tribe?",
    "answer": "Benjamin",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Acts, the mission to the Gentiles in the name of Jesus is...",
    "answer": "Successful",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Tradition says James was written by whom?",
    "answer": "Jesus' brother",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many kings named Herod Agrippa are mentioned in Acts?",
    "answer": "Two",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many missionary journeys of Paul are recorded in Acts?",
    "answer": "Three",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Determining the authenticity of a Pauline letter (or any other New Testament letter) is important for also determining...",
    "answer": "The historical context of a letter",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Scholars who think that the New Testament letters ought to be considered authentic writing (not pseudepigraphical) may argue that...",
    "answer": "All of the above<br>(Early church traditions about authorship are generally reliable; early Christians would have viewed pseudepigraphy as a dishonest practice; linguistic and other features that make the letter seem non-Pauline can be explained through Paul's use of an amanuensis)",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many of the 27 New Testament books appear to be letters?",
    "answer": "21",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "How is Jesus present in the book of Acts after his ascension into Heaven and before his Second Coming (Parousia)?",
    "answer": "All of the above<br>(Through the Holy Spirit; through Jesus' followers; through the word of God)",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a typical Christian greeting in an ancient letter?",
    "answer": "Grace and Peace",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "One basis for determining pseudepigraphy is historical anachronism. The anachronism discussed specifically by Powell works from an assumption that the early church originally lacked something which eventually became well-developed. What was it the early church supposedly lacked?",
    "answer": "A hierarchy",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Seven letters addressed to the church at large are called what?",
    "answer": "The Catholic Epistles",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In ancient times, people wrote letters on...",
    "answer": "All of the above <br>(Pottery shards; papyrus; animal skin)",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Acts is an optimistic book insofar as...",
    "answer": "All of the above<br>(Persecution serves to spread the gospel; everything always works out for the best; controversies are quickly resolved)",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Acts, the Gentile mission...",
    "answer": "Begins in Jerusalem and spreads to all nations",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Based on modern methods of measurement, which one of Paul's letters should technically be placed in front of Galatians?",
    "answer": "Ephesians",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Many chronologies of Paul's life start with the connection to this governor who served in Corinth from the summer of 51 to the summer of 52.",
    "answer": "Gallio",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Of the material available for understanding Paul's life and thought, what are the primary sources?",
    "answer": "Seven undisputed letters of Paul",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Romans 6, Paul interprets this ritual as the believer's participation in Christ's death, burial, and resurrection.",
    "answer": "Baptism",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the book of Acts, Paul is also known by this Hebrew name.",
    "answer": "Saul",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Romans, the word \"justification\" is closely associated with what idea?",
    "answer": "Reconciliation",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Judaism, which rite is viewed as a sign of the covenant that God made with Israel?",
    "answer": "Circumcision",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "For what reason was Paul writing to the Romans?",
    "answer": "All of the above<br>(To gain support for his next missionary journey; to offer theological advice on specific problems; to ask for contributions to the collection)",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to proponents of \"the new perspective on Paul,\" which of the following is probably Paul's main point in Romans?",
    "answer": "Salvation is universally available",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "If actually written by Paul, which two letters would be dated at the same time as his letter to Philemon?",
    "answer": "Ephesians &amp; Colossians",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Paul's letters and Acts, which of the following is not an aspect of Paul's early life?",
    "answer": "Paul was born in Jerusalem",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Acts, Luke portrays most people who are unfamiliar with Jesus as...",
    "answer": "Just, respectable, and sympathetic",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In writing letters, Paul used a/an",
    "answer": "Amanuensis",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Powell, all of the following are reasons Luke wrote Acts execpt...",
    "answer": "To demonstrate the love and compassion of God through Christ for Roman rulers",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Acts, Paul presents the theology of...",
    "answer": "Luke",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of books is Acts?",
    "answer": "History",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul was known for his focus on what part of the story about Jesus?",
    "answer": "Jesus' death and resurrection",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Powell, \"The cross becomes the emblem not only of Christian salvation, but of Christian____________\"",
    "answer": "Conduct",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Paul's letter to the Romans, how is God faithful to God's promises to Israel?",
    "answer": "Salvation comes through the Jewish messiah",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul was a young man when he witnessed the death of the first Christian martyr, but he considers himself an old man when he pens which letter?",
    "answer": "Philemon",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "After Paul's conversion, his thinking changed in all of the following ways except...",
    "answer": "Before: Jesus was a prophet sent by God; After: Jesus is the Son of God and Lord of all",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "It is generally believed that Paul spent the interim years between his conversion and his first missionary journey doing what?",
    "answer": "Honing his missionary skills and developing his theological understanding of the gospel",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Roman's, Paul interprets Israel's \"rejection of Christ\" as...",
    "answer": "An example of God's mysterious purpose",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Romans, Paul teaches that church members who know that it is permissible to eat the food which others think it is sinful to eat should do what?",
    "answer": "Avoid eating that food as an accommodation to those who might be offended by their action",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Romans, Paul say that \"all Israel will be saved,\" which has been interpreted as meaning what?",
    "answer": "All of the above<br>(Not \"Israel\" as an ethnic people but as a people, both Jewish and Gentile, who accept Israel's messiah; a literal salvation of of all Israel because of God's mercy and and covenant with Israel; a literal conversion of Jews will come about in the end times)",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul encourages the Roman Christians to give money for a collection to be offered for what purpose?",
    "answer": "The care of the poor in Jerusalem",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/120569164/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Corinth 57 or 58",
    "answer": "When and where does Paul write Romans?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the Above",
    "answer": "In Romans, Paul says that \"all Israel will be saved,\" which has been interpreted as meaning what?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the Above",
    "answer": "Paul's missionary work is...",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jesus' death on the cross",
    "answer": "One image for explaining how Christ justifies people's atonement is:",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jesus' death and resurrection",
    "answer": "Paul's interest in Jesus mainly focuses on:",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Reconciliation",
    "answer": "In Romans, justification is associated with:",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pharisees",
    "answer": "To which Jewish group did Paul belong?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "To reestablish contact with the Roman church",
    "answer": "Which is not a reason that Paul wrote Romans?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Gallio",
    "answer": "What governor was Paul connected to?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "the imitation of Christ",
    "answer": "For Paul, Christian ethics were shaped by:",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Covenantal",
    "answer": "The term justification comes from which Jewish language?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Phoebe",
    "answer": "Which woman does Paul applaud in Romans 16?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Past",
    "answer": "Which tense does Paul use when speaking of reconciliation in Romans?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "an example of God's mysterious purpose",
    "answer": "In Romans, Paul interprets Isreal's rejection of Christ as...",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "There is salvation for all: Jews and Gentiles",
    "answer": "What is Paul's central claim in Romans?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Present",
    "answer": "Which tense does Paul use when speaking of justification by faith in Romans?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Baptism",
    "answer": "In Romans 6, Paul interprets this ritual as the believer's participation in Christ's death, burial, and resurrection.",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Tentmaking",
    "answer": "What trade did Paul engage in to support himself?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "1st Thessalonians",
    "answer": "Which of Paul's letters was written during his second missionary journey?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Junia",
    "answer": "Which woman was \"prominent among the apostles\"?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "He targeted urban, commercial settings",
    "answer": "When preaching in new areas, what pattern did Paul use?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Judah",
    "answer": "Paul was a member of which Jewish tribe?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jesus' death and resurrection",
    "answer": "Paul is known for his focus on:",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Philemon",
    "answer": "Paul thinks of himself as an old man when he writes which book?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Claudius",
    "answer": "Which Emperor expelled Jews from Rome?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Reconciliation",
    "answer": "People have been unfaithful to God and destroyed the relationship. When Jesus repairs it, it is called what?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "A scholarly view that understands \"works of the law\" not as \"works righteousness\" but as ethnic markers that designate Israel as God's chosen people.",
    "answer": "What is the \"New Perspective on Paul\"?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Catholics and Protestants being divided over the interpretation of Romans",
    "answer": "What do scholars saw would have disturbed Paul?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Conduct",
    "answer": "According to Powell, \"The cross not only becomes the emblem of Christian salvation, but of Christian....\"",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "About",
    "answer": "Scholars argue that Paul transformed the message of Jesus to the message ____ Jesus.",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Justification by Faith",
    "answer": "What is the main theme of Romans?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Avoid eating that food as an accommodation to those who might be offended by their action",
    "answer": "In Romans, Paul teaches that church members who know that it is permissible to eat the food which others think it is sinful to eat should do what?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Gospel reveals the righteousness of God",
    "answer": "What is Paul's thesis in Romans?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Atonement",
    "answer": "The theological view, rooted in temple sacrifice, that says people have sinned against God and God therefore demands a sacrifice to set the relationship right again is called...",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The care of the poor in Jerusalem",
    "answer": "Paul encourages the Roman Christians to give money for a collection to be offered for what purpose?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Roman citizen",
    "answer": "The book of Acts records that Paul was once:",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Honing his missionary skills and developing his theological understanding of the gospel.",
    "answer": "It is generally believed that Paul spent the interim years between his conversion and his first missionary journey doing what?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Acts of the Apostles",
    "answer": "This written source helps scholars to understand the order of Paul's life.",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ethnic (Jewish) Privilege",
    "answer": "The \"New Perspective\" on Paul suggests that his language about being \"saved by grace through faith\" is not a statement against \"works\" but a statement against...",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the above",
    "answer": "For what reason does Paul write to the Churches in Rome?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul was born in Jerusalem",
    "answer": "What is not an aspect of Paul's early life?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Salvation comes through a Jewish Messiah",
    "answer": "How is God faithful in his promises to Isreal?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Circumcision",
    "answer": "In Judaism, which rite is viewed as a covenant with God?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Salvation is universally available",
    "answer": "What is Paul's main point in Romans?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ephesians and Colossians",
    "answer": "Which letters were written at the same time as Philemon?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jesus was a prophet sent by God; Jesus is Son of God and Lord of all.",
    "answer": "Paul's thinking changed after his conversion in all way but what?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "A literary device",
    "answer": "Powell notes that some scholars believe Paul's missionary journeys recorded in Acts are...",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Seven Undisputed Letters of Paul",
    "answer": "Of the material available for understanding Paul's life and thought, what are the primary sources?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul worked with his hands",
    "answer": "Paul's letters and the book of Acts agree that:",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Junia",
    "answer": "Which woman does Paul commend to the Roman Christians as a deacon of the church in Cenchrea?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Reconciliation",
    "answer": "People are placed in a right relationship with God and with each other:",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "When Jesus restores believers to a right relationship with God, this is called...",
    "answer": "Justification by faith",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Saul",
    "answer": "In the Book of Acts, Paul is also known by this Hebrew name.",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/36831325/bible-exam-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Corinth was the capital city of which Roman province?",
    "answer": "Achaia",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In contrast to Paul, the opponents claim that the \"good news\" to Gentiles is that they can become______________.",
    "answer": "Members of Israel",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In his teaching about the resurrection, Paul emphasizes what in 1 Corinthians 15?",
    "answer": "Those who are raised by Christ will have new, glorified bodies",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul writes 1 Corinthians in response to what?",
    "answer": "â€¢ Reports from Stephanus, Fortunatus, and Achaicus, who brought letter to Paul from the Corinthians<br>â€¢ A letter written to Paul from the Corinthian church<br>â€¢ Reports from Chloe's people",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Problems arose around the Lord's Supper in the Corinthian church because_____________.",
    "answer": "Wealthier members were eating the food before the lower class members arrived after long work hours",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The church in Philippi is often thought to be the first Christian church to be ___________________.",
    "answer": "In Europe",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In contrast to the Corinthians' claims to have special wisdom and knowledge, what does Paul state that as the only thing worth knowing.",
    "answer": "Christ and him crucified",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In what positive ways does Paul interpret his imprisonment for the Philippians?",
    "answer": "Paul's imprisonment has advanced the gospel, Paul is now actively sharing in Christ's suffering",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul uses a good deal of family language in his first letter to the Thessalonians. Be familiar with which familial term does not occur in the letter.",
    "answer": "Cousins",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Like the missionaries to Corinth, what do Paul's opponents in Galatia attack?",
    "answer": "Paul's apostolic authority",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The city of Corinth was famous for what particular metal.",
    "answer": "Bronze",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1 Corinthians Paul states that the cross of Christ is _________ from the perspective of outsiders.",
    "answer": "Foolishness",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Christ Hymn in Philippians 2:6-11 is one of the earliest literary references to what?",
    "answer": "Jesus' preexistence",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In his letter to the Galatians, Paul is so upset he leaves out what basic part of the letter?",
    "answer": "The thanksgiving",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "One way Paul emphasizes unity in Philippians is to use which prefix on a variety of words?",
    "answer": "-syn",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Most scholars think that 1 Thessalonians is Paul's______________.",
    "answer": "First canonical letter written",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "From Paul's words in 1 Thessalonians, one can describe his ministry as_____________.",
    "answer": "Preaching while also working with his hands",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Galatians, which Gentile companion of Paul was not required to be circumcised by the Jerusalem leaders?",
    "answer": "Titus",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Galatians, what happens to the human desires and passions of one who belongs to Christ?",
    "answer": "They have been crucified",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "First Thessalonians is sent from Paul, Silvanus, and Timothy. Why do scholars believe Paul is the primary author?",
    "answer": "Use of the first person singular references",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Galatians, Paul uses a Bible story about two women who represent two covenants. Who are these two women?",
    "answer": "Sarah and Hagar",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the book of Acts, who was Paul's first convert in Philippi?",
    "answer": "Lydia",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "For Paul, according to the letter to the Galatians, a person is only really free when one is_____________________.",
    "answer": "Free in Christ",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1 Corinthians, Paul argues that God reveals His power through what?",
    "answer": "Human weakness",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul urges the Philippians to have humility, which in this letter means what?",
    "answer": "To put others first and consciously seek what is best for others over what may be best for one's self",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul uses the metaphor of a footrace in his letter to the Philippians. Paul employs this metaphor to illustrate which point?",
    "answer": "A runner must move forward with single-minded focus on the prize; in the same manner, the believer is drawn toward God in Christ, forgetting what lies behind and pressing on toward the heavenly goal",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1 Corinthians, the \"body of Christ\" refers to what?",
    "answer": "The Christians in Corinth",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The two groups of Corinthian Christians, those who approved of prostitution and those who prohibited all sexual relationships (even in marriage), had a common commitment to what?",
    "answer": "Being Spiritual",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Speaking generally, Paul seems to have presented the gospel of Christ to the Thessalonians as________________.",
    "answer": "A meaningful moral system that allowed people to live with integrity and dignity",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ideas and behavior Paul taught while in Thessalonica resemble the teaching of which contemporary philosophical school?",
    "answer": "The Epicureans",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "From Paul's perspective, why is the gift of prophecy more important than speaking in tongues?",
    "answer": "It is more helpful to the church",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1 Thessalonians, how does Paul describe his experience of being ejected from the city?",
    "answer": "Being orphaned",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Galatians, Paul accuses the believers of all of what?",
    "answer": "â€¢ Turning to a different gospel<br>â€¢ Ignoring their experience of the spirit<br>â€¢ Nullifying the grace of God",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In his letter to the Galatians, Paul paradoxically associates freedom with what?",
    "answer": "Loving service",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to 1 Corinthians 13, what will remain forever?",
    "answer": "Faith, hope, and love",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "One notable characteristic of 1 Thessalonians is the number of times that Paul does what?",
    "answer": "Reminds his readers of things that they already know",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Christian theology, to what does the term incarnation refer?",
    "answer": "The doctrine that Jesus was God come to earth as a human being",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Philippians 4, Paul counsels Euodia and Syntyche to do what?",
    "answer": "Be of the same mind in the Lord",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "How did other Gentiles view the newly converted Christians in Thessalonica?",
    "answer": "As irreligious and unpatriotic",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Exam 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/171820901/bible-exam-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "1 John opens up with a contrast between what two things?",
    "answer": "light and darkness",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following are true descriptions of Philippi, except what?",
    "answer": "Philippi became a thriving port city to rival Corinth.",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Most Greek manuscripts contain the number 666 for the number of the beast (13:18), but some manuscripts have this number.",
    "answer": "616",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to a futurist approach to the book of Revelation, the seven letters represent...",
    "answer": "The seven future eras of church history.",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "With regard to slaves, what was a requirement under Roman law?",
    "answer": "Runaway slaves had to be returned to their masters.",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Letter to Philemon has numerous similarities with what other New Testament letter attributed to Paul?",
    "answer": "Colossians",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which group believed that Christ was a divine being who only seemed to be human?",
    "answer": "Docetists",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to 1 John, how is the love of God made perfect?",
    "answer": "Through obeying commands",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The book of Revelation shares features of all the following genres except...",
    "answer": "Homily",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "To the extent that Revelation is prophecy, it should be read as a communication intended primarily for people...",
    "answer": "Living at the time when it was written.",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul indicates to the Philippians that suffering can have positive consequences. Of these consequences, which of the following does not appear in Philippians?",
    "answer": "Suffering for Christ completes the believer's salvation.",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which group of people view the history of the world as increasingly evil which will eventually require Christ's return to initiate a thousand year reign and final judgment?",
    "answer": "Premillennialists",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Revelation animals can have a symbolic function. Which one of these animals appears as a symbol?",
    "answer": "Lion",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The book of Revelation reveals all of the following except..",
    "answer": "What believers want to hear",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The churches in Revelation appear to have experienced any one or all of the following situations except...",
    "answer": "Natural catastrophes such as earthquakes and plagues.",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In what positive ways does Paul interpret his imprisonment for the Philippians?",
    "answer": "All of the above",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What word occurring in some English translations of the Bible refers to Christ's death as an act that placates the wrath of a God offended by human sin?",
    "answer": "Propriation",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Most scholars think Revelation was written under the emperor Domitian around 95 CE, even though...",
    "answer": "Persecution of Christians was not widespread under Domitian.",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Philippians is written in the form of a/an...",
    "answer": "friendship letter.",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The church in Philippi is often thought to be the first Christian church...",
    "answer": "in Europe",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does Paul try to persuade Philemon to welcome or even free his slave Onesimus?",
    "answer": "Paul suggests that this can be a means for Philemon to repay his debt to Paul",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of thought in the first century had a pessimistic view of the current world combined with an optimistic expectation for the future of the small community of faithful people?",
    "answer": "Apocalypticism",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of these is not an element of Old Testament symbolism used by the author of Revelation?",
    "answer": "The red dragon",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a persuasive tactic used by Paul in his letter to Philemon?",
    "answer": "Having the letter read before the entire church",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which group of people read the thousand years in Revelation as symbolic of triumph and therefore not chronologically related to Christ's return?",
    "answer": "Amillennialists",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "To what does the term \"gematria\" refer?",
    "answer": "Assigning numerical values to words.",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Philemon, Paul does not refer to himself as a \"slave of Christ\" as he does in his other letters; instead he identifies himself as \"a(n) _______ of Christ.\"",
    "answer": "Prisoner",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does Paul mean when he commends Philemon for \"refreshing the hearts of the saints\"?",
    "answer": "Philemon shows hospitality to believers in his home.",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements about the author of Revelation is true?",
    "answer": "All of the above",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the book of Acts, who was Paul's first convert in Philippi?",
    "answer": "Lydia",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul uses several means to convince Philemon to do him a favor. Which of the following is one of the arguments Paul employs?",
    "answer": "Paul will pay the debt Onesimus owes",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which group of people view the history of the world as increasingly good and which will eventually climax with a thousand year period of peace preceding Christ's return?",
    "answer": "Postmillennialists",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The book of Revelation contains all of the the following except...",
    "answer": "Going fishing",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The theme of fellowship in Paul's letter to the Philippians is exemplified by Paul's references to the members of this church as...",
    "answer": "Siblings",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The genre of 1 John is probably best described as what?",
    "answer": "a theological tract",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Scholars estimate that the proportion of slaves in the Roman Empire was...",
    "answer": "Between 25 and 35%",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "To whom is the second letter of John addressed?",
    "answer": "the elect lady and her children",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Reading the number of the beast (666) as a reference to the Roman emperor Nero, or perhaps Domitian, is illustrative of which approach?",
    "answer": "Historical",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "One way Paul emphasizes unity in Philippians is to use which prefix on a variety of words?",
    "answer": "Syn-",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Christian theology, to what does the term incarnation refer?",
    "answer": "Jesus was God in human form",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul uses puns in his letter to Philemon using the name of Onesimus, whose name means what?",
    "answer": "Useful",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the letter to Philemon, Paul states Onesimus has become like what to him?",
    "answer": "A son",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What concept listed below does not occur in both 1 John and the Gospel of John?",
    "answer": "Victorious Lamb",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following are common in apocalyptic literature except...",
    "answer": "Chronological Stories",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Slavery in the Roman world was characterized by all of the following except...",
    "answer": "Slavery was based on race or ethnicity",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Philemon probably lived in what Asian city?",
    "answer": "Colossae",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Philippians 4, Paul counsels Euodia and Syntyche to do what?",
    "answer": "Have the same mind in Christ",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In contrast to apocalyptic literature, prophetic literature...",
    "answer": "Is concerned that God's people repent and escape judgment for failing to keep covenant",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What Roman legal practice provides a reasonable context for understanding Paul's letter to Philemon?",
    "answer": "A slave who had wronged his or her master could seek arbitration and sanctuary through a colleague or friend of the master",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Christ Hymn in Philippians 2:6-11 is one of the earliest literary references to what?",
    "answer": "Jesus' preexistence",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Final Exam",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42036512/bible-final-exam-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The first argument in Hebrews is that Jesus is superior to?",
    "answer": "Angels",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What word refers to the portable worship space of the Israelites before the construction of their temple in Jerusalem?",
    "answer": "A tabernacle",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which OT figure is raised to the significant prominence in Hebrews?",
    "answer": "Melchizedek",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the author of Hebrews?",
    "answer": "Unknown",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "How is Jesus's death portrayed in Hebrews?",
    "answer": "The Ultimate Sacrifice that cannot be topped; A priestly sacrifice",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Know Hebrews 13:22",
    "answer": "\"I appeal to you, brothers, bear with my word of exhortation, for I have written to you briefly\"",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What do some scholars think about Hebrews? (Powell)",
    "answer": "It's a sermon",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the two main themes in Hebrews?",
    "answer": "1) Christ's superiority<br>2) Apostle work",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the word \"faith\" signify according to Hebrews?",
    "answer": "The Six basic teachings:<br>1) Repentance<br>2) Resurrection<br>3) Eternal Judgment<br>4) Baptisms<br>5) Faith towards God<br>6) Dead Works<br>things that are hoped for",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Does the book of Hebrews discuss the Jewish religion as it was practiced in the Jerusalem Temple?",
    "answer": "No",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Did Early Christians unanimously accept the Book of Hebrews as inspired?",
    "answer": "No, they had much trouble accepting it",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Does the book of Hebrews say that Jesus sinned during his youth?",
    "answer": "No",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the word \"diaspora\" mean and what is it used to describe?",
    "answer": "The dispersion of Jews outside of Palestine",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does James approach people who aspire to become Christian Teachers?",
    "answer": "As Christian Teachers, you have to perform works and good deeds. He warns them",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the first book of the New Testament that was considered authoritative and part of the canon?",
    "answer": "NOT James",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What OT character does both Paul and James look to as a model of faith?",
    "answer": "Abraham",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "James urges his readers to consider trials in life as...?",
    "answer": "Joy. Find Joy in suffering",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Know James 1:19-20",
    "answer": "\"My dear brothers and sisters, take note of this: Everyone should be QUICK to listen, slow to speak and slow to become angry, because human anger does not produce the righteousness that God desires\"",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What other text does the Letter of James quote more than any other New Testament letter?",
    "answer": "Jesus's sayings",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What other type of literature does the Letter of James have a lot in common with?",
    "answer": "Wisdom literature",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What other NT books display an interest in the rich and poor?",
    "answer": "Luke and Acts",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which OT book does James have a lot in common with?",
    "answer": "Proverbs",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does James advise Christians to do when a rich person enters an assembly?",
    "answer": "Treat everyone equally",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the source of temptation in the letter of James?",
    "answer": "One's own desires",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which James is traditionally identified as the author of the Letter of James?",
    "answer": "Jesus's brother",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What metaphor does James use to describe the tongue?",
    "answer": "Fire",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where does the author of 1st Peter write from and to whom does he write to?",
    "answer": "From Rome to Christians in Asia Minor",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first person to deliver 1 Peter to the churches?",
    "answer": "Silvanus (Silas)",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of letter is 1 Peter known as?",
    "answer": "Circular letter",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the author call the audience in the opening of 1 Peter?",
    "answer": "Exiles of the dispersion",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Christian ritual is the contents of 1 Peter tied to?",
    "answer": "Baptism",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What image for the church does 1 Peter use?",
    "answer": "The priesthood of all believers",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the first century, becoming a Christian frequently resulted in having to cut off one's ties with former associations",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the \"fiery ordeal\" referring to in 1 Peter?",
    "answer": "The suffering of Christ",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Does Peter's name always come first when the names of Jesus' apostles are listed?",
    "answer": "Yes",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Can almost every verse in 1 Peter be read as a parallel passage to a NT writing?",
    "answer": "Yes",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Does 1 Peter want to turn the audiences' shame into honor?",
    "answer": "Yes",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does Peter view the time of human suffering?",
    "answer": "It does not come from God; suffering lasts a lifetime",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "How is the love of God made perfect according to 1 John?",
    "answer": "In those who obey God commandments",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where can you find the statement \"God is love?\"",
    "answer": "1 John 4:8",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Know 1 John 3:17",
    "answer": "\"But if anyone has the world's goods and sees his brother in need, yet closes his heart against him, how does God's love abide in him?\"",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "How is the genre of 1 John described as?",
    "answer": "A theological tract",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "1 John opens up with a contrast between what two things?",
    "answer": "1) Walking in darkness<br>2) Walking in light of God",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to lecture, the first 3 verses of 1 John contain over 14 what?",
    "answer": "Verbs",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Know 1 John 2:1",
    "answer": "\"My little children, I am writing these things to you so that you may not SIN. But if anyone does sin, we have an advocate with the Father, Jesus Christ the righteous.\"",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Know 1 John 4:18",
    "answer": "\"There is no fear in love, but perfect love casts out FEAR. For FEAR has to do with punishment, and whoever FEARS has not been perfected in love.\"",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Is the tone of 1 John very formal and impersonal?",
    "answer": "No",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Does Powell note that many influential Christians through the ages have despised the message of 1 John?",
    "answer": "No",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Does John in 1 John have a habit of addressing the readers as \"my little children\" or \"beloved\"?",
    "answer": "Yes",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1 John what does the term \"antichrist\" mean and who does it apply to?",
    "answer": "Anti-Christ is made between children of God and children of the devil and between people who hate fellow believers and people who have God's love in them",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/288682457/bible-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Corinth was the capital city of which Roman province?",
    "answer": "Achaia",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul is driven to boasting by whom?",
    "answer": "Super-apostles who tout their own credentials and achievements",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the basis for Paul's apostleshipâ€”his claim to have been personally sent by Jesus?",
    "answer": "Paul met the resurrected Jesus",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to 2 Corinthians, the role of the Apostles was to lead the universal church.",
    "answer": "False.",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does Paul teach the Corinthians regarding marriage and sex?",
    "answer": "Celibacy is preferable to marriage.",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What effect did Paul's \"tearful\" letter have on the Corinthian churches?",
    "answer": "Repentance",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why do scholars think that Paul's arguments in 2 Corinthians won out against the other apostles in the long run?",
    "answer": "The Corinthians preserved and copied Paul's letters.",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which two metaphors does Paul apply to the problem of divisions in Corinth to show that unity already exists and must be recognized by the church?",
    "answer": "Temple of God and Body of Christ",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul tells the Corinthians that Christians from this Roman Province had already given generously to the contribution for the poor in Jerusalem.",
    "answer": "Macedonia",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul devotes most of 2 Corinthians to what topic?",
    "answer": "His ministry",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul interprets the fund-raising (or collection) in Corinth as a symbol of what?",
    "answer": "All of the Above",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What occurred between the writing of 1 and 2 Corinthians?",
    "answer": "All of the Above",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "As dealt with in 2 Corinthians 8-9, Paul organized a fund raising campaign among his churches for the Jerusalem church, which had what purpose?",
    "answer": "Demonstrating unity of Jewish and Gentile believers",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In contrast to the Corinthians' claims to have special wisdom and knowledge, Paul states that this is the only thing worth knowing.",
    "answer": "Christ and Him crucified",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1 Corinthians, Paul argues that God reveals His power through what?",
    "answer": "Human weakness",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "1 Corinthians is the first letter Paul wrote to the Corinthian church.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What characterization best describes the church in Corinth?",
    "answer": "A divisive church with problems",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are scholarly hypotheses regarding the abrupt changes in tone found in 2 Corinthians?",
    "answer": "All of the Above",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not true about Roman Corinth?",
    "answer": "As a colony it held steadfast to Roman morals and virtues",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the topic of 2 Corinthians 8-9?",
    "answer": "Fund-raising",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "If 2 Corinthians is one complete letter (rather than a collection of pieces from earlier correspondence), it must be which one of the many letters Paul wrote to that city?",
    "answer": "Fourth",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Paul's primary concern when he tells the Corinthians to expel the man committing incest from the church?",
    "answer": "The purity of the church should be preserved",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the Corinthian Christians played prominent roles in city politics.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The city of Corinth was famous for this particular metal.",
    "answer": "Bronze",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the Corinthian letters, Paul's qualifications for apostleship include all of the following except what?",
    "answer": "One who was designated one of the twelve by Jesus Christ",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not something Paul uses to support his arguments in 1 Corinthians?",
    "answer": "Guidance from the Bishop",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the Greek word often used for the phenomenon of speaking in tongues?",
    "answer": "Glossolalia",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who from the Corinthian congregation visited Paul and reported on the activities of other members in that church?",
    "answer": "Chloe's People",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a description of Paul's stay and ministry in Corinth according to the Book of Acts?",
    "answer": "Paul made a living preparing meats in the marketplace",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Paul's \"thorn in the flesh\" he refers to in 2 Corinthians?",
    "answer": "An unidentified affliction",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul's initial plan to visit the Corinthians and his subsequent cancellation of that plan resulted in what accusation?",
    "answer": "Paul is unreliable and self-interested",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to 1 Corinthians 13, what will remain forever?",
    "answer": "Faith, hope, and love",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does Paul describe his ministry to the Corinthian churches?",
    "answer": "Sincere",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Because Paul was an Apostle, God never rejected any of his prayer requests.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The two groups of Corinthian Christians, those who approved of prostitution and those who prohibited all sexual relationships (even in marriage), had a common commitment to what?",
    "answer": "Being Spiritual",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "From Paul's perspective, why is the gift of prophecy more important than speaking in tongues?",
    "answer": "It is more helpful to the church",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does Paul identify as matters \"of first importance\" in 1 Corinthians?",
    "answer": "Jesus' death, burial, and resurrection",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul writes 1 Corinthians in response to what?",
    "answer": "All of the Above",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following issues divided the Corinthian church?",
    "answer": "All of the Above",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does Paul think the Corinthian Christians should do with regard to eating food sacrificed to idols?",
    "answer": "Being willing to give up their rights for the sake of others",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "To what or whom does Paul apply the metaphor \"jars of clay\" in 2 Corinthians?",
    "answer": "Christians as weak bearers of God's power",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following does Paul not identify as a problem that occurs when the Corinthians celebrated the Lord's Supper (Eucharist)?",
    "answer": "Rulers are humiliated",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Problems arose around the Lord's Supper in the Corinthian church because...",
    "answer": "Wealthier members were eating food before the lower class members arrived after long hours of work.",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not one of the three guidelines that determines Paul's teaching about marriage in 1 Corinthians?",
    "answer": "God created all males and females for marriage",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1 Corinthians Paul states that the cross of Christ is _________ from the perspective of outsiders.",
    "answer": "Foolishness",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In his teaching about the resurrection, Paul emphasizes what in 1 Corinthians 15?",
    "answer": "Those who are raised by Christ will have new, glorified bodies",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "When Paul excommunicates a member of the church or rules on disputes among Corinthian believers, he is exercising what?",
    "answer": "Apostolic Authority",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2 Corinthians, Paul's relationship with the churches in Corinth is best described as...",
    "answer": "On the rocks and troubled",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does Paul suggest the Corinthians do instead of advocating for their own rights?",
    "answer": "Consider other people first",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1 Corinthians, the \"body of Christ\" refers to what?",
    "answer": "The Corinthians in the church",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39609723/bible-quiz-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul cites Deuteronomy 21:23 to argue that Christ became what for us?",
    "answer": "a curse",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "For Paul, according to the letter to the Galatians, a person is only really free when one is...",
    "answer": "free to serve in Christ",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ephesians is written to the churches in Ephesus, a city that in first-century times was...",
    "answer": "in the capital province of Asia",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was Peter's name in Aramaic?",
    "answer": "Cephas",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who carried and delivered the letter to the Ephesians?",
    "answer": "Tychicus",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul claims that if the Gentiles seek justification (a right relation with God) by observing the law, then they are nullifying what?",
    "answer": "the grace of God",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of Paul's letters sometimes wears the label \"the Christian Magna Carta\"?",
    "answer": "Galatians",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Galatians, Paul accuses the believers of all of the following except what?",
    "answer": "leaving Christianity for Sikhism",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the traditional designation for Paul's opponents who were Jewish Christians advocating a gospel that Gentiles must first become Jews by obeying the Law of Moses before receiving full salvation from Jesus, the Jewish Messiah?",
    "answer": "Judiazers",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "A wall in the Jerusalem temple had inscriptions warning Gentiles that they would be killed if they crossed it.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The second-century writer Marcion refers to what we know as \"the letter to the Ephesians\" as what?",
    "answer": "the letter to the Laodiceans",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "We know for certain that the Galatian churches consisted mostly of what people group?",
    "answer": "Gentiles",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following best reflects the contents of Ephesians 4-5?",
    "answer": "numerous \"do\"s and \"don't\"s",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Ephesians the devil is identified as \"the ruler of the power of the ___.\"",
    "answer": "air",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Galatians, what happens to the human desires and passions of one who belongs to Christ?",
    "answer": "they have been crucified",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the first century CE, Ephesus was home to this, one of the seven wonders of the world.",
    "answer": "the temple of Artemis",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the \"table of household duties\" found in Ephesians is compared to such tables that were typical for this culture and time period, the most remarkable aspect is..",
    "answer": "the inclusion of instruction for husbands, fathers, and masters",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Like the letter to the Philippians, the letter to the Ephesians is written and sent from where?",
    "answer": "prison",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Acts, Paul had a very difficult time in Ephesus and made many enemies there. What did Paul do that disturbed the Ephesians?",
    "answer": "He denounced idolatry",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does Paul think the Galatians are fools?",
    "answer": "they want to be circumcised",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ephesus often earned the title neokoros for the region around the city. This title indicates that...",
    "answer": "Ephesus served as the official headquarters for the imperial quilt",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The \"mystery\" referred to in Ephesians concerns what?",
    "answer": "God's plan to unite all people in Christ",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What role is especially ascribed to the Holy Spirit in Paul's letter to the Galatians?",
    "answer": "The spirit bears virtuous fruit within believers",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a feature or characteristic of Ephesians that cannot be found in Paul's undisputed letters?",
    "answer": "The \"church\" is universal rather than a local congregation.",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did Paul rebuke Peter at Antioch?",
    "answer": "Paul quit eating with Gentiles",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Assuming Ephesus was the city to which the letter to the Ephesians was sent, the New Testament contains only one letter to the Christians in Ephesus.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In English Bibles, Paul's letter to the Ephesians is addressed \"to the saints who are in Ephesus and are faithful in Christ Jesus.\" Some of the oldest Greek manuscripts are missing a few of these words. Which are the missing words?",
    "answer": "in Ephesus",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Galatians, Paul uses a Bible story about two women who represent two covenants. Who are these two women?",
    "answer": "Sarah and Hagar",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Paul's letter to the Galatians, a believer can fall away from grace.",
    "answer": "True.",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Galatians, which Gentile companion of Paul was not required to be circumcised by the Jerusalem leaders?",
    "answer": "Titus",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which letter of Paul's is called the \"angry letter\"?",
    "answer": "Galatians",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul tells the Galatians that the Holy Spirit is a gift of God to Christ's followers, and its role is to..",
    "answer": "form Christ in them",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Scholars have explained the dissimilarity of Ephesians with Paul's undisputed letters in all of the following ways except...",
    "answer": "Paul wrote Ephesians as a rough draft for Colossians, but it was mistakenly inserted into the collection of Paul's letters.",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following strikes scholars as a distinctive aspect of Ephesians' view of Christians?",
    "answer": "the exaltation of Christians to heaven is depicted as a present reality",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Like the missionaries to Corinth, what do Paul's opponents in Galatia attack?",
    "answer": "his apostolic authority",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Scholars find many parallels between Ephesians and what other New Testament book?",
    "answer": "Colossians",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In his letter to the Galatians, Paul is so upset he leaves out what basic part of the letter?",
    "answer": "the thanksgiving",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the theology of Ephesians, Jesus' death on the cross accomplishes all of the following except what?",
    "answer": "Bringing immediate equity to the poor and widows",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Galatians Paul twice levels a curse against his opponents.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Ephesians, the mysterious plan of God is accomplished in what two stages?",
    "answer": "Jesus' crucifixion and exaltation",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In his letter to the Galatians, Paul paradoxically associates freedom with what?",
    "answer": "loving service",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Of the two letters, Ephesians and Colossians, scholars think Ephesians was written first.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the German word scholars use to describe discussions of family responsibilities in the Greco-Roman era?",
    "answer": "Haustafel",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul's opponents in Galatia have apparently said that his gospel lacks endorsement from the apostles in Jerusalem. What is Paul's reply?",
    "answer": "The apostles in Jerusalem do approve, but it doesn't really matter since he received his gospel from Christ and it needs no human endorsement",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Of all the people to whom Paul wrote (that we have evidence for), he was most disappointed with the Galatians.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not part of Ephesians' idea or perspective of the church?",
    "answer": "There are two dimensions of the church, the heavenly ministry inspired by Christ but also the sinful struggle of living in this world.",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Of the following temporal aspects, Paul's gospel includes all except what?",
    "answer": "God's new era in Christ is a time where both law and faith operate",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "One reason some believe Paul could not have written Ephesians is because it advocates a high ecclesiology (view of the church) often derided as early Catholicism.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In contrast to Paul, the opponents claim that the \"good news\" to Gentiles is that they can become...",
    "answer": "Members of Isreal",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The significance of the debate over whether Galatians was written to \"north Galatia\" or \"south Galatia\" is that the destination might determine which of the following?",
    "answer": "The letter was written early or late in Paul's career",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Quiz 4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/39100897/bible-quiz-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pharisees, Saducees, Essenes",
    "answer": "3 main religious groups in Luke",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test #1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/27217244/bible-test-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pagans, Orthodox Jews, Herodians, Zealots",
    "answer": "4 main population groups in Luke",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test #1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/27217244/bible-test-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "prayer, study, assembly",
    "answer": "The synagogue served as a house of these three things.",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test #1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/27217244/bible-test-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Torah teachers, Rabbis with smicha",
    "answer": "What were the two kinds of teachers?",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test #1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/27217244/bible-test-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Luke",
    "answer": "Author of Luke",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test #1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/27217244/bible-test-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Theopholis and the Gentiles",
    "answer": "Audience of Luke",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test #1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/27217244/bible-test-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "65-70 A.D.",
    "answer": "Date of writing for Luke",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test #1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/27217244/bible-test-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Worship and prayer, Jesus is welcome to all, Work of the Holy Spirit",
    "answer": "Three themes of Luke",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test #1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/27217244/bible-test-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Lost Sheep, Lost Coin, Prodigal Son",
    "answer": "3 Parables in Luke",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test #1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/27217244/bible-test-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paralytic, Woman with hemorrhage, Ten lepers",
    "answer": "3 Miracles in Luke",
    "user": "LauraH95",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test #1",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/27217244/bible-test-1-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Pastoral Letters are",
    "answer": "the three letters addressed to colleagues of Paul entrusted with pastoral leadership of churches: 1 Timothy, 2 Timothy, Titus.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Captivity letters are",
    "answer": "the five letters that appear to have been written by Paul from prison: Ephesians, Philippians, Colossians, 2 Timothy, Philemon.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Catholic (or General) letters are",
    "answer": "seven writings thought to be addressed to the church at large: James, 1 Peter, 2 Peter, 1 John, 2 John, 3 John, Jude.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The typical structure of an ancient letter was",
    "answer": "salutation, thanksgiving, main body, closing.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Christian letters, the customary \"Greetings\" is generally substituted by",
    "answer": "\"grace and peace.\"",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is counted among the deutero-Pauline letters?",
    "answer": "Ephesians",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an undisputed letter of Paul?",
    "answer": "2 Corinthians",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following New Testament letters is considered to be pseudepigraphical?",
    "answer": "James",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the context of authorship and pseudepigraphy, what is honorable pseudepigraphy?",
    "answer": "Admirers write letters in the name of a deceased leader in tribute to his influence, believing themselves to be responsible bearers of his tradition.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Scholars who think that the New Testament letters ought to be considered authentic writings (not pseudepigraphical) may argue that",
    "answer": "A. early Christians would have viewed pseudepigraphy as a dishonest practice. (Your Answer)<br> B. early church traditions about authorship are generally reliable.<br> C. linguistic and other features that make the letter seem non-Pauline can be explained through Paul's use of an amanuensis.<br> D. all of the above (Correct Answer)",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the context of authorship and pseudepigraphy, what is apprentice authorship?",
    "answer": "Disciples who have been authorized to speak for a living leader continue writing letters in his name years or decades after his death.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a feature of letter writing in ancient times as reflected in the New Testament letters?",
    "answer": "the mandatory use of official Roman stamps (or imprints) on letters",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a reason why scholars sometimes claim that a letter is pseudepigraphical?",
    "answer": "the intent to deceive",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Paul's letters and Acts, which of the following is not an aspect of Paul's early life?",
    "answer": "Paul was born in Jerusalem",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the book of Acts, Paul is also known by his Hebrew name",
    "answer": "Saul",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul understood his life-changing revelation of Jesus as",
    "answer": "a prophetic call.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "After Paul's conversion, his thinking changed in all of the following ways except",
    "answer": "before: Jesus was a prophet sent by God; after: Jesus is the Son of God and Lord of all.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "It is generally believed that Paul spent the interim years between his conversion and his first missionary journey doing what?",
    "answer": "honing his missionary skills and developing his theological understanding of the gospel",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a feature or strategy of Paul's missionary work?",
    "answer": "Paul's mission work was authorized by Peter and the other leaders of the Jerusalem church.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In developing a chronology for Paul's life, one of the most helpful pieces of information has been",
    "answer": "the brief mention in the book of Acts that Gallio was the proconsul of Corinth when Paul was in that city",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul's interest in Jesus focuses mainly on",
    "answer": "Jesus' death and resurrection",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Theologically, Paul understands Jesus to be",
    "answer": "the image of God, the Son of God, and Lord.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul's ethical expectations for Christians are shaped by all of the following except",
    "answer": "the hedonic calculus: Christians must act so as to bring the greatest satisfaction to the greatest number of people",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is \"the New Perspective on Paul\"?",
    "answer": "a scholarly view that understands \"works of the law\" not as \"works righteousness\" but as ethnic markers that designate Israel as God's chosen people",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The span of jewish history from 515 CE to 70 CE is referred to as a) The time of the maccabees b) the Persian Period c) The Second Temple Period d) The Roman Period",
    "answer": "The Second Temple period",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Gentiles embraced Jewish theology, worship. and morality but did not fully convert to Judaism by being circumcised and following the Jewish dietary laws? a) Zealots b) Samaritans c) God-fearers d) Herodians",
    "answer": "God-fearers",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What term refers to Jews living outside the traditional homeland of Palestine who were influenced by Hellenism?",
    "answer": "Diaspora",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Greek translation of the Jewish Bible is referred to as the",
    "answer": "Septuagint",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which religious movement promoted secret knowledge that will allow the soul to be set free from the bodily prison in this material world?",
    "answer": "Gnosticism",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which terms are used most often to describe the dynamics of the patron-client relationship: the patron's bestowal of benefits and the client's expected attitude of loyalty to the patron?",
    "answer": "Grace and faith",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What social value refers to the status that one has in the eyes of others whom one considers to be significant, including factors such as age, gender, nationality, and economic class?",
    "answer": "honor",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What term refers to a list of books that are officially accepted as scripture?",
    "answer": "Canon",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What two developments in early Christianity made the canon an issue for Christians?",
    "answer": "(1) some Christians were excluding certain writings and (2) some Christians were producing new writings and attributing them to apostles",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding the New Testament canon, most scholars would accept which two conclusions?",
    "answer": "(1) all New Testament writings are compatible with \"apostolic Christianity\" and (2) the New Testament writings present a variety of viewpoints",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What term refers to the scholarly study of the Bible with an emphasis on the explication of texts using various academic approaches?",
    "answer": "Exegesis",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What term refers to the philosophical reflection on the process of interpretation?",
    "answer": "hermeneutics",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What term describes the facet of Jesus' ministry in which he preaches on the road, taking his message to different groups as he and his disciples move from place to place?",
    "answer": "itinerant",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Nero",
    "answer": "Initiated the first overt, government-sponsored persecution of Christians in Rome.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Dualism",
    "answer": "refers to the tendency to separate phenomena into sharply opposed categories. with little room in between. Example: Good and Evil",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Hellenistic Period (332-167 BCE)",
    "answer": "Palestine became a part of the Seleucids, which was a period of terror: the Jews were severely persecuted.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Roman population has a large group of people similar to what we would call the \"middle class\" today.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Roman society defined <b>friends</b> as people who did things for each other.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The philosophical tendency to separate things into sharply opposed categories is called",
    "answer": "Dualism",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following were prominent tensions in the Hellenistic world except",
    "answer": "Salvation and damnation. (therefore purity and defilement, honor and shame, wealth and poverty were all prominent)",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The hellenistic social world included which of the following? a) A great deal if religious syncretism b) shocking economic inequality c) A wide variety of philosophical perspectives on life d) all of the above",
    "answer": "All of the above",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The writers of the New Testament were confident that what they were writing was scripture and should be treated as such.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The books of the New Testament are completely unified in their theological perspectives.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The study of the Bible with the intent to explain and analyze what a text actually says is called",
    "answer": "Exegesis",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The letters contained in the New Testament are arranged in chronological order based upon when they were written",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Reflection on the contents of the Bible and the process of interpretation with the intent of finding meaning through the lens of a particular philosophical stance is called:",
    "answer": "Hermeneutics",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a feature of Acts concerning the role and character of God?",
    "answer": "God only offers salvation to Israel",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In modern scholarship, the speeches in the Book of Acts are most often understood as . . .",
    "answer": "Literary devices for expressing Luke's own theology.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Powell, all of the following are reasons Luke wrote Acts except...",
    "answer": "To demonstrate the love and compassion of God through Christ for Roman rulers",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the \"We Passages\" in Acts?",
    "answer": "Passages where the author writes as a traveling companion of Paul",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a parallel between Luke and Acts?",
    "answer": "Jesus and the disciples receive the Holy Spirit and then preach a sermon",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the book of Acts, Jesus remains active on earth . . .",
    "answer": "The work of the Holy Spirit, The use of his name, Through the lives of his followers",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Acts, the Gentile mission...",
    "answer": "Begins in Jerusalem and spreads to all nations",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many missionary journeys of Paul are recorded in Acts?",
    "answer": "Three",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Luke created a number of speeches in Acts that relay in his own words the general sense of what the speakers said.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jesus is rejected by the Jews in Luke but they accept Paul in Acts",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "There are several discrepancies between how Acts portrays Paul and what Paul writes in his own letters.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Book of Acts provides a detailed account of everything that happened in the first three decades of Christianity.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a feature of letter writing in ancient times as reflected in the New Testament letters?",
    "answer": "The mandatory use of official roman Stamps or imprints on letters (therefore, amanuensis, co-authors, and use of entrusted individuals to deliver letters are all used in letters)",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the New Testament, Paul's letters to churches are arranged",
    "answer": "From Longest to Shortest",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which word meaning \"false ascription\" is applied to the practice of ancient authors attributing their own writings to other people?",
    "answer": "Pseudepigraphy",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a typical Christian greeting in an ancient letter?",
    "answer": "Grace and Peace",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Students writing letters in the name of their teachers was an established convention of the ancient world.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The early church always welcomed pseudepigraphical works and forgeries as long as they taught Christ.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "When preaching about Jesus in new areas, Paul usually follows which basic pattern?",
    "answer": "He targets urban, commercial settings",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul is known for his focus on what part of the story about Jesus?",
    "answer": "Jesus' death and resurrection",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The \"New Perspective on Paul\" is a scholarly view that:",
    "answer": "Understands \"works of the law\" not as \"works righteousness\" but as ethnic markers that designate Israel as God's chosen people",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Paul's letters and Acts, which of the following is not accurate?",
    "answer": "Paul was born in Jerusalem (therefore Paul studied under rabbi Gamaliel, was a roman citizen, and a jew)",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul's missionary travels are typically understood as being divided up into three missionary journeys.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In order to finance his mission work, Paul relied exclusively on income he received by working with his hands and did not rely on any financial support from the churches he established.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "People of the New Testament World",
    "answer": "Jews, Gentiles",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jews",
    "answer": "Shared many beliefs and practices in common, diverse in religious and political perspectives, diaspora Judaism",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Gentiles",
    "answer": "Any non-jew, various perspectives on Jews and judaism, God fearers",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Beliefs",
    "answer": "Torah/Law - first 5 books (and more!) shema. Messiah - anointed one, great human leader who would restore Israel to glory",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "practices",
    "answer": "Worship, circumcision, study of the Law, Sabbath, specific Diet.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Festivals",
    "answer": "Passover - recalls exodus from Egypt, ceremonial meal, sacrifice of lamb. Pentecost - celebrates giving of torah. Booths- commemorates 40 years of wandering in the desert.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Roman rule in the Early Christian era",
    "answer": "Emperors - Caligula (37-41), Claudius (41-54), Nero (54-68), Domitian (81-96). there were also local rulers.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Life under roman rule",
    "answer": "Jewish and Gentile residents. They were hellenized. <b>Pax Romana</b> (27BCE-180CE)<br>benefits - crime reduction, easy travel and communication<br>costs- high taxes, impoverishment &amp; slavery, military presence. <br>Religious freedom? and tension.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Social systems and cultural values",
    "answer": "Wealth and poverty, purity and defilement, patronage and loyalty, honor and shame.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Roman philosophies and religions. - attempting to answer life's largest questions",
    "answer": "Various philosophical schools, Greek and Roman mythology, mystery religions, and photo-gnosticism.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Religious Syncretism",
    "answer": "Blending of diverse religious perspectives.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "New Testament's Composition",
    "answer": "27 writings in 7 categories.<br>gospels<br>acts<br>\"pauls\" 9 letters to churches<br>\"pauls\" 4 letters to individuals <br>hebrews<br>7 catholic letters<br>revelation<br>books titles are based on claims, assumptions, and conventions.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "New testament's development",
    "answer": "Historical Jesus and church<br>early traditions about Jesus<br>Compositions of writings<br>use and preservation of writings<br>establishment of canon",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do we understand and interpret Scripture?",
    "answer": "Exegesis and Hermeneutics.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Facts about Acts",
    "answer": "Author - same person who wrote Luke (AKA part 1); similar outline. traveling companion of Paul's according to \"we passages\"<br>traditionally attributed to Luke.<br>Date - mid 80's<br>Full of good stories and good news but veers away from telling the WHOLE story. Celebrates accomplishments &amp; heroes",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "General History or hellenistic Biography?",
    "answer": "general history - records origin and progress of a group. excepted to be biased. Basic honesty, but a focus on primarily the good. <br>Hellenistic Biography? When paired with Luke, reports on the life and teachings of a teacher and the continuing mission and influence of his followers.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "parallels between Luke and Acts",
    "answer": "Possible Goals in writing Acts",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Unifying an increasingly diverse church, demonstrating Christianity is no political threat, converting pagans to this new faith, explaining how gentiles inherited God's promise, presenting a long-term theology of mission, encouraging believers. it agrees with some roman records, but still its reliability depends on who you ask and what your expect. There are discrepancies between the book of Acts and Paul's letters.",
    "answer": "Big Ideas of Acts",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "God's faithful guidance,<br>powerful presence of Jesus and the Spirit, salvation, church's expansion, turning the world upside down! (making them think something completely opposite.)",
    "answer": "Additional facts about acts",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Acts does not provide on unifies vision of what salvation looks like or how it happens. The idea of heaven is not particularly significant in Acts. Acts emphasizes that church members have become like Jesus, even about to perform miracles like his.",
    "answer": "Acts 1:1-11",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "A prologue - adressed to theophilus, the same as in Luke. Fitting Acts within the context of the story of Jesus and Jerusalem.",
    "answer": "Acts:12-26",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "A foundation from which to begin <br>rounding out the cohort of apostles, building a foundation from which the gospel can emanate.",
    "answer": "Tension builds",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "<b>With Jewish origins</b> <br>general tensions arise<br>Peter &amp; John Threatened (ch.4)<br>Apostles imporisoned (ch. 5)<br>Stephen stoned after preaching (ch 6-7)<br>James and Peter imporisoned (ch. 12)<br><b>within the church</b><br>Hebrew/hellenist controversy (ch.6)<br>Inclusion of Gentiles (ch. 10+)",
    "answer": "Hebrew-Hellenist controversy",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "<b>Hebrews</b><br>- spoke Aramaic<br>- more resistant to Greek culture and acceptance of Gentiles<br>- inclined to maintain Jewish customs after conversion<br>-all of life centered on the Temple<br><b>Hellenists</b><br>- spoke greek<br>-comfortable with Greek culture<br>-willing to accept gentile converts without imposing Jewish customs on them<br>- considered the Temple less important to Christian life<br><b>The issue &amp; solution</b><br>-Widows were being treated unequally<br>-the apostles don't have the time to oversee the matter<br>-select seven trustworthy men to oversee the work",
    "answer": "Once was blind(ed) slide facts",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Fulfillment rather than conversion<br>differing narratives in Acts 9, 22, 26; an experience of God, Saul/Paul is not the only hero, takes great faith to believe in God's surprising works through surprising people.",
    "answer": "What was foreshadowed comes to pass",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Every nation hears in its language (ch.2), Everyone who recognizes Jesus will be saved (ch.2), promise for all who are far off, if called (ch.2), all families of the earth shall be blessed (ch.3), anyone who fears God and does what is right (ch.10)",
    "answer": "Paul's First missionary Journey",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Participants- Paul, barnabas, John Mark (Acts 13-14)<br>Significant Stops - Antioch of Pisidia, Iconium, Lystra, Back to Antioch of Syria",
    "answer": "Do gentiles have to follow the Jewish law to become Christians?",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Not exactly",
    "answer": "Paul's second Missionary Journey",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "participants - Paul, Silas, Timothy, Priscilla and Aquila, Luke (15-18)<br>Significant Stops- wherever the spirit allows, Phillipi, Athens, Corinth, back to Jerusalem",
    "answer": "Paul's Third Missionary Journey",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Participants - Paul, Timothy, Luke (18-21)<br>Significant Stops - Ephesus, Miletus, Caesarea, Back to Jerusalem.",
    "answer": "Paul's Final Imprisonment",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Significant Places - Jerusalem, Caesarea, Crete, Malta, Rome (21-28)",
    "answer": "Names to know",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Theophilus, Matthias, Peter, Ananias &amp; sapphira, Stephen, Philip, Simon the magician, Saul/Paul, Ananias, Cornelius, Barnabas, John Mark, Silas, Timothy, Lydia, Aquila &amp; Priscilla, Felix, Festus, Agrippa",
    "answer": "Places to know",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In General - Jerusalem, Judea, Samaria, the Temple, Damascus.<br>Paul's Journeys - Phillipi, Athens, Areopahus, Corinth, Ephesus, Caesarea, Malta, Rome",
    "answer": "Events to Know",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "FILL IN 1.26",
    "answer": "Arrangement of New Testament Letters",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "<b>Arranged in four categories</b><br>Pauls letters to churches<br>Pauls letters to individuals<br>anonymous letter to the Hebrews<br>letters by James, Peter, John, and Jude.<br><b>Paul's letters arranged in order of length from longest to shortest within their categories</b>",
    "answer": "Groupings of New Testament letters",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pastoral epistles<br>captivity/prison epistles <br>catholic epistles",
    "answer": "Ancient snail mail",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "on clay tablets, pottery shards, wood, animal skin, or papyrus<br>by amanuensis - took direct dictation, authored a delegated portion. <br>with co-senders<br>through letter carriers<br>-represent author to recipients, read letter aloud to intended audience, interpret authors intent, wishes, or instructions. Return to sender with a report.<br>Convey the author's presence.",
    "answer": "General Letter structure",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Salutation/greeting<br>thanksgiving<br>body<br>closing<br>average greco-roman letter is 90 words<br>average Paul letter is 1300<br>shortest NT is 219",
    "answer": "Authenticity and pseudepigrpahy",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "<b>Seven levels of Authenticity</b><br>- literal authorship<br>- dictation<br>-delegated authorship<br>-posthumous authorship<br>-apprentice authorship<br>-honorable pseudepigraphy<br>-forgery<br><b>Early church nouns pseudepigraphal books helpful, but they rejected intentional forgeries</b>",
    "answer": "Paul's specs",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "<b>In a roman world</b><br>Roman citizen<br>native of tarsus<br>fluent in Greek<br>Surrounded by Gentiles<br><b>Hebrews of Hebrews</b><br>Tribe of Benjamin<br>circumcised on 8th day<br>educated in Jerusalem under Gamaliel <br>pharisee, blameless in the law<br>zealous for the church<br><b>Life changing revelation</b><br>change of heart and mind<br>a time of reflection and growth<br>a private meeting with church leaders",
    "answer": "Three missionary journeys details",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Targeted metropolitan areas, supervised missionaries and teams, provided financially when necessary, worked independently.",
    "answer": "Final years",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Desire to visit Spain, no reliable record of anything after Rome, early church traditions - a second career using his trade, executed by Nero in 64 CE",
    "answer": "The word \"apocrypha\" refers to what",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "15 additional books in the Greek old testament",
    "answer": "Most Roman citizens lived in a patron client relationship. Patrons would provide clients with food, Land, political areas with benefits or infrastructure. What do clients provide?",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Gratitude, loyalty, and praise.",
    "answer": "Uncleanliness, as understood in the Jewish religion, was always a bad or shameful thing.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 1 Laura Callarman",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267209667/bible-test-1-laura-callarman-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does Jesus do more often in Luke than in any other Gospel?",
    "answer": "Pray",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many times do people worship or give thanks to God in the Gospel of Luke?",
    "answer": "20",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not an early tradition about the author of Luke and Acts?<br>Answers:<br>He was a doctor<br>He traveled with Jesus<br>He was a historian<br>He was a painter",
    "answer": "He traveled with Jesus",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Gospel of Luke opens and closes with what?<br>Answers:<br>References to the Holy Spirit<br>The word \"Amen\"<br>People worshiping in the temple<br>Jesus taking on flesh (in birth) and shedding his flesh (at the ascension)",
    "answer": "People worshiping in the Temple",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What social groups are of special concern to Luke?<br>Answers:<br>Pharisees and Sadducees<br>Circumcised and uncircumcised people<br>Gentiles and Samaritans<br>Outcasts and marginalized people",
    "answer": "Outcasts and marginalized people",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do scholars characterize the author of Luke's Gospel?<br>Answers:<br>A learned person who knew Jewish scripture<br>A physician and companion to Paul<br>A well-educated lawyer and poet<br>A Gentile names \"Theophilus\"",
    "answer": "A learned person who knew Jewish scripture",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Luke portrays ______________ as \"the quality of life that God enables people to have in the present.\"",
    "answer": "Salvation",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which parable is not found in the Gospel of Luke?",
    "answer": "Parable of the Pearl of Great Price",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What Greek word refers to the second coming of Christ?<br>Answers:<br>Koinonia<br>Metanoia<br>Dynamis<br>Parousia",
    "answer": "Parousia",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In all likelihood, who was Theophilus, the name mentioned in the opening verses of Luke's Gospel?",
    "answer": "The one who paid for the book to be written",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is \"the Great Omission\"?",
    "answer": "The large section of Mark's Gospel that does not appear in Luke",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "More than Matthew, Mark, and John, Luke emphasizes the work of . . .<br>Answers:<br>Satan <br>The Holy Spirit<br>Jesus' disciples<br>Women",
    "answer": "The Holy Spirit",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The event in which Jesus Christ left the physical earth and was raised into heaven, as reported in Luke (24:50-51) and Acts (1:9), is called the . . .",
    "answer": "Ascension",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Luke's birth narrative is unique in its use of . . .",
    "answer": "Hymns",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the middle of Luke's Gospel is a long...",
    "answer": "Travel narrative",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The author of the Gospel of Luke also wrote what other New Testament book?",
    "answer": "Acts",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The author of Luke appears to have inserted material into the narrative structure of which Gospel?",
    "answer": "Mark",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What city receives special emphasis in the Gospel of Luke?",
    "answer": "Jerusalem",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Generally speaking, Luke alters Mark's Gospel to appeal to . . .",
    "answer": "A broader, more culturally diverse audience",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Luke's Gospel can be compared to a musical or an opera because . . .",
    "answer": "The narrative is interspersed with hymns and poetry",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Of the various groups marginalized and oppressed in the ancient world that are listed below, which is the prevailing concern in the Gospel of Luke?",
    "answer": "Poor people",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "To emphasize Jesus' connection to all humanity, Luke traces Jesus' genealogy back to whom?",
    "answer": "Adam",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What percentage of material is unique to Luke's Gospel (i.e., found nowhere else)?",
    "answer": "50%",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Luke portrays Jesus as one who . . .<br>Answers:<br>Fulfills expectations of Jewish scripture<br>Has features in common with mythological heroes<br>All of the above<br>Is similar to Hellenistic philosophers or benefactors",
    "answer": "All of the above",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about the use of the meal/food motif in the Gospel of Luke is true?<br>Answers: <br>Meals are supposed to be inclusive events<br>All of the above<br>Meals are occasions for instruction for humility and service<br>Meals are a symbol of God's blessing",
    "answer": "All of the above",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the predominant literary forms in John's Gospel is . . .",
    "answer": "Metaphor",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In John 4 the Samaritans confess that Jesus is...<br>Answers:<br>The Messiah<br>The Son of man<br>The Son of God<br>The Savior of the World",
    "answer": "The Savior of the World",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The writing of the Gospel of John is best characterized as . . .<br>Answers:<br>A theological reflection on the incarnation<br>A mythological presentation of the divine<br>A systematic biography of Jesus <br>A two-volume work dedicated to Theophilus",
    "answer": "A theological reflection on the incarnation",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "To what or whom does the Greek word Paraclete (often translated as Helper, Comforter, Advocate in English) refer in the Gospel of John?",
    "answer": "The Holy Spirit",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Fourth Gospel introduces Jesus as . . .",
    "answer": "Divine logos",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "John's Gospel repeatedly states that those who love Christ should keep his commandments. What one commandment of Jesus is particularly emphasized in that Gospel?",
    "answer": "Love your neighbor",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the Bible love is not primarily an emotion but a(n)",
    "answer": "Action",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the first miracle recorded in the Gospel of John?",
    "answer": "Turning water to wine",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What Gospel portrays Jesus as completely in control of his Passion, suffering, and death?",
    "answer": "John",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Gospel of John has a particularly negative view of what people group?",
    "answer": "Jews",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "John's Gospel has more to say about this than any of the other Gospels.",
    "answer": "Love",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Scholars who believe the Apostle John had a role in composing the Fourth Gospel associate him with which edition of the Gospel?",
    "answer": "First",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "John's Gospel refers to the opponents of Jesus as \"the Jews,\" by which is meant . . .",
    "answer": "A specific rival religious movement in the first century",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What Christian doctrine states that Christ existed (in the form of God) before he became the man Jesus who lived and died on earth?<br>Answers:<br>Preexistence<br>Logos<br>Resurrection<br>Incarnation",
    "answer": "Preexistence",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "From the perspective of modern scholars, which of the following best describes the composition of the Gospel of John?",
    "answer": "It is the testimony of one of Jesus' original disciples preserved and edited by leaders of the community he founded.",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What do theologians call the doctrine of God becoming human?<br>Answers: <br>Resurrection<br>Incarnation<br>Inflation<br>Ascension",
    "answer": "Incarnation",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Over 20 times in John's Gospel Jesus claims God is...",
    "answer": "The one who sent me",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the Gospel of John, Jesus refers to himself as all of the following except . . .<br>Answers:<br>Bread of Heaven<br>The second Adam<br>Living water<br>The way, the truth, the life",
    "answer": "The second Adam",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to John's Gospel, Jesus' death is also known as the hour in which he is...",
    "answer": "Glorified",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "One difference between John and the Synoptic Gospels is . . .<br>Answers:<br>Jesus washes the disciples' feet instead of eating Passover<br>Jesus attends to more blind people than poor people <br>Jesus doesn't die on a cross <br>Jesus' disciples are thirteen in number instead of twelve",
    "answer": "Jesus washes the disciples' feet instead of eating Passover",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In John's Gospel, \"the world\" refers to . . .",
    "answer": "Those who oppose Jesus and his followers",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In what decade do scholars believe the Gospel of John was written?",
    "answer": "90s",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Gospel of John is traditionally known as the . .<br>Answers:<br>Spiritual Gospel<br>Quintessential Gospel<br>Evangelical Gospel <br>Church's Gospel",
    "answer": "Spiritual Gospel",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the Gospel of John, when Jesus lays down his life for others he is acting as the ultimate . . .",
    "answer": "Friend",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Peter is often assumed to be the disciple closest to Jesus, but who has that role in John's Gospel?",
    "answer": "The beloved disciple",
    "user": "johnson_heather",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Test 3",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/108454567/bible-test-3-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "1:1-11- a prologue",
    "answer": "fitting acts within the context of the story of jesus and jerusalem.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jews",
    "answer": "Shared many beliefs and practices in common<br>Diversity in religious and political perspectives<br>Dispora Jews (Far way(",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Gentiles",
    "answer": "Non Jew<br>Various perspective on Jews and Judaism <br>God Fearers",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Torah/Law",
    "answer": "Five books (plus more)",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Messiah",
    "answer": "Anointed One<br>Great human leader who would restore isreal go glory.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Practices of Jews",
    "answer": "Worship<br>Circumcision<br>Study of the Law<br>Diet<br>Sabbath",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Passover",
    "answer": "Recalls Exodus from Egypt<br>Cerimonial Meal<br>Sacrifice of the lamb",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pentecost",
    "answer": "Celebrates giving of Torah",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Booths",
    "answer": "commemates 40 years of wandering in the desert",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Types of Emperors",
    "answer": "Caligula (37-41)<br>Cladius (41-54)<br>Nero (54-68)<br>Domitian (81-96)",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Life Under Roman Rule",
    "answer": "Jewish and Gentiles Residents<br>Hellenized<br>Pax Romana",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hellenization",
    "answer": "Influence of Greek Culture",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pax Romana",
    "answer": "Benefits : Crime reduction an easy communication and travel<br>Cost: High taxes, impoverishments and slavery, Military Presence <br>Religious freedom and tension",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Social System",
    "answer": "Wealth and Poverty<br>Purity and Defilement<br>Patronage and Loyalty<br>Honor and Shame",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "NT development",
    "answer": "Historical Jesus and church, early traditions, writings, establishments of canon",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Author of Acts",
    "answer": "Same person who wrote Luke <br>Traveling companion of Paul's.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Date of Acts",
    "answer": "mid 80s",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Acts",
    "answer": "Full of Good stories and accomplishments",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Acts (General History)",
    "answer": "Origins and Progress of Group<br>Biased<br>Primarily on the Good",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Acts (Hellenistic)",
    "answer": "When paired with Luke<br>Reports life and teachings of a teacher who continued influence",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Possible writing goals in Acts",
    "answer": "Unifying <br>Demonstrating Christianity is no political threat<br>Conversion <br>How Gentiles inherited God's promise<br>Long Term Theology Mission<br>Encouragement",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Big Ideas in Acts",
    "answer": "God's faithful Guidance<br>Powerful Presence of Jesus and Spirit<br>Salvation<br>Church's Expansion<br>Turning the world upside down",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "1:12-26- a foundation from which to begin",
    "answer": "-rounding out the cohort of apostles<br>-building a foundation from which the gospels can emanate.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "the Jewishness of early Christianity",
    "answer": "-the people<br>-the scriptures<br>-the stories",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "the spirit moves in a mysterious way",
    "answer": "signs of power!",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "the church of fellowship and all things together",
    "answer": "-a small but strong contingent<br>-faithful life in community<br>-unfaithful death to community",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "with jewish origins",
    "answer": "-general tensions rise<br>-peter and john threatened (chap 4)<br>-apostles imprisoned (chap 5)<br>-stephen stoned after preaching (ch 6-7)<br>-james and peter imprisoned (ch 12)",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "within the church",
    "answer": "-hebrew/helenist controversy (ch 6)<br>-inclusion of gentiles (ch 10)",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "hebrews",
    "answer": "-spoke aramaic<br>-more resistant to greek culture and acceptance of gentiles<br>-inclined to maintain jewish customs after conversion<br>-all of life centered on the temple",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "hellenists",
    "answer": "-spoke greek<br>-comfortable with greek culture<br>-willing to accept gentile converts without imposing jewish customs on them<br>-considered the temple less important to christian life",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "the issues and the solution",
    "answer": "-widows were being treated unequally<br>-the apostles don't have the time to oversee the matter<br>-select seven trustworthy men to oversee the work",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "once was blinded...",
    "answer": "-fullfilment rather than conversion<br>-differing narratives in acts 9, 22, 26<br>-an experience of god<br>-saul/paul is not the only hero<br>-takes great faith to belive in god's surprising works through surprising people",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "what god has made clean- what was foreshadowed comes to pass",
    "answer": "-every nation hears in its language (ch 2)<br>-everyone who recognizes jesus will be saved (ch 2)<br>-promise for all who are far off, if called (ch 2)<br>-all families of the earth shall be blessed (ch 3)<br>- anyone who fears god and does what is right (ch 10)",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "god does something unexpected",
    "answer": "-peter and cornelius (ch 10)<br>-cornelius' vision<br>-peter's vision<br>-a visit by/to the gentiles<br>-the holy spirit descends <br>-criticism and conversion",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "paul's first missionary journey",
    "answer": "Participants:<br>-paul<br>-barnabas<br>-john mark",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "significant stops in missionary #1",
    "answer": "-antioch of pisidia<br>-iconium<br>-lystra<br>-back to antioch of syria",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "participants in paul's missionary #2",
    "answer": "-paul<br>-silas<br>-timothy<br>-priscilla and aquila<br>-luke",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "significant stops of pauls missionary #2",
    "answer": "-wherever the spirit allows<br>-phillipi<br>-athens<br>-corinth<br>-back to jerusalem",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "participants in paul's missionary #3",
    "answer": "-paul<br>-timothy<br>-luke",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "significant stops in paul's missionary #3",
    "answer": "-ephesus<br>-miletus<br>-caesarea<br>-back to jerusalem",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "paul's final imprisonment: significant places",
    "answer": "-jerusalem<br>-caesarea<br>-crete<br>-malta<br>-rome",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "names to know",
    "answer": "-theophilus<br>-matthias<br>-peter<br>-ananias and sapphira<br>-stephen<br>-philip<br>-simon the magician<br>-saul/paul<br>-ananias<br>-cornelius<br>-barnabas<br>-john mark<br>-silas<br>-timothy<br>-lydia<br>-aquila and priscilla<br>-felix<br>-festus<br>-agrippa",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "places to know",
    "answer": "in general:<br>-jerusalem<br>-judea<br>-samaria<br>-the temple<br>-damascus",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "places to know",
    "answer": "pauls journeys:<br>-phillipi<br>-athens<br>-areopagus<br>-corinth<br>-ephesus<br>-caesarea<br>-malta<br>-rome",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "events to know",
    "answer": "-pentecost evens and sermons (ch 2)<br>-believers' sharing of all things (ch 2, 4)<br>-hebrew/hellenist dispute (ch 6)<br>-martydrom of stephen (ch 6-7)<br>-saul's \"conversion\" (ch 9, 22, 26)<br>-cornelius' and peter's visions (ch 10)<br>-first gentiles to receive the good news (ch 10)<br>-paul's missionary journeys<br>-jerusalem council (ch 15)<br>-paul's philippian imprisonment (ch 16)<br>-paul's speech to the athenians (ch 17)<br>-riot in ephesus (ch 19)<br>-pauls arrest in jerusalem, imprisonment, and transfter to rome (ch 21-28)",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "quiz 3",
    "answer": "1. which word meaning \"false ascription is applied to the practive of ancient authors attributing their own writings to other people? <br>-pseudepigraphy",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "quiz 3",
    "answer": "2. what is a typical christian greeting in an ancient letter?<br>-grace and peace",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "quiz 3",
    "answer": "3. in the new testament, paul's letters are arranged....<br>-from longest to shortest",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "quiz 3",
    "answer": "4. which is not a feature of letter writing in ancient times as a reflected in the NT letters?<br>-the mandatory use of official roman stamps or imprints on letters",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "quiz 3",
    "answer": "5. the early church always welcomed pseudepigraphical works and forgeries as long as they taugh christ<br>-false",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "quiz 3",
    "answer": "6. students writing letter in the name of their teachers was an established convention of the ancient world<br>-true",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "quiz 3",
    "answer": "7. the \"new perspective on paul\" is a scholarly view that:<br>-understands \"works of the law\" not as \"works righteosness\" but as ethnic markers that designate israel as god's chosen people",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "quiz 3",
    "answer": "8. according to pauls letters and acts, which of the following is not accurate?<br>-paul was born in jerusalem",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "quiz 3",
    "answer": "9. paul is known for his focus on what part of the story about jesus?<br>-jesus' death and resurrection",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Arrangement of NT letters",
    "answer": "Paul's Letters to Church<br>Paul's Letter to Individuals <br>Anonymous letters to Hebrew<br>Letters by James, Peter, John, and Jude",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "quiz 3",
    "answer": "10. when preaching about jesus in new areas, paul usually follows which basic pattern?<br>-he targets urban, commercial settings",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "quiz 3",
    "answer": "11. in order to finance his mission work, paul relied on the income received by working with his hands and didn't accept and money from the church<br>-false",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "quiz 3",
    "answer": "12. pauls missionary travels are typically understood as being divided up into three missionary journeys<br>-true",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Types of structures used",
    "answer": "Salutation/Greeting<br>Thanksgiving<br>Body<br>Closing",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pseudopigraphy",
    "answer": "Titling false authorship to book",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul had a",
    "answer": "Change in heart and mind .",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul went on...",
    "answer": "Three Missionary Journeys",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Final Years Of Paul",
    "answer": "Wanted to visit Spain<br>had no records after Rome",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "T/F The books of the New Testament are completely unified in their theological perspectives.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "T/F The letters contained in the New Testament are arranged in chronological order based upon when they were written.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "T/F The writers of the New Testament were confident that what they were writing was scripture and should be treated as such.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the book of Acts, Jesus remains active on earth . . .",
    "answer": "Through the work of the Holy Spirit. <br><br><br> Through the use of his name. <br><br><br> Through the lives of his followers.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "T/F Like many others in Roman society, Aquila and Prisca, the main leaders of the church, live a subsistence lifestyle of significant poverty.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "tTT",
    "answer": "...",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was a topic of major discussion",
    "answer": "The relationship between healing prayer and the medical practice. <br><br><br> The beauty of God's creation. <br><br><br> The use of spiritual gifts for the sake of others.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "T/F By the time the gathering was over, Publius felt like he had a good understanding of major Christian beliefs based upon the religious practices and ceremonies he had witnessed that evening.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "T/F The gathering of this church was an informal one, more like a family meal than anything resembling Roman or 21st century Christian religious practices and worship services.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many missionary journeys of Paul are recorded in Acts?",
    "answer": "Three",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In modern scholarship, the speeches in the Book of Acts are most often understood as . . .",
    "answer": "Literary devices for expressing Luke's own theology.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Powell, all of the following are reasons Luke wrote Acts",
    "answer": "To present a long-term theology of mission that awaited a distant second coming of Christ <br>To stave off persecution by showing that Christians were politically innocent <br>To explain how a predominantly Gentile Christianity could inherit God's promises to Israel",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a feature of Acts concerning the role and character of God?",
    "answer": "God only offers salvation to Israel",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "T/F The Book of Acts provides a detailed account of everything that happened in the first three decades of Christianity.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "T/F Jesus is rejected by the Jews in Luke but they accept Paul in Acts.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "T/F There are several discrepancies between how Acts portrays Paul and what Paul writes in his own letters.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "T/F Luke created a number of speeches in Acts that relay in his own words the general sense of what the speakers said.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Acts, the Gentile mission...",
    "answer": "Begins in Jerusalem and spreads to all nations",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a parallel between Luke and Acts?",
    "answer": "Jesus and the disciples receive the Holy Spirit and then preach a sermon",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the \"We Passages\" in Acts?",
    "answer": "Passages where the author writes as a traveling companion of Paul",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Reflection on the contents of the Bible and the process of interpretation with the intent of finding meaning through the lens of a particular philosophical stance is called:",
    "answer": "Hermeneutics",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The study of the Bible with the intent to explain and analyze what a text actually says is called:",
    "answer": "Exegesis",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "T/F Roman society defined friends as people who did things for each other.",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What were clients in the patron-client relationship supposed to provide",
    "answer": "Gratitude, loyalty and praise",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "T/F The Roman population had a large group of people similar to what we would call the \"middle class\"",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "T/F Uncleanliness was always bad or a shameful thing",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Apocrypha refers to what",
    "answer": "The fifteen additional books in the Greeks old testament",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Euangelion",
    "answer": "\"Good news\"",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul was interested in...",
    "answer": "Jesus' death and resurrection",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "When Paul spoke he..",
    "answer": "Targeted metropolitan areas<br>supervised missionaries and teams<br>Provided finances when needed<br>Worked independently",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul",
    "answer": "Roman Citizen<br>fluent in greek<br>surrounded by gentiles<br>circumcised on 8th day<br>educated under Gamaliel<br>Pharisee",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Length of the letters",
    "answer": "Average Greco Roman letter is 90 words",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Average letter by Paul is",
    "answer": "1300 Words",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Romans is about...",
    "answer": "7101 Words",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Shortest NT letter",
    "answer": "219 Words",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Letter Carriers",
    "answer": "Represent the Author<br>Reads letter out load<br>Interpret author's intent or wishes",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "NT Letters",
    "answer": "Pastoral Epistles <br>Captivity<br>Catholic Epistles",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ancient Mail",
    "answer": "was on clay tablets. pottery shards, wood, animal skin<br>Had cosenders",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Amanuensis",
    "answer": "Took dictate direction<br>Authored delegated portion",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul's letters are arranged..",
    "answer": "Length within the categories",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Bible Unit 1 Test",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/267499160/bible-unit-1-test-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Fakse teachers are dangerous and their judgement is certain",
    "answer": "2 Peter/Jude",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "matching bible 102.01",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/294166102/matching-bible-10201-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "this world is not our home, we are exiles but we will make it!",
    "answer": "1 Peter",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "matching bible 102.01",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/294166102/matching-bible-10201-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Wisdom is from above to help believers follow the way of life",
    "answer": "James",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "matching bible 102.01",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/294166102/matching-bible-10201-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "God wins. Choose a side, dont be stupid.",
    "answer": "Revelation",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "matching bible 102.01",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/294166102/matching-bible-10201-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Guidence to church leaders in the midst of tough times.",
    "answer": "Pastoral letters",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "matching bible 102.01",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/294166102/matching-bible-10201-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jesus is better. than everything. Seriously everything.",
    "answer": "Hebrews",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "matching bible 102.01",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/294166102/matching-bible-10201-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "God is love. imitate this true love in the midst of division.",
    "answer": "Johannine letters.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "matching bible 102.01",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/294166102/matching-bible-10201-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "characteristics of apocalyptic literature.",
    "answer": "â€¢ popular writing style from 200BCE - 100CE<br>â€¢ Symbolic poetry - numbers, fantastic creatures and beasts, cosmic catastrophes, names, cities <br>â€¢ Extensive use of visions <br> â€¢ God's perspective is shared <br> â€¢ Secrets are revealed, showing God's <br> â€¢ God is actively, faithfully carrying out the plan<br>â€¢ Dualism - No neutral ground!",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "matching bible 102.01",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/294166102/matching-bible-10201-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Interpretation of revelation",
    "answer": "Interpretations/Methods <br>â€¢ Futuristic &amp; Predictive <br>â€¢ letters represent eras of the future<br>â€¢Historical/Preterist <br>â€¢ Idealist/Timeless",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "matching bible 102.01",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/294166102/matching-bible-10201-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Connection between belief and behavior",
    "answer": "Paul faith is main - works are just a result of faith. <br>James - works is necessary for true faith/ proving faith. <br>corinthians - you are Devine in Christ and can do what you want/ eat but if it would cause others to fall dont do it.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "matching bible 102.01",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/294166102/matching-bible-10201-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Paul's letters and Acts, which of the following is not an aspect of Paul's early life?",
    "answer": "Paul was born in Jerusalem",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the book of Acts, Paul is also known by his Hebrew name",
    "answer": "Saul",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul understood his life changing revelation of Jesus as",
    "answer": "a prophetic call",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "After Paul's conversion, his thinking changed in all of the following ways EXCEPT",
    "answer": "before: Jesus was a prophet sent by God; after: Jesus is the son of God and Lord of all",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "It is generally believed that Paul spent the interim years between his conversion and his first missionary doing what?",
    "answer": "honoring his missionary skills and developing his theological understanding of the gospel",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a feature or strategy of Paul's missionary work?",
    "answer": "Paul's missionary work was authorized by Peter and the other leaders of the Jerusalem church",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In developing chronology for Paul's life, one of the most helpful pieces of information has been",
    "answer": "the brief mention in the book of Acts that Gallio was the proconsul of Corinth when Paul was in that city",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul's interest in Jesus focuses mainly on",
    "answer": "Jesus's death and resurrection",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Theologically, Paul understands Jesus to be",
    "answer": "the image of God, the son of God &amp; Lord",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul's ethical expectations for Christians are shaped by all EXCEPT",
    "answer": "the hedonic calculus: Christians must act so as to bring the greatest satisfaction to the greatest number of people",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is \"the New Perspective on Paul\"?",
    "answer": "a scholarly view that understands \"works of the law\" not as \"works of righteousness\" but as ethic markers that designate Israel as God's chosen people",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a proposed reason why Paul wrote Romans?",
    "answer": "to reestablish contact with the Romans church that he had established during his second missionary journey",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the thesis of Paul's letter to the Romans?",
    "answer": "The gospel reveals the righteousness of God through faith for faith",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Romans, the righteousness of God is shown through God's",
    "answer": "faithfulness and generosity",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The term justification derives from the language of",
    "answer": "God's covenant with Israel",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Romans, which of the following is NOT a possible meaning of 'faith' (pitis) in relation to being justified or put right with god",
    "answer": "People are justified by Paul's faithfulness in preaching the gospel",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "One image for explaining how Christ justifies people is redemption, which means",
    "answer": "with the blood of Christ God purchases freedom for people enslaved to sin, death, and the devil",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "One image for explaining how Christ justifies people is atonement, which means",
    "answer": "Jesus dies on the cross to offer a supreme sacrifice that fulfills God's requirement for nullifying sin",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "One image for explaining how Chris justifies people is reconciliation, which means",
    "answer": "Jesus offers his own life to restore the broken relationship between the people and God",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Prophets of \"the new perspective on Paul\" emphasizes which aspect of Paul's letter to the Romans, believing that it might be Paul's main point?",
    "answer": "the universal scope and availability of salvation",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Romans, Paul says that \"all israel will be saved,\" which as been interpreted as",
    "answer": "ALL OF THE ABOVE",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "With regard to governing authorities, Paul tells the Romans that",
    "answer": "governing authorities are instituted by God and must not be resisted",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Romans, Paul teaches that church members who know it is permissible to eat food that others think is sinful should",
    "answer": "forgo eating that food as an accommodation for those who might be injured by their action",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a description of Paul's stay and ministry in Corinth according to the book of Acts?",
    "answer": "Paul made a living preparing meats for the market place",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Corinth was the capital city of",
    "answer": "Achaia",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul writes 1 Corinthians in response to",
    "answer": "ALL OF THE ABOVE",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Divisions in the Corinthian Church seems to be based on",
    "answer": "Corinthians identifying themselves in terms of allegiance to prominent Christian leaders, whom they regard as wise and powerful",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul tells the Corinthians that he decided to know nothing among them but Christ",
    "answer": "cruicified",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In his teachings of the resurrection, Paul emphasizes in 1 Corinthians 15 that",
    "answer": "those who are raised by Christ will have new, glorified bodies",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Problems arose around the Lord's supper in the Corinthian church because",
    "answer": "wealthier members were eating the food before the lower class members arrived after long work hours",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1 Corinthians 5, Paul instructs the church to exclude from Christian fellowship a (presumably unrepentant) \"wicked man\" with the purpose of",
    "answer": "bringing about the repentance necessary for this person to be saved",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does Paul teach the Corinthians regarding marriage and sex?",
    "answer": "celibacy is preferable to marriage",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "With regards to eating \"food offered to idols\", Paul claims that believers should",
    "answer": "be willing to give up their rights for the sake of others",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to 1 Corinthians 13, what will abide forever?",
    "answer": "faith, hope, and love",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does Paul seem to regard the gift of prophecy as more important than speaking in tongues?",
    "answer": "it is more helpful to the church",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which feature of the ancient letter is actually lacking in Paul's letter to the Galatians?",
    "answer": "thanksgiving",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The significance of the debate over whether Galatians was writen to \"north Galatia\" or \"south Galatia\" is that the destination might determine whether",
    "answer": "the letter was written early or late in Paul's career",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does Paul think the Galatians are fools?",
    "answer": "they wanted to be circumcised",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul's opponents in Galatia have apparently said that his gospel lacks endorsement from the apostles in Jerusalem. Paul relies that",
    "answer": "the apostles in Jerusalem do approve",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul claims that if the Galatians seek justification (a right relationship with god) by observing the law they are nullifying",
    "answer": "the grace of God",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul's gospel includes all of the following temporal aspects EXCEPT",
    "answer": "God's new era in Christ is a time where both faith &amp; law operate",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did Paul rebuke Peter at Antioch?",
    "answer": "Peter quit eating with the Gentiles",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What role is especially ascibed to the Holy Spirit in Paul's letter to the Galatians?",
    "answer": "The Spirit bears virtuous fruit within believers",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2nd century writer Marcion actually knows and refers to what we know as \"the letter to the Ephesians\" as what letter?",
    "answer": "The Letter to the Laodiceans",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the Seven wonders of the ancient world was located in the city o fEphesus?",
    "answer": "The temple of Artemis of Ephisians",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ephesus is the capital city of",
    "answer": "Asia",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ephesians is remarkably similar and has close parallels to material found in what other New Testament letter, which has resulted in the two letters being called \"literary siblings\"?",
    "answer": "Colossians",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which word or words are missing from our most reliable Greek manuscripts?",
    "answer": "\"in Ephesus\"",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a feature or characteristic of Ephesians that is different in Paul's undisputed letters?",
    "answer": "Ephesians refers to the church as \"the body of Christ\"",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Scholars have explained the dissimilarity of Ephesians with Paul's undisputed letters in all of the following ways EXCPET",
    "answer": "Paul wrote Ephesians as a rough draft for Colossians but it was mistakenly inserted in the Pauline collection",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Ephesians, what was the mysterious plan of God?",
    "answer": "to unite all people in Christ",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Ephesians, the mysterious plan of God is accomplished in what to stages",
    "answer": "Jesus's crucifixion and exaltation",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "when the \"table of the household duties\" (Haustafel) found in Ephesians is compared to such tables that were typical for this culture and time period, the most remarkable aspect is",
    "answer": "the inclusion of instructions for husbands, fathers, and masters",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following strikes scholars as a distinctive aspect of Ephesians view of Christians?",
    "answer": "the exaltation of Christians to heaven is depicted as a present reality",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT of Ephisisan's idea or perspective of the church?",
    "answer": "there are two dimensions of the church, the heavenly ministry inspired by Christ but also the sinful struggle of living in this world",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The city of Philippi was",
    "answer": "a Roman colony dominated by retired Roman soliders",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The church in Philippi is often thought to be the first Christian church",
    "answer": "in Europe",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul's letters to the Philippians is best designated as",
    "answer": "a friendship letter",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The \"Christ Hymn\" in Philippians contains the earliest reference in Christian literature to the idea that Christ",
    "answer": "existed before he was the man Jesus",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul urges the Philippians to have humility, which in this letter means",
    "answer": "to put others first and consciously seek what is best for others over what may be best for oneself",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul indicates to the Philippians that suffering can actually have all of the following positive effects EXCEPT",
    "answer": "suffering for Christ completes their salvation",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The theme of fellowship in Paul's letters to the Philippians is exemplified by Paul's repeated reference to the members of the church as",
    "answer": "siblings",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What catastrophe destroyed the town of Colossae around the year 61 CE?",
    "answer": "earthquake",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a feature or fact of the city of Colossae?",
    "answer": "Colossae was the hometown of the emperor Nero",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The church of Colossae",
    "answer": "was not founded by Paul, but his coworker Epaphras",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not an aspect of the so-called \"Colossian heresy\" (the philosophy or teaching that threatens their Christian identity and faith?",
    "answer": "Christ fully devine but only appeared to be human",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In addition ot its parallels with Ephesians, Colossians is also closely tied to the production of this Pauline letter",
    "answer": "Philemon",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Colossians presents Christ as exalted and cosmic in all of the following ways EXCEPT",
    "answer": "Christ descended to Hades",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The realized eschatology of Colossians is particularly evident in the claim that",
    "answer": "the Colossian Christians have been raised with Christ",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Realized eschatology functions in Colossians to",
    "answer": "assure the Colossians that no power in the universe is able to affect those who believe in Christ",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Colossians, spiritual growth and maturity is attained by",
    "answer": "remaining steadfast in what they have already been taught",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The image in Colossians of people stripping off old ways of being human and clothing themselves with virtuous behavior may derive from",
    "answer": "early Christian baptismal practices",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What Roman road was a major land route across northern Greece and Asia Minor and ran through Thessalonica?",
    "answer": "Via Egnatia",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What customary greeting in Pauline churches became a standard component of the Christian worship service in the second century?",
    "answer": "kiss of peace",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "First Thessalonians has the distinction of being",
    "answer": "the earliest of Paul's letters that have survived",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Thessalonica was the capital city of",
    "answer": "Macedonia",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning the depiction of Paul's ministry in Thessalonica,",
    "answer": "Acts focuses on his preaching in the Jewish synagogue while 1 Thessalonians assumes a ministry in the marketplace practicing a trade",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1 Thessalonians, Paul says that the wrath of God has overtaken the Jews for all of the following reasons except",
    "answer": "they continue to sacrifice in the Temple",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The suffering experienced by the Thessalonian Christians was most likely",
    "answer": "social shaming for not participating in the religious and entertainment events of the city",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "One notable characteristic of 1 Thessalonians is the number of times that Paul",
    "answer": "reminds his readers of things that they already know",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "With regard to the Thessalonians, Paul says that he and his companions have been",
    "answer": "ALL OF THE ABOVE",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1 Thessalonians, Paul addresses concerns about those who died",
    "answer": "before Christ returned",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "1 Timothy, 2 Timothy, and Titus are commonly called the \"Pastoral Letters\" because",
    "answer": "they are addressed to individuals charged with the oversight of congregations.",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not true of the person Timothy?",
    "answer": "He was converted from Cynicism.",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The person Titus is best known for",
    "answer": "being brought to Jerusalem by Paul as a test case for the church in deciding whether Gentile converts needed to be circumcised.",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a church office mentioned in the Pastoral Letters?",
    "answer": "priest",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Qualifications for church leadership in the Pastoral Letters include all of the following except",
    "answer": "musical ability",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "A primary emphasis of the Pastoral Letters is",
    "answer": "preserving sound doctrine",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a proposal to explain why the Pastoral Letters do not quite fit with Paul's career?",
    "answer": "The Pastoral Letters are compilations of several letters from different times of Paul's life.",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the Pastoral Letters, instructions concerning women in ministry include all of the following EXCEPT",
    "answer": "women may baptize other women. <br>women may baptize other women.",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The genre of Hebrews is best understood as a",
    "answer": "sermon",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hebrews addresses a situation in which its recipients",
    "answer": "are being tempted to embrace a form of Judaism in a way that fails to appreciate the supremacy of Christ",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The two main themes of Hebrews that are emphasized repeatedly are",
    "answer": "the superiority of Christ and the condemnation of apostasy",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The authorship of Hebrews is accurately described as",
    "answer": "anonymous",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The relationship of Christianity to Judaism is presented in Hebrews as",
    "answer": "Christianity has continuity with Judaism but is superior to it",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not an aspect or feature of Hebrews' theology about Jesus Christ?",
    "answer": "fully divine but only appeared to be human",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The humanity of Christ is theologically significant in Hebrews in all of the following ways except",
    "answer": "being human allows Christ to trick the devil so that his divinity can then destroy evil",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What dominant image of Jesus in Hebrews is almost entirely absent elsewhere in the New Testament?",
    "answer": "a high preist",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What image does Hebrews use for salvation?",
    "answer": "rest",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hebrews seems to teach that people who come to the truth and then fall away or continue in sin",
    "answer": "will not be forgiven even if they repent",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The \"James\" that is traditionally identified as the author of this letter is",
    "answer": "the brother of Jesus who became the leader of the Jerusalem church",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the ideas and style, the letter of James seems to have been influenced by all of the following traditions except",
    "answer": "Jewish mystical tradition",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Numerous passages in the letter of James have close parallels to",
    "answer": "the Sermon on the Mount",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the letter of James, the source of temptation is",
    "answer": "One's own desires",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not an aspect or characteristic of \"wisdom from above\" according to James?",
    "answer": "It is a secret knowledge that provides salvation",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to James, believers need to choose between a fundamental orientation of life defined by either",
    "answer": "God or the world",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Most scholars believe that there is no conflict between Paul and James on the issue of faith and works, but that they use different terms in different ways as all of the following illustrate EXCEPT",
    "answer": "both speak of Jesus' faith as a work that achieves salvation",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the letter of James, God has a strong preference for",
    "answer": "the poor over the rich",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Second Peter is considered pseudepigraphical for all of the following reasons except",
    "answer": "it unwittingly shows pseudepigraphy by mentioning a fraudulent letter being circulated in Peter's name",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Second Peter used this New Testament writing as a source.",
    "answer": "Jude",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The genre of 2 Peter is best understood as",
    "answer": "a testament",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "A primary purpose of 2 Peter is",
    "answer": "to warn about and counter the effects of false teaching",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Second Peter responds to the delay of Christ's second coming in all of the following ways except",
    "answer": "Christ will not return until all Jews accept Jesus as messiah and the Gospel is preached to all the world",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2 Peter, what theme functions both to emphasize accountability for the wicked and to motivate a life of godliness for believers?",
    "answer": "the coming judgement",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In terms of the authorship of 1, 2, and 3 John (the Johannine letters), which of the following is not a fact?",
    "answer": "Only 1 John mentions the author as John.",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of all three letters is",
    "answer": "to deal with conflict and schism in Johannine churches.",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The genre of 1 John is probably best described as",
    "answer": "a theological tract",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The elder who writes 2 John and 3 John responds to conflict in the church by",
    "answer": "forbidding church members to show hospitality to those who have left",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "An important theological emphasis in the Johannine letters is",
    "answer": "the humanity of Jesus",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "First John addresses the issue of sin in all the following ways except",
    "answer": "those who commit a \"mortal sin\" must be restored to the church in order to be saved.",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The central message of love in the Johannine letters is",
    "answer": "love one another",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Most Greek manuscripts of Revelation contain the number 666 for the number of the beast (13:18), but some manuscripts have this number.",
    "answer": "616",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The book of Revelation shares features of all the following genres except",
    "answer": "homily",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a feature of apocalyptic literature, such as Revelation?",
    "answer": "linear, chronological narrative",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Reading the seven letters of Revelation as descriptions of future eras of church history is illustrative of which approach?",
    "answer": "futurist",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Reading the number of the beast (666) as a reference to the Roman emperor Nero, or perhaps Domitian, is illustrative of which approach?",
    "answer": "historical",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Academic scholarship has a clear preference for the historical reading of Revelation because of the book's intent (based on the book's genre)`",
    "answer": "to address the current circumstances of its original leaders",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Most interpreters today identify the author of Revelation as",
    "answer": "an otherwise unknown Christian prophet named John",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The dominant theory places the writing of Revelation during the reign of which Roman emperor?",
    "answer": "Domitian",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The seven churches addressed in Revelation were all cities of which Roman province?",
    "answer": "Asia",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The churches in Revelation appear to have experienced any one or all of the following situations except",
    "answer": "natural catastrophes such as earthquakes and plagues",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the Greek term that means \"unveiling\" from which the book of Revelation get its title (1:1)?",
    "answer": "apokalypsis",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The book of Revelation portrays the city of Rome as a",
    "answer": "drunken *****",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "With its expected invitation to joy, the book of Revelation is threaded with",
    "answer": "hymns or songs of worship",
    "user": "sthornto1",
    "pageTitle": "New Testament Final",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/42386865/new-testament-final-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jesus conducted his ministry during the reign of which Roman emperor?",
    "answer": "Tiberius",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "True or False: Most of the New Testament books were composed during the second century",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Define \"subsistence level\" living",
    "answer": "Life is a struggle, making just enough money to survive",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which scholarly inquiry investigates how age, gender, nationality, economic status and other factors shape one's reading of and response to the biblical text?",
    "answer": "Reader-Response criticism",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which method of biblical research is used by postmodern critics who assert that all interpretations of texts are based on subjective criteria and therefore cannot claim to be authoritative?",
    "answer": "Deconstruction",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name given to Aramaic paraphrases of the biblical text that were read in synagogue services because only the Jewish religious leaders understood Hebrew?",
    "answer": "Targum",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Herod did Jesus call a \"fox\"?",
    "answer": "Herod Antipas",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the Hebrew word for the pool in which one would take a ritual bath?",
    "answer": "Mikhev",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Define Exegesis",
    "answer": "The explication of texts",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Define Hermeneutics",
    "answer": "Philosophical reflection on the art of interpretation",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "To what do the word \"Septuagint\" and the symbol \"LXX\" refer?",
    "answer": "The Greek translation of the Hebrew Bible",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jesus was born during the reign of which Roman emperor?",
    "answer": "Augustus",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The influence of Greek philosophy on the first century world resulted in many Jews placing greater emphasis on what part of their scriptures?",
    "answer": "The wisdom literature",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which group practiced ritual baths and sacred meals similar to the Christians' baptism and Eucharist (Lord's Supper)?",
    "answer": "Essenes",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The New Testament does not mention which Jewish group?",
    "answer": "Essenes",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The time in Jewish history between the return from the Babylonian Exile (515 BCE) and the destruction of the Jerusalem temple (70 CE) is called...?",
    "answer": "Second temple Judaism",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Define Gentiles",
    "answer": "Any nation other than the Jews",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the \"Apostolic Tradition\"?",
    "answer": "The written works of those who could be connected with Jesus or Paul",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What name is given the belief that Jesus, because he was spiritual, was never actually human (i.e., physical) but only appeared to be made of flesh?",
    "answer": "Docetism",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Herod married his niece (who divorced another uncle in order to marry him)?",
    "answer": "Herod Antipas",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "When Jesus lived, who exercised the most power among the different Jewish groups?",
    "answer": "Sadducees",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Define Canon",
    "answer": "Rule",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Herod killed John the Baptist?",
    "answer": "Herod Antipas",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Herod put James, the disciple of Jesus, to death and imprisoned Peter?",
    "answer": "Herod Agrippa I",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which term applies to Jews residing outside their traditional homeland of Palestine?",
    "answer": "Diaspora",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Greek philosophy emphasized free will and the enjoyment of all things in moderation?",
    "answer": "Epicureanism",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which period did Jews increasingly focus on faithfulness to Torah as the hallmark of their religion?",
    "answer": "Persian",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which New Testament book is \"part two\" of the Gospel of Luke?",
    "answer": "Acts",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many people have the name Herod in the New Testament?",
    "answer": "3",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which period did synagogues emerge as significant sites for Jewish teaching and worship?",
    "answer": "Persian",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was Jesus' primary role in (many forms of) Gnostic Christianity?",
    "answer": "To impart secret knowledge",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which period of Jewish history did groups like the Pharisees and Sadducees begin to develop?",
    "answer": "Hasmonean",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Apostle encouraged churches to whom he had written to exchange letters with one another?",
    "answer": "Paul",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What two developments in early Christianity made the canon an issue for Christians?",
    "answer": "1) some Christians were excluding certain writings and 2) some Christians were producing new writings and attributing them to apostles",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "To what does the Aramaic word \"Sanhedrin\" refer?",
    "answer": "The religious ruling Council in Jerusalem",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The German phrase \"Sitz im Leben,\" which is frequently used even in English writings about Form Critical approaches to the Bible, means what?",
    "answer": "Setting in Life",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which group did not exercise a dominating influence over Israel during the Hellenistic Period?",
    "answer": "The Attalids",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What academic discipline studies culture through comparative methods in terms of kinship relations, power structures, gender roles, economic systems, and education?",
    "answer": "Cultural anthropology",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which pair of words listed below most often describe the working of the patron and client (respectively) in the patron-client relationship?",
    "answer": "Grace and faith",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which phrase below best describes the Pharisees?",
    "answer": "Believed in bodily resurrection",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What Seleucid ruler sought to impose Greek religion and culture on the Jews in the second century BCE?",
    "answer": "Antiochus IV Epiphanes",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "True or False: The Jews and Samaritans viewed themselves as sharing a common religion",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did the Romans destroy the Jerusalem Temple?",
    "answer": "70 CE",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "After the Bar Kokhba rebellion, led by Simon bar Kosiba, the Romans excluded Jews from entering what city?",
    "answer": "Jerusalem",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which group living in Palestine claimed to be descended from the \"lost\" tribes of Israel?",
    "answer": "Samaritans",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Caesar Augustus reportedly coined a proverb based on a person mentioned in the Gospels: \"Better to be a pig than a son in the house of ________.\"",
    "answer": "Herod",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In what region did Jesus live and do most of his work?",
    "answer": "Galilee",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Define Pax Romana",
    "answer": "Unprecedented unity in the world provided by the Romans",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is the longest book of the New Testament?",
    "answer": "Luke",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Define Hellenism",
    "answer": "The prominence of Greek culture in the Roman Empire",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The New Testament was written at a time when the Mediterranean world was dominated by which nation?",
    "answer": "Rome",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which scholarly discipline works with \"variant readings\"?",
    "answer": "Textual criticism",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Of the many general spiritual beliefs circulating during Roman times, which devoted itself to discerning the future through oracles, mediums, or observing phenomena?",
    "answer": "Augury",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What name or title did the most prevalent form of Gnosticism give to the evil God who created matter, thus entrapping eternal spirits in flesh?",
    "answer": "Demiurge",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which New Testament book offers an account of a visionary experience of a prophet named John?",
    "answer": "Revelation",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which category of New Testament books does James belong?",
    "answer": "Letters by other people",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What literary work contains a collection of rabbinic discussions regarding the interpretation of the Law of Moses?",
    "answer": "Mishnah",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "This dynasty ruled the Jewish state established by the Maccabees for about a century prior to conquest by the Roman Empire in 63 BCE.",
    "answer": "The Hasmoneans",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Approximately what percentage of the Roman population was extremely poor?",
    "answer": "90%",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What types of religious groups employing secret rituals were very popular in the Roman world?",
    "answer": "Mystery religions",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Approximately what percentage of the Roman population was extremely rich?",
    "answer": "3%",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Greek philosophy emphasized the attainment of virtue through the acceptance of fate?",
    "answer": "Stoicism",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which scholarly study excavates ancient cities and other sites?",
    "answer": "Archeology",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Define God-fearers",
    "answer": "Gentiles embracing Jewish worship and morals",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What percentage of the Roman population lived below subsistence level?",
    "answer": "28%",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Roman emperor expelled Jews from the city of Rome for a disturbance over someone named \"Chrestus\" (probably a mangled reference to Christ)?",
    "answer": "Claudius",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is the shortest book of the New Testament?",
    "answer": "3 John",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Of the many general spiritual beliefs circulating during Roman times, which assumed spirits could possess people, animals, and other entities?",
    "answer": "Animism",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "True or False: The Hellenistic social world included increased religious syncretism, grotesque economic inequality, and acute awareness of honor and shame",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Define Torah",
    "answer": "The Law of Moses",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which group is most likely associated with the Dead Sea Scrolls?",
    "answer": "Essenes",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the primary language for Jews living outside of Palestine in Jesus' day?",
    "answer": "Greek",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What area of scholarly study examines matters that characterized the social world such as the Pax Romana and an economic system with virtually no middle class?",
    "answer": "Sociological criticism",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Old Testament books of disputed canonical status are called the...?",
    "answer": "Apocrypha",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which New Testament book is in a category all by itself and is an anonymous work addressed to a group of Jewish Christians?",
    "answer": "Hebrews",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the pivotal social value in the New Testament world?",
    "answer": "Honor",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Israel had reached its high point under the rulership of which king 1,000 years before Jesus lived?",
    "answer": "David",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Of the many general spiritual beliefs circulating during Roman times, which appeared in the second century CE and regarded \"spirit\" as good and \"matter\" as evil?",
    "answer": "Gnosticism",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Define Talmud",
    "answer": "A work of 63 books interpreting the Mishnah",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Jewish group in Jesus' day considered \"the tradition of the elders\" as an authoritative understanding of God's will for His people?",
    "answer": "Pharisees",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Text criticism is a method of...?",
    "answer": "Reconstructing early Christian manuscripts",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which historical period did the Israelites enjoy freedom from foreign domination?",
    "answer": "Hasmonean",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "True or False: Sadducees can generally be described as wealthy, politically well-connected men",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which area of Hellenistic thought tended to rule out \"gray areas,\" making everything either \"good\" or \"evil.\"",
    "answer": "Dualism",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Books in the New Testament that tell about the life of Jesus fall into which category?",
    "answer": "Gospels",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "This Christian who lived in the second century created a canon that consisted of the Gospel of Luke and a collection of Paul's letters.",
    "answer": "Marcion",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Roman emperor violently persecuted Christians?",
    "answer": "Nero",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Herod ordered a massacre of babies in Bethlehem trying to kill the young Jesus?",
    "answer": "Herod the Great",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Greek philosophy repudiated shame, sought a simple lifestyle, and desired only what could be obtained naturally and freely?",
    "answer": "Cynicisim",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "True or False: Cultural Anthropology should be considered an Ideological criticism",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The High Priest in Jerusalem belonged to which group?",
    "answer": "Sadducees",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to general estimates, slaves constituted approximately what percentage of the population of the Roman Empire?",
    "answer": "30%",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What field of biblical study identifies genres incorporated into texts (like parables, genealogies, etc.) and speculates about the community life that generated those genres?",
    "answer": "Form Criticism",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Define Apocrypha",
    "answer": "15 additional books in the Greek Old Testament",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "On what basis are the letters in the New Testament ordered?",
    "answer": "Length",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Define Limited Good",
    "answer": "The idea that money and material goods were in short supply; for you to gain, someone else must lose",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Of the many general spiritual beliefs circulating during Roman times, which considered miracles possible?",
    "answer": "Supernaturalism",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Scholars working primarily in the Gospels and Acts who apply insights from modern literary analysis practice what type of methodology?",
    "answer": "Narrative criticism",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which emperor initiated the first government-sponsored persecution of Christians that cost the lives of Peter, Paul, and many other disciples?",
    "answer": "Nero",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which term below describes the capacity for any text to mean different things to different people?",
    "answer": "Polyvalence",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Most people in the Roman Empire belonged in at least one patron-client relationship. Patrons would provide individuals with food or land and political areas (cities, provinces, empire) with benefits or infrastructure. In exchange, what were \"clients\" expected to provide?",
    "answer": "Gratitude, loyalty, and praise",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "True or False: Apocalypticism refers to a dualistic outlook, a deterministic view of history , and a pessimistic view of the future",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a theios aner?",
    "answer": "A divine man",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "True or False: The large number of Jews who lived outside of Palestine, their traditional homeland resulted in an increased hatred of Pharisees over other Jewish groups",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "True or False: Both Compositional analysis and Emendation analysis are methods of redaction criticism that consider how units are arranged and how sources have been altered",
    "answer": "True",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The themes of Mark's Gospel fit most closely with what person mentioned in the New Testament?",
    "answer": "Paul",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Define Messianic secret",
    "answer": "Jesus doesn't want people to realize he's the Messiah, and he goes to great lengths to keep things secret",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Martin KÃ¤hler described Mark's Gospel as \"a passion narrative with an extended introduction.\" Why?",
    "answer": "A greater percentage of the Gospel of mark is devoted to the Passion, and everything else leads up to it.",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Mark's Gospel, what is the only phrase Jesus makes on the cross?",
    "answer": "\"My God, My God, why have You forsaken me?\"",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Mark uses this more than any of the other Gospel writers.",
    "answer": "Historical present",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which literary device repeats parallel expressions at the beginning and end of a literary unit?",
    "answer": "Inclusio",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name for the literary device where an author places one story in the middle of another?",
    "answer": "Intercalation",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Mark, Jesus speaks in parables so that...?",
    "answer": "People won't understand him",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is considered \"the masterpiece of the four Gospels\" by scholars studying the Bible as literature?",
    "answer": "Mark",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The section of Mark's Gospel devoted to Jesus' predictions of his death and teachings about discipleship (8:22-10:52) begins and ends with what type of miracle?",
    "answer": "Healing of blindness",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What word occurs 42 times in Mark's Gospel - eleven times in the first chapter - and is characteristic of its narrative style?",
    "answer": "Immediately",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Mark was writing to...",
    "answer": "Roman Christians",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In John's Gospel, \"the world\" refers to...?",
    "answer": "The parts of the world hostile to Christianity",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What Gospel portrays Jesus as completely in control of his Passion, suffering, and death?",
    "answer": "John",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What Christian doctrine states that Christ existed (in the form of God) before he became the man Jesus who lived and died on earth?",
    "answer": "Preexistence",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Over 20 times in John's Gospel Jesus claims God is...?",
    "answer": "The One Who sent Him",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Peter is often assumed to be the disciple closest to Jesus, but who has that role in John's Gospel?",
    "answer": "The beloved disciple",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "John's Gospel refers to the opponents of Jesus as \"the Jews,\" by which is meant...?",
    "answer": "A specific Jewish sect during the first century",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Fourth Gospel introduces Jesus as...",
    "answer": "God",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the Bible love is not primarily an emotion but a(n)...?",
    "answer": "Action",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Gospel of John has a particularly negative view of what people group?",
    "answer": "Jews",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "To what or whom does the Greek word Paraclete (often translated as Helper, Comforter, Advocate in English) refer in the Gospel of John?",
    "answer": "The Holy Spirit",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "True or False: In the Gospel of John, Jesus refers to himself as the second Adam.",
    "answer": "False",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "John's Gospel has more to say about this than any of the other Gospels",
    "answer": "Love",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to John's Gospel, Jesus' death is also known as the hour in which he is...",
    "answer": "Glorified",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "From the perspective of modern scholars, which of the following best describes the composition of the Gospel of John?",
    "answer": "A close apostle of Jesus wrote a testimony that his community later edited",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In John 4 the Samaritans confess that Jesus is...?",
    "answer": "The Savior of the world",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "One difference between John and the Synoptic Gospels is...?",
    "answer": "Jesus washes the disciples' feet instead of having The Last Supper",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the Gospel of John, when Jesus lays down his life for others he is acting as the ultimate...?",
    "answer": "Friend",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In what decade do scholars believe the Gospel of John was written?",
    "answer": "90s",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the first miracle recorded in the Gospel of John?",
    "answer": "Water into wine",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "John's Gospel repeatedly states that those who love Christ should keep his commandments. What one commandment of Jesus is particularly emphasized in that Gospel?",
    "answer": "Love one another",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the predominant literary forms in John's Gospel is...?",
    "answer": "Symbolism/Metaphor",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Gospel of John is traditionally known as the...?",
    "answer": "Spiritual Gospel",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Scholars who believe the Apostle John had a role in composing the Fourth Gospel associate him with which edition of the Gospel?",
    "answer": "The first edition",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What do theologians call the doctrine of God becoming human?",
    "answer": "Incarnation",
    "user": "Garrett_Reynolds73",
    "pageTitle": "NT Quizzes",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/123845250/nt-quizzes-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Romans, Paul teaches that church members who know that it is permissible to eat the food which others think it is sinful to eat should do what?",
    "answer": "Avoid eating that food as an accommodation to those who might be offended by their action",
    "user": "micaelajanssen",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Ch. 11 - 12",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/121425322/powell-ch-11-12-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "People have been unfaithful to God and destroyed the relationship between humanity and God. When Jesus repairs this relationship this is called...",
    "answer": "reconciliation",
    "user": "micaelajanssen",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Ch. 11 - 12",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/121425322/powell-ch-11-12-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Romans 6, Paul interperpates this ritual as the believer's participation in Christ's, death, burial, and resurrection.",
    "answer": "baptism",
    "user": "micaelajanssen",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Ch. 11 - 12",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/121425322/powell-ch-11-12-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Many chronologies of Paul's life start with the connection this governor who served in Corinth from the summer of 51 to the summer of 52",
    "answer": "Gallio",
    "user": "micaelajanssen",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Ch. 11 - 12",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/121425322/powell-ch-11-12-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul was a young man when he witnessed the death of the first christian martyr, but he considers himself an old man when he pens which letter?",
    "answer": "Philemon",
    "user": "micaelajanssen",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Ch. 11 - 12",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/121425322/powell-ch-11-12-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Judaism, which rite is viewed as a sign of the covenant God mad with Israel?",
    "answer": "circumcision",
    "user": "micaelajanssen",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Ch. 11 - 12",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/121425322/powell-ch-11-12-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Paul's letters and Acts, which of the following is not an aspect of Paul's early life?",
    "answer": "Paul was born in Jerusalem",
    "user": "micaelajanssen",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Ch. 11 - 12",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/121425322/powell-ch-11-12-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Romans, the word justification is most closely associated with what idea?",
    "answer": "reconciliation",
    "user": "micaelajanssen",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Ch. 11 - 12",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/121425322/powell-ch-11-12-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pauls was a member of which Jewish tribe?",
    "answer": "Benjamin",
    "user": "micaelajanssen",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Ch. 11 - 12",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/121425322/powell-ch-11-12-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the Book of Acts, Paul is also known by this Hebrew name",
    "answer": "Saul",
    "user": "micaelajanssen",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Ch. 11 - 12",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/121425322/powell-ch-11-12-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "For Paul, Christian ethics are shaped primarily by what?",
    "answer": "the imitation of Christ",
    "user": "micaelajanssen",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Ch. 11 - 12",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/121425322/powell-ch-11-12-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "After Paul's conversion, his thinking changed in all of the following ways except...",
    "answer": "before: Jesus was a prophet sent by God<br>after: Jesus is the son of God and Lord of all",
    "user": "micaelajanssen",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Ch. 11 - 12",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/121425322/powell-ch-11-12-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "It is generally believed that Paul spent the interim years between his conversion ad his first missionary journey during what?",
    "answer": "Honing his missionary skills and developing his theological understanding of the gospel",
    "user": "micaelajanssen",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Ch. 11 - 12",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/121425322/powell-ch-11-12-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Paul's letter to the Romans, how is God faithful to God's promises to Israel?",
    "answer": "salvation comes through a Jewish Messiah",
    "user": "micaelajanssen",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Ch. 11 - 12",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/121425322/powell-ch-11-12-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Powell, \"The cross becomes the emblem of not only Christian salvation, but also of Christian ________\"",
    "answer": "conduct",
    "user": "micaelajanssen",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Ch. 11 - 12",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/121425322/powell-ch-11-12-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "For what reason was Paul writing to churches in Rome?",
    "answer": "-gain support for his next missionary journey <br> -To ask for contributions to the collection <br> -To offer theological advice on specific problems <br>ALL OF THE ABVOE",
    "user": "micaelajanssen",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Ch. 11 - 12",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/121425322/powell-ch-11-12-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul is known for his focus on what part of the story about Jesus?",
    "answer": "Jesus' death and resurrection",
    "user": "micaelajanssen",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Ch. 11 - 12",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/121425322/powell-ch-11-12-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "One image for explaining how Christ justifies people is atonement, which basically means what?",
    "answer": "Jesus dies on the cross to offer a supreme sacrifice that fulfills God's requirement...",
    "user": "micaelajanssen",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Ch. 11 - 12",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/121425322/powell-ch-11-12-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "If actually written by Paul, which 2 letters would be dated at the same time as his letter to Philemon?",
    "answer": "Ephesians and Colossians",
    "user": "micaelajanssen",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Ch. 11 - 12",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/121425322/powell-ch-11-12-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Of the material available for understanding Paul's life and thought what are the primary sources?",
    "answer": "seven undisputed letters of Paul",
    "user": "micaelajanssen",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Ch. 11 - 12",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/121425322/powell-ch-11-12-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Romans, Paul interprets Israel's \"rejection of Christ\" as...",
    "answer": "An example of God's mysterious purpose",
    "user": "micaelajanssen",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Ch. 11 - 12",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/121425322/powell-ch-11-12-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Romans, Paul says that \"all Israel will be saved\", which has been intereprated as meaning what?",
    "answer": "-Not \"Israel\" as an ethnic people but as a people, both Jewish and Gentile, who accept Israel's messiah<br> -A literal salvation of all Israel because of God's mercy and covenant with Israel <br> -A literal conversion of Jews will come about in the end times <br>ALL OF THE ABOVE",
    "user": "micaelajanssen",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Ch. 11 - 12",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/121425322/powell-ch-11-12-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul encourages the roman christians to five money for a collection to be offered for what purpose?",
    "answer": "the care of the poor in jerusalem",
    "user": "micaelajanssen",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Ch. 11 - 12",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/121425322/powell-ch-11-12-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Romans, Paul uses the story of this OT character to show that Jews and Gentiles can be saved by God's grace",
    "answer": "Abraham",
    "user": "micaelajanssen",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Ch. 11 - 12",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/121425322/powell-ch-11-12-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to proponents of \"the new perspective on Paul\", which of the following is probable Paul's main point in Romans?",
    "answer": "salvation is universally available",
    "user": "micaelajanssen",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Ch. 11 - 12",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/121425322/powell-ch-11-12-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Pastoral Letters are",
    "answer": "the three letters addressed to colleagues of Paul entrusted with pastoral leadership of churches: 1 Timothy, 2 Timothy, Titus.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapter 10 and 11",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/265606858/powell-chapter-10-and-11-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Captivity letters are",
    "answer": "the five letters that appear to have been written by Paul from prison: Ephesians, Philippians, Colossians, 2 Timothy, Philemon.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapter 10 and 11",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/265606858/powell-chapter-10-and-11-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Catholic (or General) letters are",
    "answer": "seven writings thought to be addressed to the church at large: James, 1 Peter, 2 Peter, 1 John, 2 John, 3 John, Jude.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapter 10 and 11",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/265606858/powell-chapter-10-and-11-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The typical structure of an ancient letter was",
    "answer": "salutation, thanksgiving, main body, closing.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapter 10 and 11",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/265606858/powell-chapter-10-and-11-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Christian letters, the customary \"Greetings\" is generally substituted by",
    "answer": "\"grace and peace.\"",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapter 10 and 11",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/265606858/powell-chapter-10-and-11-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is counted among the deutero-Pauline letters?",
    "answer": "Ephesians",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapter 10 and 11",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/265606858/powell-chapter-10-and-11-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an undisputed letter of Paul?",
    "answer": "2 Corinthians",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapter 10 and 11",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/265606858/powell-chapter-10-and-11-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following New Testament letters is considered to be pseudepigraphical?",
    "answer": "James",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapter 10 and 11",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/265606858/powell-chapter-10-and-11-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the context of authorship and pseudepigraphy, what is honorable pseudepigraphy?",
    "answer": "Admirers write letters in the name of a deceased leader in tribute to his influence, believing themselves to be responsible bearers of his tradition.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapter 10 and 11",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/265606858/powell-chapter-10-and-11-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Scholars who think that the New Testament letters ought to be considered authentic writings (not pseudepigraphical) may argue that",
    "answer": "A. early Christians would have viewed pseudepigraphy as a dishonest practice. (Your Answer)<br> B. early church traditions about authorship are generally reliable.<br> C. linguistic and other features that make the letter seem non-Pauline can be explained through Paul's use of an amanuensis.<br> D. all of the above (Correct Answer)",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapter 10 and 11",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/265606858/powell-chapter-10-and-11-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the context of authorship and pseudepigraphy, what is apprentice authorship?",
    "answer": "Disciples who have been authorized to speak for a living leader continue writing letters in his name years or decades after his death.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapter 10 and 11",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/265606858/powell-chapter-10-and-11-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a feature of letter writing in ancient times as reflected in the New Testament letters?",
    "answer": "the mandatory use of official Roman stamps (or imprints) on letters",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapter 10 and 11",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/265606858/powell-chapter-10-and-11-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a reason why scholars sometimes claim that a letter is pseudepigraphical?",
    "answer": "the intent to deceive",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapter 10 and 11",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/265606858/powell-chapter-10-and-11-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Paul's letters and Acts, which of the following is not an aspect of Paul's early life?",
    "answer": "Paul was born in Jerusalem",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapter 10 and 11",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/265606858/powell-chapter-10-and-11-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the book of Acts, Paul is also known by his Hebrew name",
    "answer": "Saul",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapter 10 and 11",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/265606858/powell-chapter-10-and-11-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul understood his life-changing revelation of Jesus as",
    "answer": "a prophetic call.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapter 10 and 11",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/265606858/powell-chapter-10-and-11-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "After Paul's conversion, his thinking changed in all of the following ways except",
    "answer": "before: Jesus was a prophet sent by God; after: Jesus is the Son of God and Lord of all.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapter 10 and 11",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/265606858/powell-chapter-10-and-11-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "It is generally believed that Paul spent the interim years between his conversion and his first missionary journey doing what?",
    "answer": "honing his missionary skills and developing his theological understanding of the gospel",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapter 10 and 11",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/265606858/powell-chapter-10-and-11-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a feature or strategy of Paul's missionary work?",
    "answer": "Paul's mission work was authorized by Peter and the other leaders of the Jerusalem church.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapter 10 and 11",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/265606858/powell-chapter-10-and-11-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In developing a chronology for Paul's life, one of the most helpful pieces of information has been",
    "answer": "the brief mention in the book of Acts that Gallio was the proconsul of Corinth when Paul was in that city",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapter 10 and 11",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/265606858/powell-chapter-10-and-11-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul's interest in Jesus focuses mainly on",
    "answer": "Jesus' death and resurrection",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapter 10 and 11",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/265606858/powell-chapter-10-and-11-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Theologically, Paul understands Jesus to be",
    "answer": "the image of God, the Son of God, and Lord.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapter 10 and 11",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/265606858/powell-chapter-10-and-11-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul's ethical expectations for Christians are shaped by all of the following except",
    "answer": "the hedonic calculus: Christians must act so as to bring the greatest satisfaction to the greatest number of people",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapter 10 and 11",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/265606858/powell-chapter-10-and-11-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is \"the New Perspective on Paul\"?",
    "answer": "a scholarly view that understands \"works of the law\" not as \"works righteousness\" but as ethnic markers that designate Israel as God's chosen people",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapter 10 and 11",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/265606858/powell-chapter-10-and-11-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Old testament books of disputed canonical status are called the...",
    "answer": "Apocrypha",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Exegesis is...",
    "answer": "The explication of texts",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What academic discipline studies culture through comparative methods in terms of kinship relations, power structures, gender roles, economic systems, and education?",
    "answer": "Cultural anthropology",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Of the many general spiritual beliefs circulating during Roman times, which assumed spirits could spirits could possess people, animals, and other entities",
    "answer": "Animism",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jesus conducted his ministry during the reign of which Roman emperor?",
    "answer": "Tiberius",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which period of Jewish history did groups like the Pharisees and Sadducees begin to develop",
    "answer": "Hasmonean",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What to developments in early Christianity made the Canon an issue for Christians",
    "answer": "1) some Christians were excluding certain writings and 2) some Christians were producing new writings and attributing them to apostles",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The New Testament was written at a time when the Mediterranean world was dominated by which nation",
    "answer": "...",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The German phrase \"Sitz I'm Leben\" which is frequently used even in English writings about form critical approaches to the Bible means what",
    "answer": "\"Setting in life\"",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What field of biblical study identifies genres incorporated into texts (like parables, genealogies, etc.) and speculates about the community life that generated those genres?",
    "answer": "Form Criticism",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the king of Syria during the Maccabean Revolt?",
    "answer": "Antiochus",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the shortest book of the New Testament?",
    "answer": "3 John",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did the Romans destroy the Jerusalem Temple?",
    "answer": "70 CE",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Approximately what percentage of the Roman population was extremely poor?",
    "answer": "90",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Scholars working primarily in the Gospels and Acts who apply insights from modern literary analysis practice what type of methodology?",
    "answer": "Narrative Criticism",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Of the many general spiritual beliefs circulating during Roman times, which considered miracles possible?",
    "answer": "...",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What area of scholarly study examines matters that characterized the social world such as the Pax Romana and an economic system with virtually no middle class?",
    "answer": "Sociological Criticism",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Caesar Augustus reportedly coined a proverb based on a person mentioned in the Gospels: \"Better to be a pig than a son in the house of ________.\"",
    "answer": "Herod",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which period did synagogues emerge as significant sites for Jewish teaching and worship?",
    "answer": "...",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Of the many general spiritual beliefs circulating during Roman times, which devoted itself to discerning the future through oracles, mediums, or observing phenomena?",
    "answer": "Augury",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Most people in the Roman Empire belonged in at least one patron-client relationship. Patrons would provide individuals with food or land and political areas (cities, provinces, empire) with benefits or infrastructure. In exchange, what were \"clients\" expected to provide?",
    "answer": "Gratitude, Loyalty, &amp; Praise",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many people have the name Herod in the New Testament?",
    "answer": "Three",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which New Testament book is in a category all by itself and is an anonymous work addressed to a group of Jewish Christians?",
    "answer": "...",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The New Testament does not mention which Jewish group?",
    "answer": "Essenes",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The word canon literally means . . .",
    "answer": "Rule",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are methods of redaction criticism that consider how units are arranged and how sources have been altered?",
    "answer": "Emendation analysis &amp; Compositional analysis",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Books in the New Testament that tell about the life of Jesus fall into which category?",
    "answer": "Gospels",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Of the many general spiritual beliefs circulating during Roman times, which appeared in the second century CE and regarded \"spirit\" as good and \"matter\" as evil?",
    "answer": "Gnosticism",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What method of biblical research is used by postmodern critics who assert that all interpretations of texts are based on subjective criteria and therefore cannot claim to be authoritative?",
    "answer": "Deconstruction",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Approximately what percentage of the Roman population was extremely rich?",
    "answer": "3",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which New Testament book is \"part two\" of the Gospel of Luke?",
    "answer": "Acts",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Apostle encouraged churches to whom he had written to exchange letters with one another?",
    "answer": "Paul",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which historical period did the Israelites enjoy freedom from foreign domination?",
    "answer": "...",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In what region did Jesus live and do most of his work?",
    "answer": "Galilee",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the longest book of the New Testament?",
    "answer": "Luke",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The High Priest in Jerusalem belonged to which group?",
    "answer": "Sadducees",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Hellenistic social world included which of the following?",
    "answer": "Increased religious syncretism<br>Grotesque economic inequality <br>Acute awareness of honor and shame",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Apocalypticism refers to which of the following?",
    "answer": "A dualistic outlook <br> A deterministic view of history <br> A pessimistic view of the future",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Religiously Jesus Christ was a..",
    "answer": "Jew",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Text criticism is a method of . . .",
    "answer": "Reconstructing early Christian manuscripts",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What should not be considered an Ideological Criticism?",
    "answer": "Cultural Anthropology",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jesus was born during the reign of which Roman emperor?",
    "answer": "Augustus",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the \"Apostolic Tradition\"?",
    "answer": "The written works of those who could be connected with Jesus or Paul",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What term refers to the love of death?",
    "answer": "Necrophillia",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "This Christian who lived in the second century created a canon that consisted of the Gospel of Luke and a collection of Paul's letters.",
    "answer": "Marcion",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hermeneutics refers to . . .",
    "answer": "Philosophical reflection on the art of interpretation",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Israel had reached its high point under the rulership of which king 1,000 years before Jesus lived?",
    "answer": "...",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which period did Jews increasingly focus on faithfulness to Torah as the hallmark of their religion?",
    "answer": "Persian",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which New Testament book offers an account of a visionary experience of a prophet named John?",
    "answer": "...",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which category of New Testament books does James belong?",
    "answer": "Letters by other people",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 1-2",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/150312843/powell-chapters-1-2-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"If a kingdom is divided against itself, it cannot stand\" is an example of what type of saying?",
    "answer": "Wisdom Saying",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The biblical Gospels employ multiple genres. They also are",
    "answer": "Overtly evangelistic, employing a fictive narrative style",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Greek word euangelion literally means . . .",
    "answer": "Good News",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Gospel does not contain any of Jesus' parables?",
    "answer": "John",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"In everything do unto others as you would have them do to you; for this is the law and the prophets\" is an example of what type of saying?",
    "answer": "Legal Saying",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Powell places the account of Jesus walking on the water into which category of Miracle Stories?",
    "answer": "Epiphanies",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"Let the dead bury the dead\" is a phrase taken from a . . .",
    "answer": "Pronouncement Story",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Lukan Jesus . . .",
    "answer": "Promises God will clothe his disciples with the Holy Spirit",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What designation is used by scholars to denote the earthly historical figure of Jesus?",
    "answer": "Pre-Easter Jesus",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"The Kingdom of God has come near; repent and believe\" is an example of what type of saying?",
    "answer": "Prophetic Saying",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What format was Jesus particularly fond of using when he taught?",
    "answer": "Parables",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"The Son of Man is to come with his angels in the glory of his Father, and then he will repay everyone for what has been done\" is an example of what type of saying?",
    "answer": "Eschatological saying",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ministry of Jesus was . . .",
    "answer": "Jewish Rural &amp; Itinerant",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pronouncement stories in the Gospels typically occur in what context?",
    "answer": "Controversy",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The \"Griesbach Hypothesis\" argues . . .",
    "answer": "Matthew was written first; Luke used Matthew, then Mark used both Matthew and Luke",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Johannine Jesus differs from the other Gospel presentations of Jesus in that . . .",
    "answer": "John's Jesus uses multiple metaphors",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a Pronouncement Story?",
    "answer": "An anecdote preserving the memory of something Jesus said",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Extraordinary acts attributed to Jesus that are impossible for a human being, such as walking on water, changing water to wine, and controlling the weather are referred to as . . .",
    "answer": "Nature Miracles",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "One main goal of New Testament study is . . .",
    "answer": "To understand each Gospel on its own terms",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jesus chose twelve disciples to be part of his inner circle because that number corresponded with what?",
    "answer": "The traditional number of Israel's tribes",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which New Testament book is remarkable for its description of Jesus as a great high priest?",
    "answer": "Hebrews",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jesus argued with which of the following groups over ritual hand-washing?",
    "answer": "Religious leaders of Israel",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Tatian constructed what book to solve the problem of having four different Gospels?",
    "answer": "Diatessaron",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Gospel mentions that Jesus' mother was a virgin when he was born?",
    "answer": "Matthew",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Gospel depicts Jesus' death as the ultimate triumph of God's love?",
    "answer": "John",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The gospels present the death of Jesus as a result of . . .",
    "answer": "The collaborating of high-ranking Jewish leaders and an unjust Pontius Pilate.",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the most prominent topic addressed by Jesus in the New Testament?",
    "answer": "The certainty of God's rule",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jesus abides in believers and believers abide in Jesus. This is . . .",
    "answer": "An early Christian belief about the exalted Jesus",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the second century, a prominent Christian named Tatian produced the Diatessaron, which was a . . .",
    "answer": "Synthesis of the four Gospels, creating one extended narrative of Jesus' life.",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not an aspect or quality of \"historical Jesus\" studies?",
    "answer": "The exalted figure of Jesus in the New Testament helps \"historical Jesus\" scholars fill out the historical reconstructions.",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Gospels consistently connect Jesus with which town in Galilee?",
    "answer": "Nazareth",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"Seen together\" defines which concept?",
    "answer": "Synoptic",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "New Testament authors with a high Christology regard Jesus primarily as . . .",
    "answer": "Virtually equal with God",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Approximately how many parables of Jesus are preserved in the Gospels?",
    "answer": "40",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What term describes the facet of Jesus' ministry in which he preaches on the road, taking his message to different groups as he and his disciples move from place to place?",
    "answer": "Itinerant",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the ancient world, what kind of writing portrayed the essential character of a person so that people would want to emulate that person?",
    "answer": "Biography",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Powell states that Christians, with respect to the exalted Christ, can almost be defined as people who do what?",
    "answer": "Call upon the name of the Lord",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a reason the religious leaders were jealous of Jesus?",
    "answer": "Jesus' coming from a poor, uneducated family",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Gospel emphasizes the sacrificial death of Jesus as one who gives his life as a ransom for many?",
    "answer": "Mark",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "When Jesus communicates with people through visions and prophecies this is called . . .",
    "answer": "Experience of the exalted Jesus",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Gospel describes Jesus as the one whose words and deeds set free the oppressed and save the lost?",
    "answer": "Luke",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The most prominent phase of Jesus' ministry occurs after what event takes place?",
    "answer": "Herod's arrest of John the Baptist",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jesus preached . . .",
    "answer": "A message that antagonized religious leaders of his time",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Similar material found in Matthew and Luke but not in Mark is called . . .",
    "answer": "Q",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which Gospel does Jesus die as the Messiah of Israel fulfilling prophecies that he would save his people from their sin?",
    "answer": "Matthew",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The four Gospels are compilations of . . .",
    "answer": "Miracle stories, resurrection narratives, and parables",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a Passion Narrative?",
    "answer": "The story of the suffering and death of Jesus",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the Gospels, possession by an evil spirit (demon) causes people to . . .",
    "answer": "Experience some sort of physical distress or disability",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Powell, to what does the phrase \"Kingdom of God\" refer?",
    "answer": "God's reign in the present &amp; God's reign in the future",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a regular part of Jesus' ministry?",
    "answer": "Offering sacrifices",
    "user": "Cautry96",
    "pageTitle": "Powell Chapters 3-4",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/151450653/powell-chapters-3-4-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a description of Paul's stay and ministry in Corinth according to the book of Acts?<br><br>A. Paul stayed in Corinth for at least eighteen months.<br> B. Paul made a living preparing meats for the marketplace. <br> C. Paul stayed with a Jewish-Christian couple named Priscilla and Aquila.<br> D. Paul converted at least two leaders of Jewish synagogues.",
    "answer": "Paul made a living preparing meats for the marketplace.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Corinth was the capital city of which Roman province?",
    "answer": "Achaia",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul writes 1 Corinthians in response to",
    "answer": "A. reports from Chloe's \"people.\"<br> B. a letter written to Paul from the Corinthian church.<br> C. reports from Stephanas, Fortunatus, and Achaicus, who delivered to Paul a latter from the corinthian church<br><br>(Answer is all of the above)",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Divisions in the Corinthian church seem to be based on",
    "answer": "Corinthians identifying themselves in terms of allegiance to prominent Christian leaders, whom they regard as wise and powerful.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul tells the Corinthians that he decided to know nothing among them but Christ",
    "answer": "Crucified",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In his teaching on the resurrection, Paul emphasizes in 1 Corinthians 15 that",
    "answer": "those who are raised by Christ will have new, glorified bodies.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Problems arose around the Lord's Supper in the Corinthian church because",
    "answer": "wealthier members were eating the food before the lower class members arrived after long work hours.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1 Corinthians 5, Paul instructs the church to exclude from Christian fellowship a (presumably unrepentant) \"wicked man\" with the purpose of",
    "answer": "bringing about the repentance necessary for this person to be saved.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does Paul teach the Corinthians regarding marriage and sex?",
    "answer": "Celibacy is preferable to marriage",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "With regard to eating \"food offered to idols,\" Paul claims that believers should",
    "answer": "be willing to give up their rights for the sake of others",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to 1 Corinthians 13, what will abide forever?",
    "answer": "Faith, hope, and love",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does Paul seem to regard the gift of prophecy as more important than speaking in tongues?",
    "answer": "It is more helpful to the church",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Though there may be more, a close reading of 1 Corinthians and 2 Corinthians reveals that Paul actually wrote ______ letters to the Corinthians.",
    "answer": "4",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the abrupt changes in tone and content in 2 Corinthians, some scholars argue that this writing is really",
    "answer": "a compilation of several letters.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "As dealt with in 2 Corinthians 8-9, Paul organized a fund-raising campaign among his churches for the Jerusalem church, which had the purpose of",
    "answer": "demonstrating the unity of Gentile and Jewish believers.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the Corinthian letters, Paul's qualifications for apostleship include all of the following except",
    "answer": "one who was designated one of the twelve by Jesus.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In between the writings of 1 Corinthians and 2 Corinthians Paul",
    "answer": "A. made a visit to the Corinthians in which he is hurt and humiliated.<br> B. received news from Titus that the Corinthian church had repented of grieving Paul. <br> C. wrote a letter challenging the church to prove their obedience to him and discipline an individual who had wronged him.<br><br>Answer is all of the above.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2 Corinthians, Paul is driven to boasting by",
    "answer": "super-apostles who tout their own credentials and achievements.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which feature of the ancient letter is actually lacking in Paul's letter to the Galatians?",
    "answer": "thanksgiving",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The significance of the debate over whether Galatians was written to \"north Galatia\" or \"south Galatia\" is that the destination might determine whether",
    "answer": "the letter was written early or late in Paul's career.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does Paul think the Galatians are fools?",
    "answer": "They want to be circumcised",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul's opponents in Galatia have apparently said that his gospel lacks endorsement from the apostles in Jerusalem. Paul replies that",
    "answer": "the apostles in Jerusalem do approve, but it doesn't really matter since he received his gospel from Christ and it needs no human endorsement",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul claims that if the Galatians seek justification (a right relation with God) by observing the law they are nullifying",
    "answer": "the grace of God",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul's gospel includes all of the following temporal aspects except",
    "answer": "God's new era in Christ is a time where both law and faith operate.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did Paul rebuke Peter at Antioch?",
    "answer": "Peter quit eating with Gentiles.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What role is especially ascribed to the Holy Spirit in Paul's letter to the Galatians?",
    "answer": "The Spirit bears virtuous fruit within believers.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The second-century writer Marcion actually knows and refers to what we know as \"the letter to the Ephesians\" as what letter?",
    "answer": "\"the letter to the Laodiceans",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the seven wonders of the ancient world was located in the city of Ephesus?",
    "answer": "the Temple of Artemis of the Ephesians",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ephesus is the capital city of what Roman province?",
    "answer": "Asia",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ephesians is remarkably similar and has close parallels to material found in what other New Testament letter, which has resulted in the two letters being called \"literary siblings\"?",
    "answer": "Colossians",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the NRSV, the first verse of Ephesians reads, \"Paul, an apostle of Christ Jesus by the will of God, To the saints who are in Ephesus and are faithful in Christ Jesus.\" Which word or words are missing from our most reliable Greek manuscripts?",
    "answer": "\"in Ephesus",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a feature or characteristic of Ephesians that is different in Paul's undisputed letters?",
    "answer": "Ephesians refers to the church as the \"body of Christ.\"",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Scholars have explained the dissimilarity of Ephesians with Paul's undisputed letters in all of the following ways except<br><br>A. Paul wrote Ephesians to a general audience soon after writing Colossians for a specific congregation. <br> B. Paul wrote Ephesians as a rough draft for Colossians but it was mistakenly inserted in the Pauline collection. <br> C. A disciple or companion of Paul wrote Ephesians after Paul's death, providing the church a generic statement of what the apostle would have written.<br> D. A later admirer of Paul wrote Ephesians in Paul's name to continue Paul's legacy and to gain an audience for the letter's teachings.",
    "answer": "Paul wrote Ephesians as a rough draft for Colossians but it was mistakenly inserted in the Pauline collection.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Ephesians, what was the mysterious plan of God?",
    "answer": "According to Ephesians, what was the mysterious plan of God?",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Ephesians, the mysterious plan of God is accomplished in what two stages?",
    "answer": "Jesus' crucifixion and exaltation",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the \"table of household duties\" (Haustafel) found in Ephesians is compared to such tables that were typical for this culture and time period, the most remarkable aspect is",
    "answer": "the inclusion of instructions for husbands, fathers, and masters",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not part of Ephesians' idea or perspective of the church?",
    "answer": "There are two dimensions of the church, the heavenly ministry inspired by Christ but also the sinful struggle of living in this world.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following strikes scholars as a distinctive aspect of Ephesians' view of Christians?",
    "answer": "The exaltation of Christians to heaven is depicted as a present reality.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "an independent Jewish colony, one of only two in the Roman empire.",
    "answer": "a Roman colony dominated by retired Roman soldiers.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The church in Philippi is often thought to be the first Christian church",
    "answer": "in Europe",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul's letter to the Philippians is best designated as",
    "answer": "a friendship letter.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The \"Christ Hymn\" in Philippians contains the earliest reference in Christian literature to the idea that Christ",
    "answer": "existed before he became the man Jesus.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul urges the Philippians to have humility, which in this letter means",
    "answer": "to put others first and consciously seek what is best for others over what may be best for oneself.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul indicates to the Philippians that suffering can actually have all of the following positive effects except",
    "answer": "suffering for Christ completes their salvation.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The theme of fellowship in Paul's letter to the Philippians is exemplified by Paul's repeated references to the members of this church as",
    "answer": "siblings",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What catastrophe destroyed the town of Colossae around the year 61 CE?",
    "answer": "earthquake",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a feature or fact of the city of Colossae?",
    "answer": "Colossae was the hometown of the emperor Nero",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The church at Colossae",
    "answer": "was not founded by Paul but by his coworker Epaphras",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not an aspect or characteristic of the so-called \"Colossian heresy,\" that is, the philosophy or teaching that threatens their Christian identity and faith?",
    "answer": "Christ fully divine but only appeared to be human",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In addition to its parallels with Ephesians, Colossians is also closely tied to the production of this Pauline letter.",
    "answer": "Philemon",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Colossians presents Christ as exalted and cosmic in all of the following ways except",
    "answer": "Christ descended to Hades",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The realized eschatology of Colossians is particularly evident in the claim that",
    "answer": "the Colossian Christians have been raised with Christ.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Realized eschatology functions in Colossians to",
    "answer": "assure the Colossians that no power in the universe is able to affect those who believe in Christ.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Colossians, spiritual growth and maturity is attained by",
    "answer": "remaining steadfast in what they have already been taught.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The image in Colossians of people stripping off old ways of being human and clothing themselves with virtuous behavior may derive from",
    "answer": "early Christian baptismal practices",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What Roman road was a major land route across northern Greece and Asia Minor and ran through Thessalonica?",
    "answer": "Via Egnatia",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What customary greeting in Pauline churches became a standard component of the Christian worship service in the second century?",
    "answer": "kiss of peace",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "First Thessalonians has the distinction of being",
    "answer": "the earliest of Paul's letters that have survived.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Thessalonica was the capital city of",
    "answer": "Macedonia.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning the depiction of Paul's ministry in Thessalonica,",
    "answer": "Acts focuses on his preaching in the Jewish synagogue while 1 Thessalonians assumes a ministry in the marketplace practicing a trade.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1 Thessalonians, Paul says that the wrath of God has overtaken the Jews for all of the following reasons except",
    "answer": "they continue to sacrifice in the Temple.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The suffering experienced by the Thessalonian Christians was most likely",
    "answer": "social shaming for not participating in the religious and entertainment events of the city.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "One notable characteristic of 1 Thessalonians is the number of times that Paul",
    "answer": "reminds his readers of things that they already know.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "With regard to the Thessalonians, Paul says that he and his companions have been<br><br>A. as gentle as a nurse.<br> B. as encouraging as a father.<br> C. as anxious as an orphan. <br> D. all of the above",
    "answer": "All of the above",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1 Thessalonians, Paul addresses concerns about those who died",
    "answer": "before Christ returned",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Although both 1 Thessalonians and 2 Thessalonians address similar topics, the tone of the second letter is usually thought to be more",
    "answer": "stern and strident",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "For those who believe that Paul wrote 2 Thessalonians, the letter was written",
    "answer": "shortly after 1 Thess, addressing a particular crisis concerning the day of the Lord.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Second Thessalonians seeks to correct an erroneous rumor that the day of the Lord had arrived by providing a chronology, which is",
    "answer": "the restraint of the lawless one, the revelation of the lawless one, the coming of Christ.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Suggestions as to what or who restrains the \"lawless one\" include all the following except",
    "answer": "Jewish unbelief.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In dealing with the issue of idleness, 2 Thessalonians states that anyone unwilling to work should",
    "answer": "not share in the church's meal.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What proportion of the population of the Roman Empire were slaves?",
    "answer": "between one-fourth and one-third of the population",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the name Onesimus literally mean, which Paul rhetorically employs as a pun in his letter to Philemon?",
    "answer": "\"useful\"",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a fact concerning the person Philemon?",
    "answer": "a general (legate) in the Roman army",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a fact concerning the person Onesimus?",
    "answer": "the head jailer of the prison where Paul is being kept",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What legal practice in the Roman world concerning slaves best provides a reasonable context for understanding Paul's letter to Philemon?",
    "answer": "A slave who has wronged his master could seek arbitration and sanctuary with a colleague or friend of the master.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Slavery in the Roman world was characterized by all of the following except",
    "answer": "slavery was based on race or ethnicity.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does Paul try to persuade Philemon to welcome or even emancipate his errant slave?",
    "answer": "Philemon might do this as a way of repaying Paul, to whom he is indebted for his very salvation.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "One persuasive tactic that Paul uses in his letter to Philemon is",
    "answer": "having the letter read publicly to the entire church.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a proposed reason why Paul wrote Romans?",
    "answer": "to reestablish contact with the Roman church that he had established during his second missionary journey",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the thesis of Paul's letter to the Romans?",
    "answer": "The gospel reveals the righteousness of God through faith for faith.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Romans, the righteousness of God is shown through God's",
    "answer": "faithfulness and generosity.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "The term justification derives from the language of",
    "answer": "God's covenant with Israel.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Romans, which of the following is not a possible meaning of \"faith\" (pistis) in relation to being justified or put right with God?",
    "answer": "People are justified by Paul's faithfulness in preaching the gospel.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "One image for explaining how Christ justifies people is redemption, which means",
    "answer": "with the blood of Christ God purchases freedom for people enslaved to sin, death, and the devil.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "One image for explaining how Christ justifies people is atonement, which means",
    "answer": "Jesus dies on the cross to offer a supreme sacrifice that fulfills God's requirement for nullifying sin.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "One image for explaining how Christ justifies people is reconciliation, which means",
    "answer": "Jesus offers his own life to restore the broken relationship between people and God.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "Proponents of \"the new perspective on Paul\" emphasize which aspect of Paul's letter to the Romans, believing that it might be Paul's main point.",
    "answer": "the universal scope and availability of salvation",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Romans, Paul says that \"all Israel will be saved,\" which has been interpreted as<br><br>A. a literal conversion of Jews will come about in the end times.<br> B. a literal salvation of all Israel because of God's mercy and covenant with Israel.<br> C. not \"Israel\" as an ethnic people but as a people, both Jew and Gentile, who accept Israel's messiah.<br>d. all of the above",
    "answer": "D. all of the above",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "With regard to governing authorities, Paul tells the Romans that",
    "answer": "governing authorities are instituted by God and must not be resisted",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Romans, Paul teaches that church members who know it is permissible to eat food that others think it is sinful to eat should",
    "answer": "forgo eating that food as an accommodation for those who might be injured by their action.",
    "user": "ivriab",
    "pageTitle": "Powell TEST 2 Powell Quiz Answers",
    "link": "https://quizlet.com/281820156/powell-test-2-powell-quiz-answers-flash-cards/#"
  }
]